const getFrenchWords = () => {
        return b
    }
    let b = [];
b.push({"front":"de","back":"of, from, some, any"});
b.push({"front":"je","back":"I"});
b.push({"front":"pas","back":"not, no"});
b.push({"front":"le","back":"the; him, her, it, them"});
b.push({"front":"que","back":"that, which, who, whom"});
b.push({"front":"tu","back":"you"});
b.push({"front":"vous","back":"you(pl)"});
b.push({"front":"un","back":"a, an, one"});
b.push({"front":"et","back":"and"});
b.push({"front":"à","back":"to, at, in"});
b.push({"front":"il","back":"he, it"});
b.push({"front":"ne","back":"not"});
b.push({"front":"en","back":"in, by"});
b.push({"front":"on","back":"one, we"});
b.push({"front":"ce","back":"this, that"});
b.push({"front":"pour","back":"for, in order to"});
b.push({"front":"qui","back":"who, whom"});
b.push({"front":"mais","back":"but"});
b.push({"front":"dans","back":"in, into, from"});
b.push({"front":"nous","back":"we, us"});
b.push({"front":"elle","back":"she, her"});
b.push({"front":"bien","back":"well"});
b.push({"front":"me","back":"me, to me, myself"});
b.push({"front":"si","back":"if, whether"});
b.push({"front":"y","back":"there"});
b.push({"front":"non","back":"no, not"});
b.push({"front":"avec","back":"with"});
b.push({"front":"tout","back":"all, very"});
b.push({"front":"plus","back":"more, no more"});
b.push({"front":"mon","back":"my"});
b.push({"front":"te","back":"you, to you, from you"});
b.push({"front":"fait","back":"done, fact"});
b.push({"front":"moi","back":"me"});
b.push({"front":"oui","back":"yes"});
b.push({"front":"faire","back":"to do, make"});
b.push({"front":"sur","back":"on, upon"});
b.push({"front":"quoi","back":"what"});
b.push({"front":"se","back":"oneself, himself, herself, itself, themselves"});
b.push({"front":"comme","back":"like, as"});
b.push({"front":"être","back":"to be; being"});
b.push({"front":"ici","back":"here"});
b.push({"front":"toi","back":"you, yourself"});
b.push({"front":"dit","back":"said, so-called; tale"});
b.push({"front":"lui","back":"him, her"});
b.push({"front":"votre","back":"your"});
b.push({"front":"pourquoi","back":"why"});
b.push({"front":"où","back":"where"});
b.push({"front":"rien","back":"nothing"});
b.push({"front":"là","back":"there, here"});
b.push({"front":"quand","back":"when"});
b.push({"front":"dire","back":"to say"});
b.push({"front":"son","back":"his, her, its; sound"});
b.push({"front":"ton","back":"your"});
b.push({"front":"alors","back":"then, so"});
b.push({"front":"comment","back":"how"});
b.push({"front":"par","back":"by"});
b.push({"front":"ou","back":"or"});
b.push({"front":"la chose","back":"thing"});
b.push({"front":"bon","back":"good"});
b.push({"front":"le merci, la merci","back":"thank you; favor"});
b.push({"front":"juste","back":"just, only; fair"});
b.push({"front":"très","back":"very"});
b.push({"front":"jamais","back":"never"});
b.push({"front":"un été","back":"summer; past particle of être (to be)"});
b.push({"front":"avoir","back":"to have"});
b.push({"front":"vraiment","back":"truly, really, very"});
b.push({"front":"aussi","back":"too, also, as"});
b.push({"front":"voir","back":"to see"});
b.push({"front":"oh","back":"oh"});
b.push({"front":"même","back":"same, even, self"});
b.push({"front":"maintenant","back":"now"});
b.push({"front":"le deux","back":"two"});
b.push({"front":"autre","back":"other"});
b.push({"front":"peu","back":"little"});
b.push({"front":"quelque","back":"some"});
b.push({"front":"le temps","back":"time"});
b.push({"front":"toujours","back":"always"});
b.push({"front":"encore","back":"again, yet"});
b.push({"front":"notre","back":"our"});
b.push({"front":"besoin","back":"need"});
b.push({"front":"un accord","back":"agreement"});
b.push({"front":"la vie","back":"life"});
b.push({"front":"aller","back":"to go"});
b.push({"front":"la fois","back":"time, times"});
b.push({"front":"sans","back":"without"});
b.push({"front":"donc","back":"so, then, therefore, thus"});
b.push({"front":"le monde","back":"world, people"});
b.push({"front":"avant","back":"before; forward"});
b.push({"front":"sûr","back":"sure"});
b.push({"front":"trop","back":"too much, too many"});
b.push({"front":"parler","back":"to speak"});
b.push({"front":"le père","back":"father"});
b.push({"front":"la personne","back":"person, people, anybody, anyone, nobody"});
b.push({"front":"après","back":"after"});
b.push({"front":"ouais","back":"yeah"});
b.push({"front":"le dieu","back":"god"});
b.push({"front":"un homme","back":"man"});
b.push({"front":"la femme","back":"woman, wife"});
b.push({"front":"leur","back":"them, their, theirs"});
b.push({"front":"vrai","back":"true"});
b.push({"front":"mal","back":"bad"});
b.push({"front":"chez","back":"at, with; home"});
b.push({"front":"depuis","back":"since, for"});
b.push({"front":"déjà","back":"already"});
b.push({"front":"beaucoup","back":"a lot of, many"});
b.push({"front":"le mort, la mort","back":"dead; death"});
b.push({"front":"le mieux","back":"better"});
b.push({"front":"la mère","back":"mother"});
b.push({"front":"la fille","back":"girl, daughter"});
b.push({"front":"le gens","back":"people"});
b.push({"front":"quel","back":"which, what"});
b.push({"front":"voilà","back":"right, there, here"});
b.push({"front":"le petit","back":"small, little"});
b.push({"front":"la maison","back":"house"});
b.push({"front":"soit","back":"either...or"});
b.push({"front":"le soir","back":"evening"});
b.push({"front":"cela","back":"that, it"});
b.push({"front":"le passé","back":"past"});
b.push({"front":"le jour","back":"day"});
b.push({"front":"prendre","back":"to take"});
b.push({"front":"le monsieur","back":"mister, sir, gentleman"});
b.push({"front":"savoir","back":"to know"});
b.push({"front":"un argent","back":"money; silver"});
b.push({"front":"le salut","back":"salute, hi, bye"});
b.push({"front":"le nom","back":"name"});
b.push({"front":"la nuit","back":"night"});
b.push({"front":"le bonjour","back":"hello"});
b.push({"front":"la raison","back":"reason"});
b.push({"front":"le moins","back":"less"});
b.push({"front":"la maman","back":"mom"});
b.push({"front":"le reste","back":"rest"});
b.push({"front":"un air","back":"air, appearance"});
b.push({"front":"seul","back":"alone, only"});
b.push({"front":"le moment","back":"moment"});
b.push({"front":"aider","back":"to help, assist"});
b.push({"front":"le papa","back":"dad, daddy"});
b.push({"front":"entre","back":"between"});
b.push({"front":"le passe, la passe","back":"pass, channel"});
b.push({"front":"le problème","back":"problem"});
b.push({"front":"la peur","back":"fear"});
b.push({"front":"le gars","back":"guy"});
b.push({"front":"le fils","back":"son"});
b.push({"front":"eh","back":"hey, uh"});
b.push({"front":"trois","back":"three"});
b.push({"front":"assez","back":"enough"});
b.push({"front":"la famille","back":"family"});
b.push({"front":"trouver","back":"to find"});
b.push({"front":"le travail","back":"work"});
b.push({"front":"la tête","back":"head"});
b.push({"front":"ah","back":"ah, oh"});
b.push({"front":"la voiture","back":"car"});
b.push({"front":"vite","back":"fast, quickly"});
b.push({"front":"partir","back":"to leave"});
b.push({"front":"hé","back":"hey"});
b.push({"front":"la merde","back":"sh*t, crap"});
b.push({"front":"tuer","back":"to kill"});
b.push({"front":"la chance","back":"luck; chance"});
b.push({"front":"le pendant","back":"during"});
b.push({"front":"une idée","back":"idea"});
b.push({"front":"le part, la part","back":"share"});
b.push({"front":"demain","back":"tomorrow"});
b.push({"front":"grand","back":"great, big, tall"});
b.push({"front":"un ami","back":"friend"});
b.push({"front":"venir","back":"to come"});
b.push({"front":"tard","back":"late"});
b.push({"front":"le mec","back":"guy"});
b.push({"front":"hein","back":"eh, huh"});
b.push({"front":"passer","back":"to pass"});
b.push({"front":"le truc","back":"trick; thing"});
b.push({"front":"tant","back":"so much, so many"});
b.push({"front":"combien","back":"how much, how many"});
b.push({"front":"le sens","back":"sense, meaning"});
b.push({"front":"puis","back":"then, so"});
b.push({"front":"la porte","back":"door"});
b.push({"front":"super","back":"great"});
b.push({"front":"sortir","back":"to go out, leave"});
b.push({"front":"une heure","back":"hour"});
b.push({"front":"contre","back":"against"});
b.push({"front":"le coup","back":"coup, blow, knock, stroke"});
b.push({"front":"ensemble","back":"together"});
b.push({"front":"nouveau","back":"new"});
b.push({"front":"un amour","back":"love"});
b.push({"front":"le sang","back":"blood"});
b.push({"front":"sous","back":"under"});
b.push({"front":"le cas","back":"case"});
b.push({"front":"rester","back":"to stay"});
b.push({"front":"la question","back":"question"});
b.push({"front":"la partie","back":"part"});
b.push({"front":"une histoire","back":"history, story"});
b.push({"front":"chercher","back":"to look for"});
b.push({"front":"seulement","back":"only"});
b.push({"front":"la police","back":"police"});
b.push({"front":"un aide, une aide","back":"help, assistance"});
b.push({"front":"la demande","back":"request, demand"});
b.push({"front":"le genre","back":"type, kind, sort"});
b.push({"front":"le mois","back":"month"});
b.push({"front":"le frère","back":"brother"});
b.push({"front":"laisser","back":"to leave, to let"});
b.push({"front":"le car","back":"because; bus"});
b.push({"front":"mettre","back":"to put, place"});
b.push({"front":"aucun","back":"none, either, neither, not any"});
b.push({"front":"eux","back":"them"});
b.push({"front":"la ville","back":"city"});
b.push({"front":"chaque","back":"each"});
b.push({"front":"arrivé","back":"arrived"});
b.push({"front":"le bébé","back":"baby"});
b.push({"front":"longtemps","back":"a long time, a long while"});
b.push({"front":"la putain","back":"whore, bitch; stupid"});
b.push({"front":"revoir","back":"to see again, revise"});
b.push({"front":"la place","back":"room, space, square, place"});
b.push({"front":"ni","back":"nor"});
b.push({"front":"une attention","back":"attention"});
b.push({"front":"voici","back":"here is, here are, this is, these are"});
b.push({"front":"une affaire","back":"business, matter"});
b.push({"front":"donner","back":"to give"});
b.push({"front":"le type","back":"type; guy"});
b.push({"front":"le train","back":"train"});
b.push({"front":"le corps","back":"body"});
b.push({"front":"un endroit","back":"place, spot"});
b.push({"front":"la façon","back":"way, manner"});
b.push({"front":"une écoute","back":"listening"});
b.push({"front":"dont","back":"whose, of which"});
b.push({"front":"le premier","back":"first"});
b.push({"front":"perdu","back":"lost, stray, wasted"});
b.push({"front":"la main","back":"hand"});
b.push({"front":"le côté","back":"side"});
b.push({"front":"pouvoir","back":"can, to be able to"});
b.push({"front":"le vieux","back":"old"});
b.push({"front":"tiens","back":"ah, well"});
b.push({"front":"le matin","back":"morning"});
b.push({"front":"tellement","back":"so much, indeed"});
b.push({"front":"un enfant, une enfant","back":"child"});
b.push({"front":"le point","back":"point; at all"});
b.push({"front":"venu","back":"come"});
b.push({"front":"la suite","back":"result, follow-up, rest"});
b.push({"front":"le pardon","back":"forgiveness"});
b.push({"front":"le devant","back":"in front, ahead"});
b.push({"front":"le vers","back":"toward"});
b.push({"front":"la chambre","back":"bedroom, chamber"});
b.push({"front":"le droit","back":"right"});
b.push({"front":"le mari, la mari","back":"husband"});
b.push({"front":"la cause","back":"cause"});
b.push({"front":"enfin","back":"at last, finally"});
b.push({"front":"une eau","back":"water"});
b.push({"front":"le parti","back":"political party; gone"});
b.push({"front":"le boulot","back":"work, job"});
b.push({"front":"arrêter","back":"to stop, arrest"});
b.push({"front":"la terre","back":"earth, world, soil, land"});
b.push({"front":"le compte","back":"account, count"});
b.push({"front":"loin","back":"far"});
b.push({"front":"le fin, la fin","back":"end; gist; clever person"});
b.push({"front":"croire","back":"to believe"});
b.push({"front":"gros","back":"big"});
b.push({"front":"plutôt","back":"rather"});
b.push({"front":"jouer","back":"to play"});
b.push({"front":"le bureau","back":"office, desk"});
b.push({"front":"hier","back":"yesterday"});
b.push({"front":"le prêt","back":"ready"});
b.push({"front":"mourir","back":"to die"});
b.push({"front":"celui","back":"that, the one, he, him"});
b.push({"front":"demander","back":"to ask for"});
b.push({"front":"possible","back":"possible"});
b.push({"front":"le jeune, la jeune","back":"young"});
b.push({"front":"le dehors","back":"outside"});
b.push({"front":"euh","back":"er, um, uh"});
b.push({"front":"une école","back":"school"});
b.push({"front":"beau","back":"handsome, fine, right"});
b.push({"front":"appeler","back":"to call"});
b.push({"front":"la semaine","back":"week"});
b.push({"front":"le propos","back":"remark, about"});
b.push({"front":"la vérité","back":"truth"});
b.push({"front":"le chef","back":"head, leader, chief"});
b.push({"front":"la confiance","back":"confidence, trust"});
b.push({"front":"le feu","back":"fire"});
b.push({"front":"vivre","back":"to live"});
b.push({"front":"le docteur","back":"doctor"});
b.push({"front":"la journée","back":"day"});
b.push({"front":"près","back":"near, nearby, close by"});
b.push({"front":"la madame","back":"madam, lady"});
b.push({"front":"le meilleur","back":"better, best"});
b.push({"front":"le dessus","back":"above, on top"});
b.push({"front":"le téléphone","back":"telephone"});
b.push({"front":"le dur","back":"hard"});
b.push({"front":"manger","back":"to eat"});
b.push({"front":"le garçon","back":"boy"});
b.push({"front":"le mariage","back":"marriage"});
b.push({"front":"une équipe","back":"team"});
b.push({"front":"arriver","back":"to arrive, happen"});
b.push({"front":"la marche","back":"walk, step, march"});
b.push({"front":"la guerre","back":"war"});
b.push({"front":"le derrière","back":"last; behind"});
b.push({"front":"plein","back":"full"});
b.push({"front":"important","back":"important"});
b.push({"front":"le fort","back":"strong"});
b.push({"front":"exactement","back":"exactly"});
b.push({"front":"presque","back":"almost"});
b.push({"front":"dernier","back":"last, previous"});
b.push({"front":"le fou","back":"mad, crazy"});
b.push({"front":"la fête","back":"holiday, celebration"});
b.push({"front":"tomber","back":"to fall"});
b.push({"front":"attendre","back":"to wait"});
b.push({"front":"la sécurité","back":"security, safety"});
b.push({"front":"la vue","back":"view"});
b.push({"front":"le jeu","back":"game"});
b.push({"front":"génial","back":"inspired, great, brilliant"});
b.push({"front":"une envie","back":"envy, desire"});
b.push({"front":"le capitaine","back":"captain"});
b.push({"front":"le pays","back":"country"});
b.push({"front":"le garde, la garde","back":"guard"});
b.push({"front":"le cours, la cours","back":"course"});
b.push({"front":"le numéro","back":"number"});
b.push({"front":"bientôt","back":"soon"});
b.push({"front":"cinq","back":"five"});
b.push({"front":"le parfait","back":"perfect"});
b.push({"front":"la minute","back":"minute"});
b.push({"front":"ainsi","back":"thus"});
b.push({"front":"autant","back":"as much, as many"});
b.push({"front":"le retour","back":"return"});
b.push({"front":"la peine","back":"effort, trouble"});
b.push({"front":"un instant","back":"instant, moment"});
b.push({"front":"mauvais","back":"bad, wrong"});
b.push({"front":"une arme","back":"weapon"});
b.push({"front":"le prison, la prison","back":"prison"});
b.push({"front":"penser","back":"to think"});
b.push({"front":"le mot","back":"word"});
b.push({"front":"le film","back":"film"});
b.push({"front":"quatre","back":"four"});
b.push({"front":"essayer","back":"to try"});
b.push({"front":"rentrer","back":"to go in, come in, come back, return"});
b.push({"front":"le plan","back":"plan"});
b.push({"front":"travailler","back":"to work"});
b.push({"front":"regarder","back":"to look, watch"});
b.push({"front":"parfois","back":"sometimes"});
b.push({"front":"la faute","back":"mistake, error, fault"});
b.push({"front":"le choix","back":"choice"});
b.push({"front":"le bas","back":"low; stockings"});
b.push({"front":"heureux","back":"happy, lucky, fortunate"});
b.push({"front":"facile","back":"easy"});
b.push({"front":"entendre","back":"to hear"});
b.push({"front":"changer","back":"to change"});
b.push({"front":"le lit","back":"bed"});
b.push({"front":"entrer","back":"to enter, go in, come in"});
b.push({"front":"le plaisir","back":"pleasure"});
b.push({"front":"ensuite","back":"next, following"});
b.push({"front":"propre","back":"clean, proper, own"});
b.push({"front":"la route","back":"road"});
b.push({"front":"le tour, la tour","back":"tower; turn; tour"});
b.push({"front":"garder","back":"to keep"});
b.push({"front":"une année","back":"year"});
b.push({"front":"drôle","back":"funny, strange"});
b.push({"front":"le service","back":"service"});
b.push({"front":"rendre","back":"to render, return, yield, give up"});
b.push({"front":"un agent, une agent","back":"agent"});
b.push({"front":"le lieu","back":"the place"});
b.push({"front":"devoir","back":"to have to, owe; duty"});
b.push({"front":"le sujet","back":"subject, topic"});
b.push({"front":"difficile","back":"difficult"});
b.push({"front":"le pire","back":"worse, worst"});
b.push({"front":"la sorte","back":"sort, kind"});
b.push({"front":"ceci","back":"this"});
b.push({"front":"un état","back":"state"});
b.push({"front":"bizarre","back":"strange, odd"});
b.push({"front":"le chien","back":"dog"});
b.push({"front":"perdre","back":"to lose"});
b.push({"front":"impossible","back":"impossible"});
b.push({"front":"tôt","back":"early"});
b.push({"front":"dès","back":"from, as soon"});
b.push({"front":"payer","back":"to pay"});
b.push({"front":"le calme","back":"calm"});
b.push({"front":"le café","back":"coffee, café"});
b.push({"front":"le verre","back":"glass, cup"});
b.push({"front":"la ferme","back":"farm; firm"});
b.push({"front":"la photo","back":"photo"});
b.push({"front":"sûrement","back":"surely"});
b.push({"front":"montrer","back":"to show"});
b.push({"front":"le cœur","back":"heart"});
b.push({"front":"le meurtre","back":"murder"});
b.push({"front":"un hôpital","back":"hospital"});
b.push({"front":"la musique","back":"music"});
b.push({"front":"un avis","back":"opinion, mind"});
b.push({"front":"sauf","back":"except; safe"});
b.push({"front":"le courant","back":"current"});
b.push({"front":"le doute, la doute","back":"doubt"});
b.push({"front":"la seconde","back":"second"});
b.push({"front":"sérieux","back":"serious"});
b.push({"front":"le marché","back":"market"});
b.push({"front":"le gentil","back":"nice, kind"});
b.push({"front":"un haut","back":"top, high"});
b.push({"front":"le malade, la malade","back":"ill, sick"});
b.push({"front":"dîner","back":"dinner; to dine"});
b.push({"front":"un esprit","back":"mind, spirit"});
b.push({"front":"le moyen","back":"means, way; medium"});
b.push({"front":"le six","back":"six"});
b.push({"front":"la salle","back":"the room, the hall"});
b.push({"front":"comprendre","back":"to understand"});
b.push({"front":"sauver","back":"to rescue, save"});
b.push({"front":"le cul","back":"bum, arse, ass"});
b.push({"front":"le seigneur","back":"lord"});
b.push({"front":"le simple","back":"simple"});
b.push({"front":"le bras","back":"arm"});
b.push({"front":"le chéri","back":"darling, love, dear"});
b.push({"front":"partout","back":"everywhere"});
b.push({"front":"le visage","back":"face"});
b.push({"front":"le chemin","back":"path, way"});
b.push({"front":"le retard","back":"delay"});
b.push({"front":"la soirée","back":"evening, party"});
b.push({"front":"un écrit","back":"writing"});
b.push({"front":"le livre, la livre","back":"book"});
b.push({"front":"la face","back":"front, side, face"});
b.push({"front":"boire","back":"to drink"});
b.push({"front":"le surtout","back":"especially, above all"});
b.push({"front":"le bois","back":"wood"});
b.push({"front":"la joue","back":"cheek"});
b.push({"front":"le rapport","back":"relationship, report"});
b.push({"front":"le message","back":"message"});
b.push({"front":"le pauvre","back":"poor"});
b.push({"front":"une erreur","back":"mistake, error"});
b.push({"front":"sinon","back":"otherwise, or else"});
b.push({"front":"un honneur","back":"honor"});
b.push({"front":"rencontrer","back":"to meet"});
b.push({"front":"un an","back":"year"});
b.push({"front":"devenir","back":"to become"});
b.push({"front":"souvent","back":"often"});
b.push({"front":"revenir","back":"to come back"});
b.push({"front":"messieurs","back":"gentlemen"});
b.push({"front":"le sort","back":"fate, curse"});
b.push({"front":"la pièce","back":"piece, part, component; room"});
b.push({"front":"dormir","back":"to sleep"});
b.push({"front":"la grave","back":"serious, grave"});
b.push({"front":"commencer","back":"to begin, start"});
b.push({"front":"le roi","back":"king"});
b.push({"front":"le groupe","back":"group"});
b.push({"front":"la carte","back":"card, map"});
b.push({"front":"un intérieur","back":"interior, inside"});
b.push({"front":"le reçu","back":"receipt, accepted"});
b.push({"front":"le rêve","back":"dream"});
b.push({"front":"bonsoir","back":"good evening"});
b.push({"front":"le faux, la faux","back":"false; scythe"});
b.push({"front":"le manque, la manque","back":"lack"});
b.push({"front":"un appel","back":"call"});
b.push({"front":"le sac","back":"bag, sack"});
b.push({"front":"content","back":"glad, pleased, happy"});
b.push({"front":"cher","back":"expensive"});
b.push({"front":"le président","back":"president"});
b.push({"front":"acheter","back":"to buy"});
b.push({"front":"le début","back":"the beginning"});
b.push({"front":"le secret","back":"secret"});
b.push({"front":"le maître","back":"master"});
b.push({"front":"la venue","back":"coming"});
b.push({"front":"le patron","back":"boss"});
b.push({"front":"la rue","back":"street"});
b.push({"front":"occuper","back":"to occupy"});
b.push({"front":"le âge","back":"age"});
b.push({"front":"le prix","back":"price; prize"});
b.push({"front":"gagner","back":"to win, earn"});
b.push({"front":"un effet","back":"effect"});
b.push({"front":"tirer","back":"to pull, fire"});
b.push({"front":"un avocat","back":"lawyer"});
b.push({"front":"la grâce","back":"thanks, grace, favour"});
b.push({"front":"la voix","back":"voice"});
b.push({"front":"le général","back":"general"});
b.push({"front":"le noir","back":"black"});
b.push({"front":"long","back":"long, lengthy"});
b.push({"front":"apprendre","back":"to learn"});
b.push({"front":"dix","back":"ten"});
b.push({"front":"un accident","back":"accident"});
b.push({"front":"probablement","back":"probably"});
b.push({"front":"le bout","back":"bit, tip, end"});
b.push({"front":"un ordre","back":"order"});
b.push({"front":"incroyable","back":"incredible, unbelievable"});
b.push({"front":"la scène","back":"scene"});
b.push({"front":"le voyage","back":"trip, journey"});
b.push({"front":"retrouver","back":"to find, recall"});
b.push({"front":"la force","back":"force"});
b.push({"front":"simplement","back":"simply"});
b.push({"front":"ailleurs","back":"elsewhere, somewhere else"});
b.push({"front":"la situation","back":"situation"});
b.push({"front":"protéger","back":"to protect"});
b.push({"front":"un hôtel","back":"hotel"});
b.push({"front":"utiliser","back":"to use"});
b.push({"front":"la sœur","back":"sister"});
b.push({"front":"le complètement","back":"completely"});
b.push({"front":"le crime","back":"crime"});
b.push({"front":"le dos","back":"back"});
b.push({"front":"un idiot","back":"idiot, fool, stupid"});
b.push({"front":"une armée","back":"army"});
b.push({"front":"la sale","back":"dirty"});
b.push({"front":"la liste","back":"list"});
b.push({"front":"un anniversaire","back":"anniversary, birthday"});
b.push({"front":"un oncle","back":"uncle"});
b.push({"front":"la victime","back":"victim"});
b.push({"front":"un arrêté","back":"decree, order"});
b.push({"front":"la paix","back":"peace"});
b.push({"front":"battre","back":"to beat, hit"});
b.push({"front":"absolument","back":"absolutely"});
b.push({"front":"finir","back":"to finish"});
b.push({"front":"libre","back":"free"});
b.push({"front":"un avion","back":"plane"});
b.push({"front":"le rouge","back":"red"});
b.push({"front":"retourner","back":"to return, go back"});
b.push({"front":"réussi","back":"successful"});
b.push({"front":"le bateau","back":"boat, ship"});
b.push({"front":"stupide","back":"stupid, silly, bemused"});
b.push({"front":"le médecin, la médecin","back":"physician, doctor"});
b.push({"front":"la balle","back":"ball, bullet"});
b.push({"front":"la faim","back":"hungry"});
b.push({"front":"le contrôle","back":"control"});
b.push({"front":"la table","back":"table"});
b.push({"front":"le fond","back":"bottom"});
b.push({"front":"le bordel","back":"brothel, mess, chaos"});
b.push({"front":"une habitude","back":"habit"});
b.push({"front":"une impression","back":"impression"});
b.push({"front":"la surprise","back":"surprise"});
b.push({"front":"porter","back":"to wear, carry"});
b.push({"front":"un autour","back":"around"});
b.push({"front":"la colère","back":"anger"});
b.push({"front":"un or","back":"gold; hence, thus"});
b.push({"front":"la ligne","back":"line"});
b.push({"front":"magnifique","back":"magnificent"});
b.push({"front":"le gauche, la gauche","back":"left"});
b.push({"front":"le clair","back":"clear"});
b.push({"front":"neuf","back":"nine; new"});
b.push({"front":"le cadeau","back":"present, gift"});
b.push({"front":"le risque","back":"risk"});
b.push({"front":"le système","back":"system"});
b.push({"front":"un inspecteur","back":"inspector"});
b.push({"front":"hors","back":"except, outside"});
b.push({"front":"le dedans, la dedans","back":"inside, indoors"});
b.push({"front":"expliquer","back":"to explain"});
b.push({"front":"une espèce","back":"species"});
b.push({"front":"la montre","back":"watch"});
b.push({"front":"le pied","back":"foot"});
b.push({"front":"le présent","back":"present; gift"});
b.push({"front":"plusieurs","back":"several"});
b.push({"front":"marcher","back":"to walk"});
b.push({"front":"la lumière","back":"light"});
b.push({"front":"la réponse","back":"the answer, the response"});
b.push({"front":"le coin","back":"corner"});
b.push({"front":"suivre","back":"to follow"});
b.push({"front":"la moitié","back":"half"});
b.push({"front":"le club","back":"club"});
b.push({"front":"pareil","back":"similar, likewise; peer, equal"});
b.push({"front":"joli","back":"pretty, attractive"});
b.push({"front":"le camp","back":"camp"});
b.push({"front":"vouloir","back":"to want"});
b.push({"front":"envoyer","back":"to send"});
b.push({"front":"la mission","back":"mission"});
b.push({"front":"le soleil","back":"sun"});
b.push({"front":"selon","back":"according to"});
b.push({"front":"un arrière","back":"back, rear"});
b.push({"front":"lire","back":"to read; lira"});
b.push({"front":"doucement","back":"gently, softly"});
b.push({"front":"tenir","back":"to hold"});
b.push({"front":"la sortie","back":"the exit"});
b.push({"front":"exact","back":"exact, correct"});
b.push({"front":"la recherche","back":"research, search"});
b.push({"front":"continuer","back":"to continue"});
b.push({"front":"poser","back":"to put, pose, ask"});
b.push({"front":"le chaud","back":"warm, hot"});
b.push({"front":"la lettre","back":"letter"});
b.push({"front":"le tueur","back":"killer, hit man"});
b.push({"front":"une avance","back":"advance"});
b.push({"front":"une arrivée","back":"arrival"});
b.push({"front":"le bar","back":"bar"});
b.push({"front":"quitter","back":"to leave"});
b.push({"front":"connaître","back":"to know"});
b.push({"front":"la loi","back":"law"});
b.push({"front":"le gamin","back":"kid"});
b.push({"front":"le professeur, la professeur","back":"professor, teacher"});
b.push({"front":"le froid","back":"cold"});
b.push({"front":"la forme","back":"form"});
b.push({"front":"normal","back":"normal"});
b.push({"front":"le but","back":"goal, aim, objective, purpose"});
b.push({"front":"une offre","back":"offer"});
b.push({"front":"le conseil","back":"advice, counsel, council"});
b.push({"front":"debout","back":"standing"});
b.push({"front":"dangereux","back":"dangerous"});
b.push({"front":"tranquille","back":"quiet"});
b.push({"front":"la boîte","back":"box"});
b.push({"front":"le ciel","back":"sky"});
b.push({"front":"la classe","back":"class"});
b.push({"front":"le danger","back":"danger"});
b.push({"front":"une enquête","back":"inquiry, enquiry, investigation"});
b.push({"front":"la télé","back":"TV"});
b.push({"front":"oublier","back":"to forget"});
b.push({"front":"la visite","back":"visit"});
b.push({"front":"le juge, la juge","back":"judge"});
b.push({"front":"le poste, la poste","back":"post, position; post office"});
b.push({"front":"une attaque","back":"attack"});
b.push({"front":"la touche","back":"button, key, touch, touchline"});
b.push({"front":"la droite","back":"right"});
b.push({"front":"triste","back":"sad"});
b.push({"front":"aimer","back":"to like, love"});
b.push({"front":"le vivant","back":"alive, living"});
b.push({"front":"coucher","back":"to lie down, sleep"});
b.push({"front":"la tombe","back":"grave, tomb"});
b.push({"front":"la preuve","back":"proof"});
b.push({"front":"la dame","back":"lady"});
b.push({"front":"le flic, la flic","back":"cop"});
b.push({"front":"écouter","back":"to listen to"});
b.push({"front":"la cuisine","back":"cooking, kitchen"});
b.push({"front":"la relation","back":"relationship"});
b.push({"front":"le dossier","back":"file, record; case"});
b.push({"front":"sentir","back":"to feel, smell"});
b.push({"front":"le blanc","back":"white"});
b.push({"front":"la chanson","back":"song"});
b.push({"front":"la gueule","back":"mouth, trap"});
b.push({"front":"foutre","back":"to f*ck, shove off"});
b.push({"front":"la santé","back":"health"});
b.push({"front":"déjeuner","back":"lunch; to have lunch"});
b.push({"front":"pourtant","back":"yet, nonetheless, nevertheless"});
b.push({"front":"le change","back":"exchange"});
b.push({"front":"le travers","back":"breadth, across; fault, amiss"});
b.push({"front":"ouvrir","back":"to open"});
b.push({"front":"la âme","back":"soul"});
b.push({"front":"voler","back":"to steal, rob; fly"});
b.push({"front":"le centre","back":"center"});
b.push({"front":"chacun","back":"each"});
b.push({"front":"le lieutenant","back":"lieutenant"});
b.push({"front":"le certain","back":"certain, sure"});
b.push({"front":"la compagnie","back":"company"});
b.push({"front":"la clé","back":"key"});
b.push({"front":"la manière","back":"manner, way"});
b.push({"front":"différent","back":"different"});
b.push({"front":"le bord","back":"edge, side"});
b.push({"front":"la décision","back":"decision"});
b.push({"front":"vendre","back":"to sell"});
b.push({"front":"un enfer","back":"hell"});
b.push({"front":"le diable","back":"devil"});
b.push({"front":"un appartement","back":"appartment, flat"});
b.push({"front":"étrange","back":"strange, odd"});
b.push({"front":"monter","back":"to go up, rise, assemble"});
b.push({"front":"le signe","back":"sign"});
b.push({"front":"la bouche","back":"mouth"});
b.push({"front":"écrire","back":"to write"});
b.push({"front":"le cheval","back":"horse"});
b.push({"front":"le responsable, la responsable","back":"responsible"});
b.push({"front":"le coupable, la coupable","back":"guilty"});
b.push({"front":"une honte","back":"shame"});
b.push({"front":"emmener","back":"to take (a person, from a place)"});
b.push({"front":"le soin","back":"care"});
b.push({"front":"le milieu","back":"middle"});
b.push({"front":"le prochain","back":"next"});
b.push({"front":"rire","back":"to laugh"});
b.push({"front":"le cerveau","back":"brain"});
b.push({"front":"la voie","back":"road, lane, route, track, way"});
b.push({"front":"un amoureux","back":"in love, amorous"});
b.push({"front":"le silence","back":"silence"});
b.push({"front":"la drogue","back":"drug"});
b.push({"front":"la blague","back":"joke"});
b.push({"front":"le trou","back":"hole"});
b.push({"front":"un intérêt","back":"interest"});
b.push({"front":"tel","back":"such"});
b.push({"front":"le public","back":"public, audience"});
b.push({"front":"la réunion","back":"meeting"});
b.push({"front":"capable","back":"able, capable"});
b.push({"front":"le client","back":"client"});
b.push({"front":"une époque","back":"era, period"});
b.push({"front":"la prise","back":"grip, hold, seizure, catch"});
b.push({"front":"une adresse","back":"address"});
b.push({"front":"cacher","back":"to hide"});
b.push({"front":"le combat","back":"fight, combat"});
b.push({"front":"la peau","back":"skin"});
b.push({"front":"le blessé","back":"injured"});
b.push({"front":"la robe","back":"dress"});
b.push({"front":"la fiche","back":"card, sheet, slip, form"});
b.push({"front":"la bière","back":"beer; coffin"});
b.push({"front":"le colonel","back":"colonel"});
b.push({"front":"lequel","back":"who, whom, which"});
b.push({"front":"le don","back":"gift, talent"});
b.push({"front":"le journal","back":"newspaper, paper"});
b.push({"front":"la société","back":"society"});
b.push({"front":"sept","back":"seven"});
b.push({"front":"le contact","back":"contact"});
b.push({"front":"la base","back":"base"});
b.push({"front":"le vin","back":"wine"});
b.push({"front":"servir","back":"to serve"});
b.push({"front":"un exemple","back":"example"});
b.push({"front":"jeter","back":"to throw"});
b.push({"front":"la mer","back":"sea"});
b.push({"front":"le tort","back":"wrong"});
b.push({"front":"ouvert","back":"open"});
b.push({"front":"récupérer","back":"to get back, recover, recuperate"});
b.push({"front":"le dommage","back":"damage, harm; too bad"});
b.push({"front":"le gouvernement","back":"government"});
b.push({"front":"le vol","back":"flight, theft"});
b.push({"front":"le nez","back":"nose"});
b.push({"front":"un héros","back":"hero"});
b.push({"front":"horrible","back":"horrible, terrible, dreadful, hideous"});
b.push({"front":"prévu","back":"planned, expected"});
b.push({"front":"une enceinte","back":"pregnant; enclosure"});
b.push({"front":"le secours","back":"help, aid, assistance"});
b.push({"front":"une entrée","back":"entrance"});
b.push({"front":"une opération","back":"operation"});
b.push({"front":"le témoin","back":"witness"});
b.push({"front":"environ","back":"about, thereabouts, or so"});
b.push({"front":"répondre","back":"to answer"});
b.push({"front":"le départ","back":"departure"});
b.push({"front":"la danse","back":"dance, dancing"});
b.push({"front":"vérifier","back":"to check, verify"});
b.push({"front":"la lune","back":"moon"});
b.push({"front":"le sexe","back":"sex"});
b.push({"front":"la justice","back":"justice"});
b.push({"front":"terrible","back":"terrible, dreadful"});
b.push({"front":"le peuple","back":"people"});
b.push({"front":"le bruit","back":"noise"});
b.push({"front":"le commandant","back":"commander"});
b.push({"front":"intéressant","back":"interesting"});
b.push({"front":"le lycée","back":"high school"});
b.push({"front":"ramener","back":"to bring back, return, take back"});
b.push({"front":"la mise","back":"putting, placing"});
b.push({"front":"le radio, la radio","back":"radio"});
b.push({"front":"inutile","back":"useless"});
b.push({"front":"une excuse","back":"excuse, apology"});
b.push({"front":"le tas","back":"pile, lots of"});
b.push({"front":"la banque","back":"bank"});
b.push({"front":"apparemment","back":"apparently"});
b.push({"front":"baiser","back":"to kiss"});
b.push({"front":"la bête","back":"animal, beast; stupid"});
b.push({"front":"ridicule","back":"ridiculous, silly"});
b.push({"front":"un avenir","back":"future"});
b.push({"front":"le thé","back":"tea"});
b.push({"front":"la bande","back":"band, strip"});
b.push({"front":"le œil","back":"eye"});
b.push({"front":"plupart","back":"most, the majority"});
b.push({"front":"le procès","back":"trial, proceedings"});
b.push({"front":"le bravo","back":"bravo, well done"});
b.push({"front":"la position","back":"position"});
b.push({"front":"sérieusement","back":"seriously"});
b.push({"front":"la pitié","back":"pity, mercy"});
b.push({"front":"un humain","back":"human"});
b.push({"front":"une approche","back":"approach"});
b.push({"front":"la liberté","back":"liberty, freedom"});
b.push({"front":"le revenu","back":"income"});
b.push({"front":"un anglais","back":"English"});
b.push({"front":"la nourriture","back":"food"});
b.push({"front":"le nord","back":"north"});
b.push({"front":"le deuxième, la deuxième","back":"second"});
b.push({"front":"le vaisseau","back":"ship, vessel"});
b.push({"front":"éviter","back":"to avoid"});
b.push({"front":"la cour","back":"yard, court"});
b.push({"front":"le rôle","back":"role"});
b.push({"front":"une expérience","back":"experience"});
b.push({"front":"le match","back":"match, game"});
b.push({"front":"empêcher","back":"to prevent"});
b.push({"front":"le directeur","back":"director"});
b.push({"front":"le mur","back":"wall"});
b.push({"front":"conduire","back":"to lead, drive"});
b.push({"front":"la défense","back":"defense"});
b.push({"front":"la tante","back":"aunt"});
b.push({"front":"marier","back":"to marry"});
b.push({"front":"le vide","back":"empty"});
b.push({"front":"spécial","back":"special"});
b.push({"front":"le sud","back":"south"});
b.push({"front":"censé","back":"supposed"});
b.push({"front":"une église","back":"church"});
b.push({"front":"merveilleux","back":"marvellous, wonderful"});
b.push({"front":"huit","back":"eight"});
b.push({"front":"le sol","back":"floor, ground"});
b.push({"front":"excuser","back":"to excuse"});
b.push({"front":"le personnel","back":"personnel, personal"});
b.push({"front":"hum","back":"um, uh"});
b.push({"front":"la bombe","back":"bomb"});
b.push({"front":"le code","back":"code"});
b.push({"front":"le niveau","back":"level"});
b.push({"front":"la fenêtre","back":"window"});
b.push({"front":"le magasin","back":"store"});
b.push({"front":"asseoir","back":"to sit"});
b.push({"front":"la vidéo","back":"video"});
b.push({"front":"obtenir","back":"to get, obtain"});
b.push({"front":"la reine","back":"queen"});
b.push({"front":"un espoir","back":"hope"});
b.push({"front":"certainement","back":"certainly"});
b.push({"front":"la glace","back":"ice, ice cream; mirror"});
b.push({"front":"mien","back":"mine"});
b.push({"front":"la presse","back":"press"});
b.push({"front":"souvenir","back":"memory; to remember"});
b.push({"front":"le terrain","back":"ground, terrain"});
b.push({"front":"danser","back":"to dance"});
b.push({"front":"le quartier","back":"district, quarter"});
b.push({"front":"lorsque","back":"when"});
b.push({"front":"la douleur","back":"pain"});
b.push({"front":"le rose, la rose","back":"rose; pink"});
b.push({"front":"la zone","back":"zone, area"});
b.push({"front":"le spectacle","back":"the sight, the show"});
b.push({"front":"le proche, la proche","back":"nearby, close"});
b.push({"front":"présenter","back":"to present"});
b.push({"front":"honnête","back":"honest, decent, fair"});
b.push({"front":"le rapide","back":"fast, quick"});
b.push({"front":"le camion","back":"truck"});
b.push({"front":"le village","back":"village"});
b.push({"front":"une importance","back":"importance"});
b.push({"front":"nul","back":"nil, null"});
b.push({"front":"le mérite","back":"merit"});
b.push({"front":"assurer","back":"to assure, insure"});
b.push({"front":"fier","back":"to rely on; proud"});
b.push({"front":"prouver","back":"to prove"});
b.push({"front":"une occasion","back":"chance, opportunity"});
b.push({"front":"le projet","back":"project"});
b.push({"front":"la rencontre","back":"meeting"});
b.push({"front":"la machine","back":"machine"});
b.push({"front":"la parole","back":"word"});
b.push({"front":"le gosse, la gosse","back":"kid"});
b.push({"front":"un officier, une officier","back":"officer; officiate"});
b.push({"front":"discuter","back":"to discuss, debate; to question"});
b.push({"front":"remettre","back":"to deliver, replace, set, put"});
b.push({"front":"le copain","back":"friend, buddy, mate"});
b.push({"front":"le respect","back":"respect"});
b.push({"front":"épouser","back":"to marry, wed"});
b.push({"front":"la réalité","back":"reality"});
b.push({"front":"le portable","back":"portable, wearable; cell phone"});
b.push({"front":"choisir","back":"to choose"});
b.push({"front":"le programme","back":"program"});
b.push({"front":"rappeler","back":"to recall, call back"});
b.push({"front":"la planète","back":"planet"});
b.push({"front":"offrir","back":"to offer"});
b.push({"front":"la pression","back":"pressure"});
b.push({"front":"découvrir","back":"to discover"});
b.push({"front":"le court","back":"short"});
b.push({"front":"le bain","back":"bath, bathing"});
b.push({"front":"détruire","back":"to destroy"});
b.push({"front":"chanter","back":"to sing"});
b.push({"front":"la mademoiselle","back":"Miss"});
b.push({"front":"la charge","back":"to charge, load"});
b.push({"front":"énorme","back":"enormous"});
b.push({"front":"la nature","back":"nature"});
b.push({"front":"le monstre","back":"monster"});
b.push({"front":"riche","back":"rich"});
b.push({"front":"la solution","back":"solution"});
b.push({"front":"un envers","back":"towards"});
b.push({"front":"réfléchir","back":"to reflect (over a subject)"});
b.push({"front":"la pierre","back":"stone"});
b.push({"front":"le test","back":"test"});
b.push({"front":"enlever","back":"to remove"});
b.push({"front":"sauter","back":"to jump"});
b.push({"front":"préparer","back":"to prepare"});
b.push({"front":"le nécessaire","back":"necessary, required"});
b.push({"front":"le patient","back":"patient"});
b.push({"front":"finalement","back":"finally, eventually"});
b.push({"front":"immédiatement","back":"immediately"});
b.push({"front":"arranger","back":"to arrange"});
b.push({"front":"toucher","back":"to touch"});
b.push({"front":"le bus, la bus","back":"bus"});
b.push({"front":"un ennemi","back":"enemy"});
b.push({"front":"un invité","back":"guest"});
b.push({"front":"le suspect","back":"suspicious, suspect"});
b.push({"front":"le couteau","back":"knife"});
b.push({"front":"durant","back":"during, for"});
b.push({"front":"ancien","back":"ancient; former"});
b.push({"front":"le vent","back":"wind"});
b.push({"front":"le futur","back":"future"});
b.push({"front":"tourner","back":"to turn"});
b.push({"front":"le repas","back":"meal"});
b.push({"front":"un espace, une espace","back":"space"});
b.push({"front":"la taille","back":"the size, the height"});
b.push({"front":"la politique","back":"politics; political"});
b.push({"front":"le papier","back":"paper"});
b.push({"front":"accepter","back":"to accept"});
b.push({"front":"une université","back":"university"});
b.push({"front":"descendre","back":"to go down, come down"});
b.push({"front":"la conversation","back":"conversation"});
b.push({"front":"le contrat","back":"contract"});
b.push({"front":"le chat","back":"cat; chat"});
b.push({"front":"la beauté","back":"beauty"});
b.push({"front":"le double","back":"double"});
b.push({"front":"excellent","back":"excellent"});
b.push({"front":"un ordinateur","back":"computer"});
b.push({"front":"la course","back":"race, shopping"});
b.push({"front":"la carrière","back":"career"});
b.push({"front":"le mille","back":"a thousand"});
b.push({"front":"le bonheur","back":"happiness"});
b.push({"front":"le mémoire, la mémoire","back":"memory"});
b.push({"front":"le permis","back":"license, permit, permitted"});
b.push({"front":"le contraire","back":"opposite, contrary"});
b.push({"front":"une énergie","back":"energy"});
b.push({"front":"une urgence","back":"emergency"});
b.push({"front":"le taxi","back":"taxi"});
b.push({"front":"joyeux","back":"merry, joyful, happy"});
b.push({"front":"parmi","back":"among"});
b.push({"front":"le courage","back":"courage"});
b.push({"front":"la différence","back":"difference"});
b.push({"front":"le couple, la couple","back":"couple"});
b.push({"front":"le prince","back":"prince"});
b.push({"front":"la crise","back":"crisis"});
b.push({"front":"la série","back":"series"});
b.push({"front":"la piste","back":"track, trail"});
b.push({"front":"puisque","back":"since"});
b.push({"front":"une action","back":"action"});
b.push({"front":"la coupe","back":"bowl, dish, cut"});
b.push({"front":"la maladie","back":"illness, disease"});
b.push({"front":"la cible","back":"target"});
b.push({"front":"le restaurant","back":"restaurant"});
b.push({"front":"le fil","back":"thread, wire"});
b.push({"front":"un alcool","back":"alcohol"});
b.push({"front":"la caméra","back":"camera"});
b.push({"front":"lors","back":"at the time of"});
b.push({"front":"un accès","back":"access"});
b.push({"front":"pleurer","back":"to cry"});
b.push({"front":"totalement","back":"totally"});
b.push({"front":"remercier","back":"to thank"});
b.push({"front":"un entier","back":"whole, full"});
b.push({"front":"la couleur","back":"color"});
b.push({"front":"la île","back":"island"});
b.push({"front":"fermer","back":"to close, shut"});
b.push({"front":"le soldat","back":"soldier"});
b.push({"front":"un étage","back":"floor, level"});
b.push({"front":"amuser","back":"to amuse"});
b.push({"front":"régler","back":"to pay, adjust, settle"});
b.push({"front":"le frais","back":"cool, fresh; fee, expense"});
b.push({"front":"une image","back":"picture, image"});
b.push({"front":"la langue","back":"language, tongue"});
b.push({"front":"le suivi","back":"follow-up; consistent, continuous"});
b.push({"front":"la direction","back":"direction, management"});
b.push({"front":"mentir","back":"to lie"});
b.push({"front":"le salaud","back":"bastard"});
b.push({"front":"sacré","back":"sacred"});
b.push({"front":"le troisième, la troisième","back":"third"});
b.push({"front":"le poisson","back":"fish"});
b.push({"front":"frapper","back":"to hit, strike, knock"});
b.push({"front":"courir","back":"to run"});
b.push({"front":"bouger","back":"to move, shift, budge"});
b.push({"front":"rejoindre","back":"to rejoin, reunite"});
b.push({"front":"le bleu","back":"blue"});
b.push({"front":"un américain","back":"American"});
b.push({"front":"superbe","back":"superb, magnificient, handsome, gorgeous"});
b.push({"front":"le destin","back":"fate, destiny"});
b.push({"front":"le mark","back":"mark"});
b.push({"front":"le faible","back":"weak"});
b.push({"front":"le lait","back":"milk"});
b.push({"front":"un adieu","back":"goodbye, farewell, adieu"});
b.push({"front":"le pont","back":"bridge"});
b.push({"front":"le costume","back":"suit, costume, dress"});
b.push({"front":"le procureur","back":"prosecutor"});
b.push({"front":"attraper","back":"to catch, get, pick up"});
b.push({"front":"la princesse","back":"princess"});
b.push({"front":"le partenaire, la partenaire","back":"partner"});
b.push({"front":"un arrêt","back":"stop"});
b.push({"front":"le goût","back":"taste"});
b.push({"front":"sourire","back":"smile, to smile"});
b.push({"front":"la bouteille","back":"bottle"});
b.push({"front":"une intention","back":"intention"});
b.push({"front":"formidable","back":"tremendous, considerable"});
b.push({"front":"moindre","back":"lesser, least, slightest"});
b.push({"front":"unique","back":"unique"});
b.push({"front":"le tribunal","back":"court"});
b.push({"front":"le français","back":"French"});
b.push({"front":"la foi","back":"faith"});
b.push({"front":"un art","back":"art"});
b.push({"front":"évidemment","back":"obviously"});
b.push({"front":"la date","back":"date"});
b.push({"front":"la chasse","back":"chase, hunt, hunting"});
b.push({"front":"amener","back":"to bring someone (to a place)"});
b.push({"front":"un os","back":"bone"});
b.push({"front":"afin","back":"in order to, so that"});
b.push({"front":"le gâteau","back":"cake"});
b.push({"front":"le cou","back":"neck"});
b.push({"front":"couper","back":"to cut"});
b.push({"front":"ha","back":"oh"});
b.push({"front":"chier","back":"to sh*t, piss off, get pissed off"});
b.push({"front":"la pause","back":"break, pause"});
b.push({"front":"utile","back":"useful"});
b.push({"front":"la jambe","back":"leg"});
b.push({"front":"le bref","back":"brief"});
b.push({"front":"intelligent","back":"intelligent, clever, bright"});
b.push({"front":"le morceau","back":"piece, bit_"});
b.push({"front":"obligé","back":"necessary, required"});
b.push({"front":"la présence","back":"presence"});
b.push({"front":"le signal","back":"signal"});
b.push({"front":"raconter","back":"to tell"});
b.push({"front":"une identité","back":"identity"});
b.push({"front":"vendu","back":"sold, bribed"});
b.push({"front":"privé","back":"private"});
b.push({"front":"une entreprise","back":"enterprise, business"});
b.push({"front":"justement","back":"exactly, rightly, precisely"});
b.push({"front":"le cinéma","back":"cinema"});
b.push({"front":"le discours","back":"speech, talk, discourse"});
b.push({"front":"rapidement","back":"quickly, rapidly"});
b.push({"front":"le méchant","back":"nasty, wicked, mean"});
b.push({"front":"la campagne","back":"countryside"});
b.push({"front":"le regard","back":"look, glance"});
b.push({"front":"le lien","back":"link, bond"});
b.push({"front":"un appareil","back":"apparatus, device"});
b.push({"front":"un ange","back":"angel"});
b.push({"front":"le joie, la joie","back":"joy"});
b.push({"front":"compter","back":"to count"});
b.push({"front":"malgré","back":"despite, in spite of"});
b.push({"front":"reprendre","back":"to resume, recover, start again, take back"});
b.push({"front":"le nombre","back":"number"});
b.push({"front":"la star","back":"star"});
b.push({"front":"le chapeau","back":"hat"});
b.push({"front":"décider","back":"to decide"});
b.push({"front":"la menace","back":"threat"});
b.push({"front":"agir","back":"to act"});
b.push({"front":"le produit","back":"product"});
b.push({"front":"le vendredi","back":"Friday"});
b.push({"front":"malheureusement","back":"unfortunately"});
b.push({"front":"une odeur","back":"smell, odor"});
b.push({"front":"mince","back":"thin, slim, slender"});
b.push({"front":"fermé","back":"shut, closed, locked"});
b.push({"front":"une aise","back":"comfort, joy, pleasure, ease"});
b.push({"front":"la saison","back":"season"});
b.push({"front":"le succès","back":"success"});
b.push({"front":"gérer","back":"to manage"});
b.push({"front":"le pain","back":"bread"});
b.push({"front":"la règle","back":"rule"});
b.push({"front":"million","back":"million"});
b.push({"front":"parfaitement","back":"perfectly"});
b.push({"front":"le malin","back":"smart, shrewd, cunning"});
b.push({"front":"la majesté","back":"majesty"});
b.push({"front":"le toit","back":"roof"});
b.push({"front":"la faveur","back":"favor"});
b.push({"front":"doux","back":"soft, sweet"});
b.push({"front":"le coffre","back":"trunk, boot, chest"});
b.push({"front":"la couverture","back":"blanket"});
b.push({"front":"un arbre","back":"tree"});
b.push({"front":"réparer","back":"to repair, fix, correct, make up"});
b.push({"front":"un article","back":"article"});
b.push({"front":"lever","back":"to lift, raise"});
b.push({"front":"une unité","back":"unity; unit"});
b.push({"front":"un échange","back":"exchange"});
b.push({"front":"surpris","back":"surprised, amazed"});
b.push({"front":"le parc","back":"park"});
b.push({"front":"apporter","back":"to bring_"});
b.push({"front":"imaginer","back":"to imagine"});
b.push({"front":"le jardin","back":"garden"});
b.push({"front":"falloir","back":"to take, require, need"});
b.push({"front":"partager","back":"to share"});
b.push({"front":"la plage","back":"beach"});
b.push({"front":"échapper","back":"to escape"});
b.push({"front":"la valeur","back":"value, worth"});
b.push({"front":"également","back":"too, as well, equally"});
b.push({"front":"la folie","back":"madness, folly, insanity"});
b.push({"front":"le ministre, la ministre","back":"minister"});
b.push({"front":"le samedi","back":"Saturday"});
b.push({"front":"le mode, la mode","back":"mode, way, fashion"});
b.push({"front":"le maire, la maire","back":"mayor"});
b.push({"front":"un extérieur","back":"exterior"});
b.push({"front":"le génie","back":"genius"});
b.push({"front":"inquiéter","back":"to worry, disturb"});
b.push({"front":"recevoir","back":"to receive"});
b.push({"front":"un hasard","back":"chance, luck"});
b.push({"front":"un ouest","back":"west"});
b.push({"front":"le membre","back":"member"});
b.push({"front":"le réel","back":"real"});
b.push({"front":"le poids","back":"weight"});
b.push({"front":"prévenir","back":"to prevent, warn; to notify"});
b.push({"front":"la poche","back":"pocket"});
b.push({"front":"la vitesse","back":"speed"});
b.push({"front":"la frappe","back":"strike, striking, stamp, impression, punch"});
b.push({"front":"fantastique","back":"fantastic, terrific, great, weird, eerie"});
b.push({"front":"le fantôme","back":"ghost, phantom"});
b.push({"front":"la viande","back":"meat"});
b.push({"front":"le poulet","back":"chicken"});
b.push({"front":"le page, la page","back":"page"});
b.push({"front":"le trésor","back":"treasure, treasury"});
b.push({"front":"la file","back":"line, queue"});
b.push({"front":"abandonner","back":"to give up, abandon"});
b.push({"front":"embrasser","back":"to kiss, embrace"});
b.push({"front":"le dimanche","back":"Sunday"});
b.push({"front":"le passage","back":"passage, way"});
b.push({"front":"la naissance","back":"birth"});
b.push({"front":"amusant","back":"funny, amusing, entertaining"});
b.push({"front":"le cent","back":"one hundred, cent"});
b.push({"front":"la retraite","back":"retirement, pension"});
b.push({"front":"un étranger","back":"foreigner; foreign"});
b.push({"front":"le paradis","back":"paradise, heaven"});
b.push({"front":"directement","back":"directly"});
b.push({"front":"le champ","back":"field, realm"});
b.push({"front":"débarrasser","back":"to clear, get rid of"});
b.push({"front":"manquer","back":"to miss"});
b.push({"front":"le doigt","back":"finger"});
b.push({"front":"agréable","back":"pleasant, nice, agreeable"});
b.push({"front":"le changement","back":"change"});
b.push({"front":"un univers","back":"universe"});
b.push({"front":"le piège","back":"trap"});
b.push({"front":"la marque","back":"brand, mark"});
b.push({"front":"la perte","back":"the loss"});
b.push({"front":"créer","back":"to create"});
b.push({"front":"nettoyer","back":"to clean"});
b.push({"front":"la note","back":"note, grade"});
b.push({"front":"un animal","back":"animal"});
b.push({"front":"franchement","back":"frankly"});
b.push({"front":"le bâtiment","back":"building"});
b.push({"front":"le cancer","back":"cancer"});
b.push({"front":"heureusement","back":"fortunately, luckily"});
b.push({"front":"compliqué","back":"complicated, complex"});
b.push({"front":"la source","back":"source, spring"});
b.push({"front":"la connaissance","back":"knowledge"});
b.push({"front":"une émission","back":"transmission, broadcasting, programme"});
b.push({"front":"le mensonge","back":"the lie"});
b.push({"front":"joindre","back":"to join"});
b.push({"front":"convaincre","back":"to convince"});
b.push({"front":"nerveux","back":"nervous, irritable"});
b.push({"front":"le pantalon","back":"trousers, pants"});
b.push({"front":"vôtre","back":"yours"});
b.push({"front":"la bataille","back":"battle"});
b.push({"front":"la conscience","back":"conscience, consciousness"});
b.push({"front":"le sentiment","back":"the feel"});
b.push({"front":"le salon","back":"lounge, living room"});
b.push({"front":"le traitement","back":"treatment, salary, wage"});
b.push({"front":"la volonté","back":"will"});
b.push({"front":"un interdit","back":"prohibited, banned"});
b.push({"front":"direct","back":"direct"});
b.push({"front":"le cousin","back":"cousin"});
b.push({"front":"le souci","back":"worry, concern"});
b.push({"front":"la lance","back":"lance"});
b.push({"front":"signer","back":"to sign"});
b.push({"front":"contrôler","back":"to control, check, inspect, monitor"});
b.push({"front":"reposer","back":"to rest"});
b.push({"front":"le gaz","back":"gas"});
b.push({"front":"la victoire","back":"victory"});
b.push({"front":"la trace","back":"trace, mark, track"});
b.push({"front":"une information","back":"information"});
b.push({"front":"la queue","back":"tail, handle, stalk, stem, rear"});
b.push({"front":"désormais","back":"from now on, henceforth, now"});
b.push({"front":"un acte","back":"act"});
b.push({"front":"le paquet","back":"packet"});
b.push({"front":"le semblant","back":"semblance, pretence"});
b.push({"front":"le style","back":"style"});
b.push({"front":"un aéroport","back":"airport"});
b.push({"front":"supporter","back":"to support, endure"});
b.push({"front":"le chinois","back":"Chinese"});
b.push({"front":"innocent","back":"innocent"});
b.push({"front":"autrement","back":"differently, something else, otherwise"});
b.push({"front":"le suicide","back":"suicide"});
b.push({"front":"lancer","back":"to launch"});
b.push({"front":"la théorie","back":"theory"});
b.push({"front":"un immeuble","back":"building"});
b.push({"front":"le métier","back":"job, occupation, trade"});
b.push({"front":"un aveugle, une aveugle","back":"blind"});
b.push({"front":"la leçon","back":"lesson"});
b.push({"front":"le militaire","back":"military"});
b.push({"front":"la protection","back":"protection"});
b.push({"front":"le propriétaire, la propriétaire","back":"owner"});
b.push({"front":"le mandat","back":"term, mandate"});
b.push({"front":"la surveillance","back":"surveillance, monitoring"});
b.push({"front":"le pilote, la pilote","back":"pilot, experimental"});
b.push({"front":"fuir","back":"to flee"});
b.push({"front":"un oiseau","back":"bird"});
b.push({"front":"retirer","back":"to remove, withdraw"});
b.push({"front":"récemment","back":"recently"});
b.push({"front":"un assassin","back":"murderer, assassin"});
b.push({"front":"célèbre","back":"famous"});
b.push({"front":"défendre","back":"to defend, forbid"});
b.push({"front":"le vert","back":"green"});
b.push({"front":"une assurance","back":"insurance, confidence"});
b.push({"front":"charmant","back":"charming"});
b.push({"front":"la chemise","back":"shirt, folder"});
b.push({"front":"le ventre","back":"belly, stomach"});
b.push({"front":"le sport","back":"sport"});
b.push({"front":"un est","back":"east"});
b.push({"front":"commun","back":"common"});
b.push({"front":"atteindre","back":"to reach, to attain"});
b.push({"front":"virer","back":"to turn, change, transfer, kick out"});
b.push({"front":"la pluie","back":"rain"});
b.push({"front":"le talent","back":"talent"});
b.push({"front":"le jury","back":"jury, board of examiners"});
b.push({"front":"la commande","back":"order, control"});
b.push({"front":"la tente","back":"tent"});
b.push({"front":"la couche","back":"layer, coat"});
b.push({"front":"le voleur","back":"thief, light-fingered"});
b.push({"front":"le chocolat","back":"chocolate"});
b.push({"front":"réveiller","back":"to wake up"});
b.push({"front":"la souris","back":"mouse"});
b.push({"front":"accusé","back":"defendant"});
b.push({"front":"le terme","back":"term, deadline"});
b.push({"front":"un emploi","back":"employment, work, use"});
b.push({"front":"un ombre, une ombre","back":"shade, shadow"});
b.push({"front":"le repos","back":"rest"});
b.push({"front":"blesser","back":"to hurt"});
b.push({"front":"la neige","back":"snow"});
b.push({"front":"le lundi","back":"Monday"});
b.push({"front":"le théâtre","back":"theater"});
b.push({"front":"permettre","back":"to allow"});
b.push({"front":"le policier","back":"policeman"});
b.push({"front":"surveiller","back":"to watch"});
b.push({"front":"le saint","back":"saint, holy"});
b.push({"front":"la chaise","back":"chair"});
b.push({"front":"réfléchi","back":"thoughtful, well thought out"});
b.push({"front":"le site","back":"site"});
b.push({"front":"une hâte","back":"haste, impatience"});
b.push({"front":"le zéro","back":"zero"});
b.push({"front":"facilement","back":"easily"});
b.push({"front":"un épisode","back":"episode"});
b.push({"front":"le siège","back":"seat, bench"});
b.push({"front":"la traduction","back":"translation"});
b.push({"front":"la montagne","back":"mountain"});
b.push({"front":"la gorge","back":"throat"});
b.push({"front":"le sommeil","back":"sleep, sleepiness"});
b.push({"front":"la rivière","back":"river"});
b.push({"front":"le miracle","back":"miracle"});
b.push({"front":"le titre","back":"title"});
b.push({"front":"le second","back":"second"});
b.push({"front":"la cellule","back":"cell"});
b.push({"front":"le mouvement","back":"movement"});
b.push({"front":"la mine","back":"mine; appearance, look"});
b.push({"front":"clairement","back":"clearly"});
b.push({"front":"le choc","back":"shock, clash"});
b.push({"front":"la fortune","back":"fortune"});
b.push({"front":"le divorce","back":"divorce"});
b.push({"front":"un ours","back":"bear"});
b.push({"front":"exploser","back":"to explode, blow up"});
b.push({"front":"évident","back":"obvious"});
b.push({"front":"le minuit","back":"midnight"});
b.push({"front":"un examen","back":"exam"});
b.push({"front":"respirer","back":"to breath"});
b.push({"front":"le tableau","back":"frame, picture, painting, panel"});
b.push({"front":"le plat","back":"dish, flat"});
b.push({"front":"le meurtrier","back":"murderer, deadly, lethal"});
b.push({"front":"survivre","back":"to survive"});
b.push({"front":"auprès","back":"nearby, close to"});
b.push({"front":"le principal","back":"principal"});
b.push({"front":"la forêt","back":"forest"});
b.push({"front":"la violence","back":"violence"});
b.push({"front":"une amitié","back":"friendship"});
b.push({"front":"la blessure","back":"injury, wound"});
b.push({"front":"la distance","back":"distance"});
b.push({"front":"une humeur","back":"mood, temper"});
b.push({"front":"le modèle","back":"model"});
b.push({"front":"le démon","back":"demon, fiend"});
b.push({"front":"la puissance","back":"power"});
b.push({"front":"casser","back":"to break"});
b.push({"front":"le romantique, la romantique","back":"romantic"});
b.push({"front":"la responsabilité","back":"responsibility"});
b.push({"front":"le crédit","back":"credit"});
b.push({"front":"crier","back":"to shout, scream, cry out"});
b.push({"front":"le concert","back":"concert"});
b.push({"front":"pousser","back":"to push"});
b.push({"front":"le tir","back":"fire, shot, launch"});
b.push({"front":"la fuite","back":"the escape_"});
b.push({"front":"la gare","back":"station, railway station; beware"});
b.push({"front":"le midi","back":"noon"});
b.push({"front":"la permission","back":"permission, leave"});
b.push({"front":"le dessous","back":"underneath, below, bottom, underside"});
b.push({"front":"une explosion","back":"explosion"});
b.push({"front":"une annonce","back":"announcement"});
b.push({"front":"le secrétaire, la secrétaire","back":"secretary"});
b.push({"front":"le chauffeur","back":"driver, chauffeur"});
b.push({"front":"une oreille","back":"ear"});
b.push({"front":"attaquer","back":"to attack"});
b.push({"front":"le cabinet","back":"cabinet, agency, office"});
b.push({"front":"une usine","back":"factory"});
b.push({"front":"nombreux","back":"numerous"});
b.push({"front":"la vache","back":"cow"});
b.push({"front":"prudent","back":"prudent, careful, cautious"});
b.push({"front":"la station","back":"station"});
b.push({"front":"la vente","back":"sale"});
b.push({"front":"la logique","back":"logic, logical"});
b.push({"front":"le sage, la sage","back":"wise, good, sound, sensible"});
b.push({"front":"le souffle","back":"breath, puff"});
b.push({"front":"la rentrée","back":"reopening, return, start"});
b.push({"front":"le liquide","back":"liquid"});
b.push({"front":"libérer","back":"to free, liberate, release"});
b.push({"front":"la mesure","back":"measure"});
b.push({"front":"le garage","back":"garage"});
b.push({"front":"la vision","back":"vision, view"});
b.push({"front":"le château","back":"castle"});
b.push({"front":"le physique, la physique","back":"physical, physics"});
b.push({"front":"une alerte","back":"agile, alert, warning"});
b.push({"front":"le moteur","back":"motor"});
b.push({"front":"le fer","back":"iron"});
b.push({"front":"la version","back":"version"});
b.push({"front":"le lac","back":"lake"});
b.push({"front":"le canon","back":"gun, cannon"});
b.push({"front":"réellement","back":"really"});
b.push({"front":"un artiste, une artiste","back":"artist"});
b.push({"front":"la côte","back":"coast"});
b.push({"front":"quiconque","back":"whoever, anyone who"});
b.push({"front":"la chaleur","back":"the heat"});
b.push({"front":"une essence","back":"gas, petrol"});
b.push({"front":"le soutien","back":"the support_"});
b.push({"front":"le particulier","back":"particular, peculiar; person"});
b.push({"front":"traiter","back":"to treat, handle, deal with"});
b.push({"front":"le fusil","back":"rifle, gun"});
b.push({"front":"une herbe","back":"grass, herb"});
b.push({"front":"le virus","back":"virus"});
b.push({"front":"la tournée","back":"tour, round"});
b.push({"front":"traverser","back":"to cross, traverse"});
b.push({"front":"sombre","back":"dark"});
b.push({"front":"bosser","back":"to work, bash on"});
b.push({"front":"avancer","back":"to advance, move forward"});
b.push({"front":"puissant","back":"powerful"});
b.push({"front":"cependant","back":"however"});
b.push({"front":"construire","back":"to build, construct"});
b.push({"front":"une agence","back":"agency"});
b.push({"front":"le criminel","back":"criminal"});
b.push({"front":"le chèque","back":"check"});
b.push({"front":"le comportement","back":"behavior"});
b.push({"front":"le période, la période","back":"period"});
b.push({"front":"le lendemain","back":"next day"});
b.push({"front":"disparaître","back":"to disappear, vanish"});
b.push({"front":"fumer","back":"to smoke"});
b.push({"front":"inviter","back":"to invite"});
b.push({"front":"souffrir","back":"to suffer"});
b.push({"front":"le rock","back":"rock music"});
b.push({"front":"le fromage","back":"cheese"});
b.push({"front":"un adulte, une adulte","back":"adult"});
b.push({"front":"le billet","back":"ticket"});
b.push({"front":"résoudre","back":"to solve, resolve"});
b.push({"front":"la chair","back":"flesh"});
b.push({"front":"le résultat","back":"result, follow-up"});
b.push({"front":"taire","back":"to keep quiet"});
b.push({"front":"déranger","back":"to disturb, bother"});
b.push({"front":"le concours","back":"entrance exam, competition"});
b.push({"front":"le crâne","back":"skull"});
b.push({"front":"élevé","back":"high, heavy, tall"});
b.push({"front":"une attente","back":"the wait"});
b.push({"front":"le russe","back":"Russian"});
b.push({"front":"la chaîne","back":"chain, channel"});
b.push({"front":"le gardien","back":"guardian, keeper"});
b.push({"front":"laver","back":"to wash, clean"});
b.push({"front":"le gouverneur, la gouverneur","back":"governor"});
b.push({"front":"enfuir","back":"to run away, flee"});
b.push({"front":"une arrestation","back":"arrest"});
b.push({"front":"une enfance","back":"childhood"});
b.push({"front":"le demi","back":"half"});
b.push({"front":"un objet","back":"objective; object"});
b.push({"front":"le sénateur","back":"senator"});
b.push({"front":"profiter","back":"to take advantage, profit"});
b.push({"front":"le vote","back":"vote"});
b.push({"front":"la caisse","back":"cash desk, box"});
b.push({"front":"la science","back":"science"});
b.push({"front":"la poitrine","back":"chest, breast, breasts, bosom"});
b.push({"front":"magique","back":"magic; magical"});
b.push({"front":"inquiet","back":"worried, anxious"});
b.push({"front":"le sucre","back":"sugar"});
b.push({"front":"le siècle","back":"century"});
b.push({"front":"le geste, la geste","back":"gesture"});
b.push({"front":"étudier","back":"to study"});
b.push({"front":"la réputation","back":"reputation"});
b.push({"front":"forcément","back":"without question, inevitably"});
b.push({"front":"le traité","back":"treaty"});
b.push({"front":"refaire","back":"to redo, make again"});
b.push({"front":"le département","back":"department"});
b.push({"front":"la cloche","back":"bell"});
b.push({"front":"la chute","back":"fall"});
b.push({"front":"le joueur","back":"player"});
b.push({"front":"la peinture","back":"painting, paint, picture"});
b.push({"front":"une horreur","back":"horror"});
b.push({"front":"la tenue","back":"dress, outfit"});
b.push({"front":"la marine","back":"marine, navy"});
b.push({"front":"la promesse","back":"promise"});
b.push({"front":"la barre","back":"bar, rod"});
b.push({"front":"la plainte","back":"the moan, groan, complaint"});
b.push({"front":"la soupe","back":"soup"});
b.push({"front":"le studio","back":"studio, studio apartment"});
b.push({"front":"une opinion","back":"opinion"});
b.push({"front":"le crème, la crème","back":"cream"});
b.push({"front":"le foyer","back":"home, hearth"});
b.push({"front":"le somme, la somme","back":"amount, sum; nap"});
b.push({"front":"le manteau","back":"coat, overcoat"});
b.push({"front":"un incendie","back":"fire, blaze"});
b.push({"front":"le journaliste, la journaliste","back":"journalist"});
b.push({"front":"une aventure","back":"adventure"});
b.push({"front":"mener","back":"to lead"});
b.push({"front":"le cauchemar","back":"nightmare, bad dream"});
b.push({"front":"un uniforme","back":"uniform, steady, regular"});
b.push({"front":"le prêtre","back":"priest"});
b.push({"front":"le scientifique, la scientifique","back":"scientific"});
b.push({"front":"réglé","back":"regular, steady, well-ordered, ruled"});
b.push({"front":"la corde","back":"rope, chord, string"});
b.push({"front":"la propriété","back":"property"});
b.push({"front":"recommencer","back":"to resume, restart"});
b.push({"front":"calmer","back":"to calm down"});
b.push({"front":"deviner","back":"to guess, solve"});
b.push({"front":"un hiver","back":"winter"});
b.push({"front":"le champion","back":"champion"});
b.push({"front":"la conférence","back":"conference"});
b.push({"front":"complet","back":"full, complete; suit"});
b.push({"front":"le couloir","back":"corridor, aisle"});
b.push({"front":"le matériel","back":"material, equipment"});
b.push({"front":"admettre","back":"to admit"});
b.push({"front":"la foule","back":"crowd"});
b.push({"front":"la réaction","back":"reaction"});
b.push({"front":"le désert","back":"desert, wilderness"});
b.push({"front":"le réseau","back":"network"});
b.push({"front":"le commissaire, la commissaire","back":"superintendent, commissioner"});
b.push({"front":"un entraînement","back":"training, coaching, drive"});
b.push({"front":"ex","back":"ex"});
b.push({"front":"le fonds","back":"funds"});
b.push({"front":"le cadavre","back":"corpse"});
b.push({"front":"pardonner","back":"to forgive, excuse"});
b.push({"front":"uniquement","back":"only, uniquely"});
b.push({"front":"la liaison","back":"liaison, connection"});
b.push({"front":"traîner","back":"to drag; to hang out"});
b.push({"front":"le vélo","back":"bike, bicycle"});
b.push({"front":"la discussion","back":"discussion"});
b.push({"front":"filer","back":"slip, get out"});
b.push({"front":"soi","back":"one, oneself, self"});
b.push({"front":"répéter","back":"to repeat"});
b.push({"front":"la boutique","back":"shop"});
b.push({"front":"le front","back":"front, forehead"});
b.push({"front":"le curieux","back":"curious"});
b.push({"front":"le mardi","back":"Tuesday"});
b.push({"front":"un empire","back":"empire"});
b.push({"front":"la médecine","back":"medecine, medical science"});
b.push({"front":"le ménage","back":"housekeeping, housework"});
b.push({"front":"soudain","back":"sudden, suddenly"});
b.push({"front":"le ballon","back":"ball"});
b.push({"front":"combattre","back":"to fight"});
b.push({"front":"remonter","back":"to go back up (previously)"});
b.push({"front":"un acteur","back":"actor"});
b.push({"front":"rare","back":"rare"});
b.push({"front":"le bouton","back":"button, knob, spot"});
b.push({"front":"la tâche","back":"task"});
b.push({"front":"réussir","back":"to succeed"});
b.push({"front":"conseiller","back":"adviser, to advise"});
b.push({"front":"la cérémonie","back":"ceremony"});
b.push({"front":"brûler","back":"to burn"});
b.push({"front":"couvrir","back":"to cover"});
b.push({"front":"un océan","back":"ocean"});
b.push({"front":"rater","back":"to miss, misfire"});
b.push({"front":"la communauté","back":"community"});
b.push({"front":"le prisonnier","back":"prisoner, captive"});
b.push({"front":"le prénom","back":"first name"});
b.push({"front":"la surface","back":"surface"});
b.push({"front":"la gloire","back":"glory, fame"});
b.push({"front":"lourd","back":"heavy"});
b.push({"front":"remplacer","back":"to replace"});
b.push({"front":"affreux","back":"dreadful, awful, horrible"});
b.push({"front":"une humanité","back":"humanity"});
b.push({"front":"le tapis","back":"carpet, mat, covering"});
b.push({"front":"la réserve","back":"reserve"});
b.push({"front":"tenter","back":"to tempt, try"});
b.push({"front":"le véhicule","back":"vehicule"});
b.push({"front":"la déclaration","back":"declaration"});
b.push({"front":"réaliser","back":"to realize, achieve"});
b.push({"front":"lâcher","back":"to let go, release"});
b.push({"front":"la baisse","back":"the fall of, the drop of"});
b.push({"front":"venger","back":"to avenge, take revenge"});
b.push({"front":"installer","back":"to install"});
b.push({"front":"brillant","back":"brilliant"});
b.push({"front":"un inconnu","back":"unknown"});
b.push({"front":"la récompense","back":"reward, award"});
b.push({"front":"poursuivre","back":"to pursue"});
b.push({"front":"la frontière","back":"border"});
b.push({"front":"traite","back":"trade, draft, stretch, milking"});
b.push({"front":"le loup","back":"wolf"});
b.push({"front":"le navire","back":"ship"});
b.push({"front":"une origine","back":"origin, source"});
b.push({"front":"la fleur","back":"flower"});
b.push({"front":"une absence","back":"absence"});
b.push({"front":"la pratique","back":"practice, practical"});
b.push({"front":"le jeudi","back":"Thursday"});
b.push({"front":"le célibataire, la célibataire","back":"single, unmarried"});
b.push({"front":"attirer","back":"to attract"});
b.push({"front":"étonnant","back":"surprising, amazing, incredible__"});
b.push({"front":"la vengeance","back":"revenge"});
b.push({"front":"le professionnel","back":"professional"});
b.push({"front":"la veille","back":"the day before, the eve of, night watch"});
b.push({"front":"le salaire","back":"salary, wage"});
b.push({"front":"le rythme","back":"rhythm, rate"});
b.push({"front":"la tempête","back":"storm, gale, turmoil"});
b.push({"front":"la lutte","back":"struggle, fight, conflict"});
b.push({"front":"accompagner","back":"to accompany"});
b.push({"front":"la ceinture","back":"belt, waist"});
b.push({"front":"la panique","back":"panic"});
b.push({"front":"une opportunité","back":"opportunity, timeliness"});
b.push({"front":"le personnage","back":"character, individual"});
b.push({"front":"le mars","back":"March; Mars"});
b.push({"front":"le vingt","back":"twenty"});
b.push({"front":"profond","back":"deep"});
b.push({"front":"nourrir","back":"to feed, nourish"});
b.push({"front":"le singe","back":"monkey"});
b.push({"front":"la pêche","back":"fishing; peach"});
b.push({"front":"une haine","back":"hatred, hate"});
b.push({"front":"tromper","back":"to deceive_"});
b.push({"front":"le pis","back":"worse"});
b.push({"front":"un écran","back":"screen"});
b.push({"front":"assistant","back":"assistant"});
b.push({"front":"le malheur","back":"misfortune, bad luck"});
b.push({"front":"le couvert","back":"covered, overcast; place, seat, cutlery"});
b.push({"front":"le porc","back":"pig, pork"});
b.push({"front":"une explication","back":"explanation"});
b.push({"front":"la limite","back":"limit"});
b.push({"front":"un entretien","back":"interview, discussion, maintenance"});
b.push({"front":"la région","back":"region"});
b.push({"front":"vierge","back":"virgin"});
b.push({"front":"le comité","back":"committee"});
b.push({"front":"la cigarette","back":"cigarette"});
b.push({"front":"le palais","back":"palace, palate"});
b.push({"front":"identifier","back":"to identify"});
b.push({"front":"gâcher","back":"to waste, spoil"});
b.push({"front":"quant","back":"as for"});
b.push({"front":"annoncer","back":"to announce"});
b.push({"front":"le bloc","back":"block"});
b.push({"front":"un élève, une élève","back":"pupil, student"});
b.push({"front":"engager","back":"to hire, involve"});
b.push({"front":"le masque","back":"mask"});
b.push({"front":"extraordinaire","back":"extraordinary"});
b.push({"front":"un incident","back":"incident"});
b.push({"front":"la monnaie","back":"currency, coin, change"});
b.push({"front":"le temple","back":"temple"});
b.push({"front":"davantage","back":"more"});
b.push({"front":"final","back":"final"});
b.push({"front":"une alarme","back":"alarm"});
b.push({"front":"le roman","back":"novel"});
b.push({"front":"le classique","back":"classic"});
b.push({"front":"la soif","back":"thirst"});
b.push({"front":"normalement","back":"normally"});
b.push({"front":"naturel","back":"natural"});
b.push({"front":"le piano","back":"piano"});
b.push({"front":"la passion","back":"passion"});
b.push({"front":"le pot","back":"jar, pot"});
b.push({"front":"le japonais","back":"Japanese"});
b.push({"front":"la technique","back":"technique, technics, technical"});
b.push({"front":"une étoile","back":"star"});
b.push({"front":"concentrer","back":"to concentrate"});
b.push({"front":"le voisin","back":"neighbor"});
b.push({"front":"la créature","back":"creature"});
b.push({"front":"entièrement","back":"entirely, completely"});
b.push({"front":"le volant","back":"steering wheel"});
b.push({"front":"la portée","back":"range, reach, scope"});
b.push({"front":"le courrier","back":"mail, post"});
b.push({"front":"central","back":"central"});
b.push({"front":"affronter","back":"to confront, face"});
b.push({"front":"impressionnant","back":"impressive, upsetting"});
b.push({"front":"le golf","back":"golf, golf course"});
b.push({"front":"le jaune","back":"yellow"});
b.push({"front":"la bibliothèque","back":"library"});
b.push({"front":"lentement","back":"slowly"});
b.push({"front":"personnellement","back":"personally"});
b.push({"front":"le mystère","back":"mystery"});
b.push({"front":"la clinique","back":"clinic"});
b.push({"front":"une étape","back":"the step, the stage of"});
b.push({"front":"la fumée","back":"smoke"});
b.push({"front":"le royaume","back":"kingdom"});
b.push({"front":"la qualité","back":"quality"});
b.push({"front":"la tension","back":"tension"});
b.push({"front":"courageux","back":"courageous"});
b.push({"front":"le port","back":"harbour, port"});
b.push({"front":"une alliance","back":"alliance"});
b.push({"front":"la copie","back":"copy, replica, paper"});
b.push({"front":"un essai","back":"attempt, try, test"});
b.push({"front":"un expert","back":"expert"});
b.push({"front":"le désir","back":"desire"});
b.push({"front":"avouer","back":"to admit_"});
b.push({"front":"la conduite","back":"behavior, driving"});
b.push({"front":"un hall","back":"foyer, lobby"});
b.push({"front":"soigner","back":"to treat, look after, take care over"});
b.push({"front":"contacter","back":"to contact, get in touch with"});
b.push({"front":"la pile","back":"pile, stack, battery, tails"});
b.push({"front":"approcher","back":"to approach"});
b.push({"front":"le disque","back":"disc"});
b.push({"front":"le jugement","back":"judgement"});
b.push({"front":"un équipage","back":"crew, gear"});
b.push({"front":"une analyse","back":"analysis"});
b.push({"front":"une aube","back":"dawn, daybreak"});
b.push({"front":"la section","back":"section"});
b.push({"front":"la cage","back":"cage"});
b.push({"front":"le miroir","back":"mirror"});
b.push({"front":"une épreuve","back":"test, ordeal, trial"});
b.push({"front":"la condition","back":"condition"});
b.push({"front":"remplir","back":"to fill, fulfill"});
b.push({"front":"une existence","back":"existence"});
b.push({"front":"égal","back":"equal"});
b.push({"front":"retenir","back":"to retain, hold back, remember"});
b.push({"front":"le précis","back":"precise"});
b.push({"front":"annuler","back":"to cancel"});
b.push({"front":"le rayon","back":"ray, beam, radius; department, section, shelf"});
b.push({"front":"le football","back":"football, soccer"});
b.push({"front":"une assise","back":"basis, foundation"});
b.push({"front":"le secteur","back":"sector"});
b.push({"front":"la séance","back":"session, meeting"});
b.push({"front":"le profil","back":"profile, outline, contour"});
b.push({"front":"la valise","back":"suitcase"});
b.push({"front":"un avantage","back":"advantage"});
b.push({"front":"le nu","back":"naked, nude"});
b.push({"front":"la technologie","back":"technology"});
b.push({"front":"la procédure","back":"procedure"});
b.push({"front":"la pointe","back":"point, tip"});
b.push({"front":"le cochon","back":"pig"});
b.push({"front":"la figure","back":"face; figure"});
b.push({"front":"la patience","back":"patience"});
b.push({"front":"la poussière","back":"dust"});
b.push({"front":"le printemps","back":"spring"});
b.push({"front":"interroger","back":"to question, interrogate"});
b.push({"front":"une accusation","back":"accusation, indictment"});
b.push({"front":"un intéressé","back":"concerned, involved"});
b.push({"front":"idéal","back":"ideal"});
b.push({"front":"la poule","back":"hen, chick"});
b.push({"front":"correct","back":"correct"});
b.push({"front":"briser","back":"to break"});
b.push({"front":"le boule, la boule","back":"ball"});
b.push({"front":"le partage","back":"division, cutting, sharing"});
b.push({"front":"le mobile","back":"mobile, portable"});
b.push({"front":"la proposition","back":"proposition, proposal"});
b.push({"front":"une objection","back":"objection"});
b.push({"front":"le sauvage","back":"savage, wild"});
b.push({"front":"le rat","back":"rat"});
b.push({"front":"urgent","back":"urgent"});
b.push({"front":"reconnaître","back":"to recognize"});
b.push({"front":"la œuvre","back":"work, task"});
b.push({"front":"un échec","back":"failure"});
b.push({"front":"une attitude","back":"attitude"});
b.push({"front":"la paire","back":"pair"});
b.push({"front":"médical","back":"medical"});
b.push({"front":"suffisamment","back":"sufficiently"});
b.push({"front":"la fièvre","back":"fever"});
b.push({"front":"la télévision","back":"television"});
b.push({"front":"le magazine","back":"magazine"});
b.push({"front":"auparavant","back":"beforehand"});
b.push({"front":"séparer","back":"to separate"});
b.push({"front":"le musée","back":"museum"});
b.push({"front":"juger","back":"to judge"});
b.push({"front":"carrément","back":"(emphasis word) completely, directly, straight out"});
b.push({"front":"une épaule","back":"shoulder"});
b.push({"front":"la plaque","back":"plate, tag, plaque"});
b.push({"front":"organiser","back":"to organize"});
b.push({"front":"le sable","back":"sand"});
b.push({"front":"la légende","back":"legend, caption, key"});
b.push({"front":"la possibilité","back":"possibility"});
b.push({"front":"diriger","back":"to lead, direct"});
b.push({"front":"une éducation","back":"education"});
b.push({"front":"une imagination","back":"imagination"});
b.push({"front":"le maximum","back":"maximum"});
b.push({"front":"le collègue, la collègue","back":"colleague"});
b.push({"front":"ajouter","back":"to add"});
b.push({"front":"une audience","back":"audience, hearing"});
b.push({"front":"visiter","back":"to visit"});
b.push({"front":"le beurre","back":"butter"});
b.push({"front":"une organisation","back":"organisation"});
b.push({"front":"exprès","back":"deliberately, on purpose, intentionally_"});
b.push({"front":"le camarade, la camarade","back":"friend, comrade, pal, mate"});
b.push({"front":"le domaine","back":"domain, field"});
b.push({"front":"un empereur","back":"emperor"});
b.push({"front":"profondément","back":"profoundly, deeply"});
b.push({"front":"un effort","back":"effort"});
b.push({"front":"le cirque","back":"circus; cirque"});
b.push({"front":"terminer","back":"to finish, end,"});
b.push({"front":"déposer","back":"to deposit, put down"});
b.push({"front":"la balance","back":"scales, balance"});
b.push({"front":"raisonnable","back":"reasonable, fair"});
b.push({"front":"refuser","back":"to refuse"});
b.push({"front":"sensible","back":"sensitive"});
b.push({"front":"forcer","back":"to force"});
b.push({"front":"malheureux","back":"unhappy, miserable"});
b.push({"front":"le critique, la critique","back":"criticism, critic, critical"});
b.push({"front":"la pensée","back":"thought"});
b.push({"front":"chasser","back":"to hunt, chase away"});
b.push({"front":"la disparition","back":"disappearance"});
b.push({"front":"un ordinaire","back":"ordinary"});
b.push({"front":"un étudiant","back":"student"});
b.push({"front":"un orange, une orange","back":"orange"});
b.push({"front":"la coïncidence","back":"coincidence"});
b.push({"front":"voyager","back":"to travel"});
b.push({"front":"fêter","back":"to celebrate"});
b.push({"front":"un allemand","back":"German"});
b.push({"front":"le congé","back":"holiday, time off, day off, notice"});
b.push({"front":"la thérapie","back":"therapy"});
b.push({"front":"la croix","back":"cross"});
b.push({"front":"une autorisation","back":"authorization, permission, permit"});
b.push({"front":"le scénario","back":"scenario, script"});
b.push({"front":"le parfum","back":"perfume, scent, fragrance"});
b.push({"front":"adorer","back":"to adore, worship"});
b.push({"front":"la donnée","back":"fact, datum"});
b.push({"front":"le portefeuille","back":"wallet"});
b.push({"front":"une huile","back":"oil"});
b.push({"front":"examiner","back":"to examine"});
b.push({"front":"le solide","back":"solid"});
b.push({"front":"extrêmement","back":"extremely"});
b.push({"front":"guérir","back":"to cure, heal, get better"});
b.push({"front":"le géant","back":"giant, gigantic"});
b.push({"front":"emprunter","back":"to borrow"});
b.push({"front":"publique","back":"public"});
b.push({"front":"le poil","back":"hair, bristle"});
b.push({"front":"entraîner","back":"to carry along, train"});
b.push({"front":"taper","back":"to beat, slam, bang, type"});
b.push({"front":"digne","back":"dignified, worthy"});
b.push({"front":"le stade","back":"stadium, stage"});
b.push({"front":"renvoyer","back":"to send back, dismiss"});
b.push({"front":"le large","back":"wide; the width"});
b.push({"front":"le taux","back":"the rate of"});
b.push({"front":"armé","back":"armed"});
b.push({"front":"le loyer","back":"rent"});
b.push({"front":"la jeunesse","back":"youth"});
b.push({"front":"une adaptation","back":"adaptation"});
b.push({"front":"le détail","back":"detail"});
b.push({"front":"le juif","back":"Jew, Jewish"});
b.push({"front":"éloigner","back":"to move away, take away, distance"});
b.push({"front":"livrer","back":"to deliver"});
b.push({"front":"le moral","back":"moral, morale"});
b.push({"front":"un incapable","back":"incapable, incompetent"});
b.push({"front":"une invitation","back":"invitation"});
b.push({"front":"le péché","back":"sin"});
b.push({"front":"le cercle","back":"circle, cycle"});
b.push({"front":"le territoire","back":"territory"});
b.push({"front":"le plateau","back":"plateau, tray, set, stage"});
b.push({"front":"éliminer","back":"to eliminate"});
b.push({"front":"le supérieur","back":"superior"});
b.push({"front":"suffisant","back":"sufficient"});
b.push({"front":"le viol","back":"rape"});
b.push({"front":"une ouverture","back":"opening"});
b.push({"front":"furieux","back":"furious, raging, violent"});
b.push({"front":"un exercice","back":"exercise,"});
b.push({"front":"respecter","back":"to respect"});
b.push({"front":"une expression","back":"expression"});
b.push({"front":"un original","back":"original"});
b.push({"front":"la remise","back":"presentation, delivery"});
b.push({"front":"le tribu, la tribu","back":"tribe"});
b.push({"front":"la cabine","back":"hut, cubicle, booth, box, room"});
b.push({"front":"la race","back":"breed, race"});
b.push({"front":"la tentative","back":"the attempt"});
b.push({"front":"le décès","back":"death_"});
b.push({"front":"le cap","back":"cape"});
b.push({"front":"la bourse","back":"purse, scholarship"});
b.push({"front":"le populaire","back":"popular"});
b.push({"front":"la signature","back":"signature"});
b.push({"front":"sexuel","back":"sexual"});
b.push({"front":"un humour","back":"humour"});
b.push({"front":"le cave, la cave","back":"cellar, basement"});
b.push({"front":"précieux","back":"precious"});
b.push({"front":"la matière","back":"matter, subject, material"});
b.push({"front":"la cassette","back":"cassette"});
b.push({"front":"injuste","back":"unfair, unjust"});
b.push({"front":"la réception","back":"reception"});
b.push({"front":"le sommet","back":"summit"});
b.push({"front":"un employé","back":"employee"});
b.push({"front":"le progrès","back":"progress"});
b.push({"front":"le mercredi","back":"Wednesday"});
b.push({"front":"un angle","back":"angle, point of view"});
b.push({"front":"un instinct","back":"instinct"});
b.push({"front":"officiellement","back":"officially"});
b.push({"front":"nôtre","back":"ours, our own"});
b.push({"front":"la panne","back":"the breakdown, the failure (of a machine)"});
b.push({"front":"la compétition","back":"competition"});
b.push({"front":"illégal","back":"illegal"});
b.push({"front":"électrique","back":"electric"});
b.push({"front":"participer","back":"to participate"});
b.push({"front":"la comédie","back":"comedy, playacting"});
b.push({"front":"témoigner","back":"to testify"});
b.push({"front":"la nation","back":"nation"});
b.push({"front":"la commission","back":"commission"});
b.push({"front":"rattraper","back":"to recapture, recover, catch up, make up for"});
b.push({"front":"la poudre","back":"powder"});
b.push({"front":"un objectif","back":"objective, aim, goal; lens"});
b.push({"front":"un accueil","back":"welcome, reception"});
b.push({"front":"une union","back":"union"});
b.push({"front":"le témoignage","back":"testimony"});
b.push({"front":"ranger","back":"to tidy up, put away"});
b.push({"front":"absurde","back":"absurd"});
b.push({"front":"le trafic","back":"traffic, circulation"});
b.push({"front":"une agression","back":"agression"});
b.push({"front":"déplacer","back":"to move, displace"});
b.push({"front":"la division","back":"division"});
b.push({"front":"élever","back":"to grow, lift, raise"});
b.push({"front":"un enregistrement","back":"recording, registration, check-in, logging"});
b.push({"front":"pur","back":"pure"});
b.push({"front":"durer","back":"to last"});
b.push({"front":"le comte","back":"the count"});
b.push({"front":"négatif","back":"negative"});
b.push({"front":"le gagnant","back":"winner, winning"});
b.push({"front":"le langage","back":"language"});
b.push({"front":"le noble, la noble","back":"noble"});
b.push({"front":"une échelle","back":"ladder, scale"});
b.push({"front":"la température","back":"temperature"});
b.push({"front":"prier","back":"to pray"});
b.push({"front":"un indice","back":"indication, sign, clue"});
b.push({"front":"la matinée","back":"morning"});
b.push({"front":"le guide, la guide","back":"guide"});
b.push({"front":"la souffrance","back":"suffering"});
b.push({"front":"le finale, finale","back":"finale, final event"});
b.push({"front":"une influence","back":"influence"});
b.push({"front":"une autorité","back":"authority"});
b.push({"front":"la production","back":"production"});
b.push({"front":"le tunnel","back":"tunnel"});
b.push({"front":"transformer","back":"to transform"});
b.push({"front":"le fauteuil","back":"armchair, seat"});
b.push({"front":"le foie","back":"liver"});
b.push({"front":"causer","back":"to cause"});
b.push({"front":"violent","back":"violent"});
b.push({"front":"commander","back":"to order, command"});
b.push({"front":"fouiller","back":"to search, frisk, go through, rummage through"});
b.push({"front":"la rage","back":"rage, fury, rabies"});
b.push({"front":"une hauteur","back":"height"});
b.push({"front":"le ministère","back":"ministry"});
b.push({"front":"la culture","back":"culture"});
b.push({"front":"le stress","back":"stress"});
b.push({"front":"le pari","back":"the bet"});
b.push({"front":"interne","back":"internal, interior, intern"});
b.push({"front":"le diplôme","back":"diploma, certificate"});
b.push({"front":"une activité","back":"activity"});
b.push({"front":"un auteur, une auteur","back":"author"});
b.push({"front":"paraître","back":"to appear"});
b.push({"front":"le serment","back":"oath, vow"});
b.push({"front":"le clan","back":"clan"});
b.push({"front":"un album","back":"album"});
b.push({"front":"le charme","back":"charm"});
b.push({"front":"apprécier","back":"to appreciate"});
b.push({"front":"la livraison","back":"the delivery"});
b.push({"front":"habiller","back":"to dress, get dressed"});
b.push({"front":"la promotion","back":"promotion, advertising"});
b.push({"front":"pervers","back":"pervert, perverse, perverted"});
b.push({"front":"rompre","back":"to break"});
b.push({"front":"la collection","back":"collection, series"});
b.push({"front":"le plastique","back":"plastic"});
b.push({"front":"naturellement","back":"naturally"});
b.push({"front":"une électricité","back":"electricity"});
b.push({"front":"la flotte","back":"fleet"});
b.push({"front":"une étude","back":"study"});
b.push({"front":"national","back":"national"});
b.push({"front":"le terroriste, la terroriste","back":"terrorist"});
b.push({"front":"autrefois","back":"in the past; once"});
b.push({"front":"la caution","back":"deposit, guarantee, bail"});
b.push({"front":"la cité","back":"city"});
b.push({"front":"le total","back":"total"});
b.push({"front":"le commerce","back":"trade, commerce"});
b.push({"front":"gratuit","back":"free, gratuitous, unwarranted"});
b.push({"front":"un écart","back":"space, gap"});
b.push({"front":"charger","back":"to load, charge"});
b.push({"front":"le cimetière","back":"cemetery, graveyard"});
b.push({"front":"une empreinte","back":"imprint, print, mark, impression"});
b.push({"front":"le septembre","back":"September"});
b.push({"front":"la phase","back":"phase"});
b.push({"front":"rêver","back":"to dream"});
b.push({"front":"le vague, la vague","back":"vague; wave"});
b.push({"front":"le dollar","back":"dollar"});
b.push({"front":"emporter","back":"to take, remove (an object)"});
b.push({"front":"ignorer","back":"to ignore"});
b.push({"front":"le micro","back":"mike, micro, microphone"});
b.push({"front":"le rang","back":"rank, row"});
b.push({"front":"la révolution","back":"revolution"});
b.push({"front":"léger","back":"something light"});
b.push({"front":"douze","back":"twelve"});
b.push({"front":"plaindre","back":"complain"});
b.push({"front":"un esclave, une esclave","back":"slave"});
b.push({"front":"le métro","back":"underground, metro"});
b.push({"front":"soutenir","back":"to sustain, support"});
b.push({"front":"la culpabilité","back":"guilt"});
b.push({"front":"la dette","back":"debt"});
b.push({"front":"le parent","back":"parent"});
b.push({"front":"interrompre","back":"to interrupt"});
b.push({"front":"le sein","back":"breast, bosom"});
b.push({"front":"le commissariat","back":"police station"});
b.push({"front":"produire","back":"to product"});
b.push({"front":"sain","back":"healthy, sane"});
b.push({"front":"le régime","back":"regime"});
b.push({"front":"efficace","back":"effective"});
b.push({"front":"la fierté","back":"pride"});
b.push({"front":"éteindre_","back":"to extinguish, put out, turn off"});
b.push({"front":"écraser_","back":"to crush, grind"});
b.push({"front":"un adjoint","back":"assistant, deputy"});
b.push({"front":"le laboratoire","back":"laboratory"});
b.push({"front":"la religion","back":"religion"});
b.push({"front":"couler","back":"to flow; to sink"});
b.push({"front":"le rond","back":"round"});
b.push({"front":"le comté","back":"county, earldom"});
b.push({"front":"pratiquement","back":"practically"});
b.push({"front":"la communication","back":"communication"});
b.push({"front":"une option","back":"option"});
b.push({"front":"un escalier","back":"stairs, staircase"});
b.push({"front":"un espagnol","back":"Spanish"});
b.push({"front":"la lecture","back":"the (act of) reading"});
b.push({"front":"le quatrième, la quatrième","back":"fourth"});
b.push({"front":"le chirurgien","back":"surgeon"});
b.push({"front":"tandis","back":"while"});
b.push({"front":"un amant","back":"lover"});
b.push({"front":"jusque","back":"to, up to, until"});
b.push({"front":"la personnalité","back":"personality"});
b.push({"front":"une évidence","back":"evidence"});
b.push({"front":"le remède","back":"cure, remedy"});
b.push({"front":"la formation","back":"training"});
b.push({"front":"le manuel","back":"manual"});
b.push({"front":"enterrer","back":"to bury, lay aside"});
b.push({"front":"le caractère","back":"character"});
b.push({"front":"particulièrement","back":"particularly"});
b.push({"front":"le fidèle","back":"faithful"});
b.push({"front":"la dose","back":"dose, amount"});
b.push({"front":"généreux","back":"generous"});
b.push({"front":"rouler","back":"to roll"});
b.push({"front":"le congrès","back":"congress, conference"});
b.push({"front":"la lampe","back":"lamp, light"});
b.push({"front":"actuellement","back":"at present, at the moment"});
b.push({"front":"grandir","back":"to grow, increase, expand"});
b.push({"front":"améliorer","back":"to improve"});
b.push({"front":"résister","back":"to resist"});
b.push({"front":"le réveil","back":"waking up, awakening, alarm clock"});
b.push({"front":"la boisson","back":"drink, beverage"});
b.push({"front":"le dessin","back":"drawing, pattern, design"});
b.push({"front":"crever","back":"to burst, puncture"});
b.push({"front":"nucléaire","back":"nuclear"});
b.push({"front":"goûter","back":"to taste, snack"});
b.push({"front":"le portrait","back":"portrait, photograph"});
b.push({"front":"exprimer","back":"to express"});
b.push({"front":"une avenue","back":"avenue"});
b.push({"front":"un accent","back":"accent"});
b.push({"front":"la découverte","back":"discovery"});
b.push({"front":"centrale","back":"power station, central office"});
b.push({"front":"une exécution","back":"execution, accomplishment"});
b.push({"front":"espérer","back":"to hope"});
b.push({"front":"détendre_","back":"to release, to relax"});
b.push({"front":"plaire","back":"to please"});
b.push({"front":"la brigade","back":"team, squad, brigade"});
b.push({"front":"la tradition","back":"tradition"});
b.push({"front":"officiel","back":"official"});
b.push({"front":"le défi","back":"challenge"});
b.push({"front":"le désastre","back":"disaster"});
b.push({"front":"disponible","back":"available"});
b.push({"front":"un italien","back":"Italian"});
b.push({"front":"le budget","back":"budget"});
b.push({"front":"ressentir","back":"to feel"});
b.push({"front":"la reconnaissance","back":"recognition, gratitude"});
b.push({"front":"le drapeau","back":"flag"});
b.push({"front":"un indien","back":"Indian"});
b.push({"front":"la phrase","back":"sentence, phrase"});
b.push({"front":"le métal","back":"metal"});
b.push({"front":"le processus","back":"process"});
b.push({"front":"correctement","back":"properly, correctly"});
b.push({"front":"la rumeur","back":"rumour"});
b.push({"front":"assister","back":"to attend; to assist, help"});
b.push({"front":"la jungle","back":"jungle"});
b.push({"front":"mortel","back":"mortal, deadly, lethal"});
b.push({"front":"la survie","back":"survival"});
b.push({"front":"une intelligence","back":"intelligence"});
b.push({"front":"le chasseur","back":"hunter, fighter, page, messenger"});
b.push({"front":"quoique","back":"although, though; whatever"});
b.push({"front":"le passeport","back":"passport"});
b.push({"front":"risquer","back":"to risk"});
b.push({"front":"la stratégie","back":"strategy"});
b.push({"front":"accueillir","back":"to welcome, greet, accommodate"});
b.push({"front":"serré","back":"tight, packed, crowded"});
b.push({"front":"la remarque","back":"remark"});
b.push({"front":"le commercial","back":"commercial"});
b.push({"front":"définitivement","back":"definitely, permanently, for good"});
b.push({"front":"le commandement","back":"command, order, commandment"});
b.push({"front":"une interview","back":"interview"});
b.push({"front":"complexe","back":"complex"});
b.push({"front":"le pétrole","back":"crude oil, petroleum"});
b.push({"front":"la pomme","back":"apple"});
b.push({"front":"une intervention","back":"intervention; talk"});
b.push({"front":"le lot","back":"the share, the lot"});
b.push({"front":"la charité","back":"charity"});
b.push({"front":"promener","back":"to take for a walk, go for a walk"});
b.push({"front":"la méthode","back":"method, procedure"});
b.push({"front":"le câble","back":"cable, wire"});
b.push({"front":"creuser","back":"to dig"});
b.push({"front":"tendre","back":"to tighten; to extend, stretch; tender"});
b.push({"front":"la batterie","back":"battery; drum set"});
b.push({"front":"un écrivain","back":"writer"});
b.push({"front":"reconnaissant","back":"grateful"});
b.push({"front":"sincèrement","back":"sincerely"});
b.push({"front":"timide","back":"timid, shy, bashful"});
b.push({"front":"une héroïne","back":"heroine"});
b.push({"front":"la tendance","back":"tendency, trend"});
b.push({"front":"le complice, la complice","back":"accomplice"});
b.push({"front":"la torture","back":"torture"});
b.push({"front":"un otage, une otage","back":"hostage"});
b.push({"front":"techniquement","back":"technically"});
b.push({"front":"la masse","back":"mass"});
b.push({"front":"opérer","back":"to operate, carry out"});
b.push({"front":"sincère","back":"sincere"});
b.push({"front":"le collège","back":"secondary school, college"});
b.push({"front":"un échantillon","back":"sample"});
b.push({"front":"le sacrifice","back":"sacrifice"});
b.push({"front":"le pasteur","back":"minister, clergyman, pastor"});
b.push({"front":"le dent, la dent","back":"tooth"});
b.push({"front":"le quart","back":"quarter"});
b.push({"front":"un équipement","back":"equipment"});
b.push({"front":"cruel","back":"cruel, ferocious, bitter"});
b.push({"front":"arracher","back":"to pull up, tear up_"});
b.push({"front":"le juillet","back":"July"});
b.push({"front":"la génération","back":"generation"});
b.push({"front":"un événement","back":"event_"});
b.push({"front":"solitaire","back":"solitary, lone, lonely"});
b.push({"front":"le bâton","back":"tick, club, baton"});
b.push({"front":"la marge","back":"margin"});
b.push({"front":"un héritage","back":"heritage"});
b.push({"front":"ressembler","back":"to look like, resemble"});
b.push({"front":"le volontaire, la volontaire","back":"volunteer; voluntary"});
b.push({"front":"énormément","back":"enormously"});
b.push({"front":"la priorité","back":"priority"});
b.push({"front":"le mélange","back":"mixing, mixture, blend"});
b.push({"front":"la rupture","back":"the break, rupture"});
b.push({"front":"le sel","back":"salt"});
b.push({"front":"déménager","back":"to move"});
b.push({"front":"tester","back":"to test"});
b.push({"front":"le conducteur","back":"driver, operator, conductor"});
b.push({"front":"la trahison","back":"betrayal, treachery, treason"});
b.push({"front":"le transfert","back":"the transfer"});
b.push({"front":"débrouiller","back":"to untangle, sort out, manage, get by"});
b.push({"front":"la moyenne","back":"average"});
b.push({"front":"moderne","back":"modern"});
b.push({"front":"effacer","back":"to erase, clean"});
b.push({"front":"le positif","back":"positive"});
b.push({"front":"la publicité","back":"advertising, advertisement, publicity"});
b.push({"front":"un environnement","back":"environment"});
b.push({"front":"médias","back":"media"});
b.push({"front":"le scandale","back":"scandal, uproar"});
b.push({"front":"le vendeur","back":"salesman, seller"});
b.push({"front":"invisible","back":"invisible"});
b.push({"front":"la tragédie","back":"tragedy"});
b.push({"front":"une issue","back":"the exit, outcome"});
b.push({"front":"voter","back":"to vote"});
b.push({"front":"probable","back":"probable, likely"});
b.push({"front":"la destruction","back":"destruction"});
b.push({"front":"négocier","back":"to negotiate"});
b.push({"front":"aimable","back":"pleasant, kind, nice"});
b.push({"front":"un avril","back":"April"});
b.push({"front":"la connerie","back":"crap, bullsh*t, stupidity"});
b.push({"front":"le saut","back":"jump, leap"});
b.push({"front":"quinze","back":"fifteen"});
b.push({"front":"le leader, la leader","back":"leader"});
b.push({"front":"le séjour","back":"the stay"});
b.push({"front":"le marin, la marin","back":"sea, marine, sailor"});
b.push({"front":"la sensation","back":"sensation"});
b.push({"front":"une exception","back":"exception"});
b.push({"front":"sien","back":"his, hers"});
b.push({"front":"la possession","back":"possession, ownership"});
b.push({"front":"le motif","back":"motive, purpose"});
b.push({"front":"le serveur","back":"waiter, server"});
b.push({"front":"la prière","back":"prayer"});
b.push({"front":"protégé","back":"protected, protégé"});
b.push({"front":"baisser","back":"to lower"});
b.push({"front":"abattre","back":"to pull down, kill, beat"});
b.push({"front":"une association","back":"association"});
b.push({"front":"le poing","back":"fist, punch"});
b.push({"front":"le producteur","back":"producer"});
b.push({"front":"une écriture","back":"the writing"});
b.push({"front":"craindre","back":"to fear, be afraid of"});
b.push({"front":"la vallée","back":"valley"});
b.push({"front":"le règlement","back":"rule, regulation"});
b.push({"front":"net","back":"clear; Internet"});
b.push({"front":"précisément","back":"precisely"});
b.push({"front":"la morale","back":"ethics; moral"});
b.push({"front":"immense","back":"immense"});
b.push({"front":"informer","back":"to inform"});
b.push({"front":"le chapitre","back":"chapter"});
b.push({"front":"le potentiel","back":"potential"});
b.push({"front":"une audition","back":"hearing, examination, audition"});
b.push({"front":"confirmer","back":"to confirm"});
b.push({"front":"la capacité","back":"capacity, ability"});
b.push({"front":"le fruit","back":"fruit"});
b.push({"front":"le chaos","back":"chaos"});
b.push({"front":"éclater","back":"to burst, explode"});
b.push({"front":"un acier","back":"steel"});
b.push({"front":"le cri","back":"the shout, cry"});
b.push({"front":"la population","back":"population"});
b.push({"front":"effectivement","back":"effectively"});
b.push({"front":"regretter","back":"to regret"});
b.push({"front":"proposer","back":"to propose"});
b.push({"front":"le panneau","back":"sign, notice, panel"});
b.push({"front":"légal","back":"legal, lawful"});
b.push({"front":"la construction","back":"construction, building"});
b.push({"front":"la boue","back":"mud"});
b.push({"front":"rarement","back":"rarely, seldom"});
b.push({"front":"la combinaison","back":"combination"});
b.push({"front":"le franc","back":"frank; franc (money)"});
b.push({"front":"la plante","back":"plant"});
b.push({"front":"une apparence","back":"appearance"});
b.push({"front":"le menu","back":"menu, slender, slim, minor"});
b.push({"front":"le luxe","back":"luxury"});
b.push({"front":"un essentiel","back":"essential"});
b.push({"front":"maintenir","back":"to maintain"});
b.push({"front":"stable","back":"stable"});
b.push({"front":"le satellite","back":"satellite"});
b.push({"front":"la branche","back":"branch"});
b.push({"front":"une autoroute","back":"motorway, highway, freeway"});
b.push({"front":"rembourser","back":"to reimburse, pay back, pay off, repay"});
b.push({"front":"le transport","back":"transportation"});
b.push({"front":"la statue","back":"statue"});
b.push({"front":"le principe","back":"principle"});
b.push({"front":"la couronne","back":"crown, wreath"});
b.push({"front":"subir","back":"to undergo, be subjected to, suffer"});
b.push({"front":"le sec","back":"dry"});
b.push({"front":"accuser","back":"to accuse"});
b.push({"front":"la goutte","back":"the drop (of one liquid)"});
b.push({"front":"la colline","back":"hill"});
b.push({"front":"la revanche","back":"revenge; return"});
b.push({"front":"le trente","back":"thirty"});
b.push({"front":"une aile","back":"wing, sail, blade"});
b.push({"front":"le bienvenu","back":"welcome"});
b.push({"front":"hélas","back":"alas"});
b.push({"front":"la résistance","back":"resistance"});
b.push({"front":"la prime","back":"free gift, premium, bonus"});
b.push({"front":"littéralement","back":"literally"});
b.push({"front":"fédéral","back":"federal"});
b.push({"front":"un engagement","back":"agreement, commitment"});
b.push({"front":"le médicament","back":"medicine, drug, medication"});
b.push({"front":"le symbole","back":"symbol"});
b.push({"front":"un avertissement","back":"warning"});
b.push({"front":"le réalisateur","back":"director"});
b.push({"front":"douter","back":"to doubt"});
b.push({"front":"douloureux","back":"painful, grievous, distressing"});
b.push({"front":"louer","back":"to rent, praise"});
b.push({"front":"un impact","back":"impact"});
b.push({"front":"le chagrin","back":"grief, sorrow,"});
b.push({"front":"révéler","back":"to reveal"});
b.push({"front":"le juin","back":"June"});
b.push({"front":"téléphoner","back":"to telephone, phone, call"});
b.push({"front":"une excellence","back":"excellence"});
b.push({"front":"remarquer","back":"to remark; to notice, point out"});
b.push({"front":"la pension","back":"pension; room and board, boarding school"});
b.push({"front":"roue_","back":"wheel"});
b.push({"front":"un arrangement","back":"arrangement, layout, order, agreement"});
b.push({"front":"la routine","back":"routine"});
b.push({"front":"la poignée","back":"handful, fistful, handle"});
b.push({"front":"le local","back":"local"});
b.push({"front":"le légitime, la légitime","back":"legitimate"});
b.push({"front":"un hélicoptère","back":"helicopter"});
b.push({"front":"filmer","back":"to film, shoot"});
b.push({"front":"un octobre","back":"October"});
b.push({"front":"une obscurité","back":"darkness"});
b.push({"front":"le domicile","back":"home, place of residence"});
b.push({"front":"une administration","back":"administration"});
b.push({"front":"la médaille","back":"medal"});
b.push({"front":"le casque","back":"helmet"});
b.push({"front":"la boucle","back":"loop, buckle, curl"});
b.push({"front":"tarder","back":"to delay"});
b.push({"front":"un asile","back":"shelter, asylum, hospital"});
b.push({"front":"le texte","back":"text"});
b.push({"front":"le deuil","back":"mourning, grief"});
b.push({"front":"un auto, une auto","back":"car"});
b.push({"front":"la fonction","back":"function"});
b.push({"front":"la république","back":"republic"});
b.push({"front":"allumer","back":"to switch on, light up, turn on"});
b.push({"front":"enquêter","back":"to investigate, hold inquiry, conduct a survey"});
b.push({"front":"piquer","back":"to sting, bite, prick, be hot; to steal"});
b.push({"front":"le manche, la manche","back":"handle, sleeve"});
b.push({"front":"la circulation","back":"circulation, traffic"});
b.push({"front":"une enveloppe","back":"envelope"});
b.push({"front":"le blé","back":"wheat"});
b.push({"front":"le record","back":"record"});
b.push({"front":"le puits","back":"well, shaft, pit"});
b.push({"front":"renoncer","back":"renounce"});
b.push({"front":"décrire","back":"to describe"});
b.push({"front":"accomplir","back":"to accomplish"});
b.push({"front":"réduire","back":"to reduce"});
b.push({"front":"enseigner","back":"to teach"});
b.push({"front":"un entraîneur","back":"coach, trainer"});
b.push({"front":"contrairement","back":"contrary"});
b.push({"front":"la facture","back":"invoice, bill"});
b.push({"front":"un époux","back":"husband, spouse"});
b.push({"front":"la revue","back":"review, magazine, journal"});
b.push({"front":"le pouce","back":"thumb, inch"});
b.push({"front":"avaler","back":"to swallow"});
b.push({"front":"remarquable","back":"remarkable, outstanding"});
b.push({"front":"le délit","back":"crime, offence"});
b.push({"front":"le réduit","back":"reduced, scaled-down, cut-down, tiny room, hideout"});
b.push({"front":"ruiner","back":"to ruin, bankrupt oneself"});
b.push({"front":"la détention","back":"detention, possession"});
b.push({"front":"coûter","back":"to cost"});
b.push({"front":"mêler","back":"to mingle, mix"});
b.push({"front":"la douzaine","back":"dozen"});
b.push({"front":"suprême","back":"supreme"});
b.push({"front":"le gris","back":"grey"});
b.push({"front":"le restant","back":"remaining, the rest, the remainder"});
b.push({"front":"la crainte","back":"fear"});
b.push({"front":"le panier","back":"basket"});
b.push({"front":"informé","back":"informed"});
b.push({"front":"sortant","back":"outgoing"});
b.push({"front":"terriblement","back":"terribly, awfully"});
b.push({"front":"le conflit","back":"conflict"});
b.push({"front":"le sourd","back":"deaf"});
b.push({"front":"observer","back":"to observe, watch"});
b.push({"front":"le protocole","back":"etiquette, protocol"});
b.push({"front":"placer","back":"to place"});
b.push({"front":"le silencieux","back":"silent, noiseless, silencer"});
b.push({"front":"le malentendu","back":"misunderstanding"});
b.push({"front":"punir","back":"to punish"});
b.push({"front":"la faiblesse","back":"weakness"});
b.push({"front":"rapporter","back":"to bring back, report"});
b.push({"front":"la quantité","back":"quantity"});
b.push({"front":"un historique","back":"historical"});
b.push({"front":"serrer","back":"to tighten, squeeze"});
b.push({"front":"avertir","back":"to warn"});
b.push({"front":"enfermer","back":"to shut"});
b.push({"front":"le candidat","back":"candidate"});
b.push({"front":"le compromis","back":"compromise, agreement"});
b.push({"front":"une atmosphère","back":"atmosphere"});
b.push({"front":"établir","back":"to establish"});
b.push({"front":"le tube","back":"tube"});
b.push({"front":"le cadre","back":"frame, executive"});
b.push({"front":"le trône","back":"throne"});
b.push({"front":"le festival","back":"festival"});
b.push({"front":"intéresser","back":"to interest, involve"});
b.push({"front":"un ingénieur, une ingénieur","back":"engineer"});
b.push({"front":"différemment","back":"differently"});
b.push({"front":"balancer","back":"to swing, sway"});
b.push({"front":"le minimum","back":"minimum"});
b.push({"front":"un ambassadeur","back":"ambassador"});
b.push({"front":"tragique","back":"tragic"});
b.push({"front":"vaincre","back":"to defeat, overcome, conquer"});
b.push({"front":"conscient","back":"conscious, aware"});
b.push({"front":"le tissu","back":"fabric, material, cloth, tissue, woven"});
b.push({"front":"une intimité","back":"privacy, intimacy"});
b.push({"front":"obéir","back":"to obey, comply with, respond to"});
b.push({"front":"le lancement","back":"the launch"});
b.push({"front":"la demeure","back":"residence, home"});
b.push({"front":"mystérieux","back":"mysterious, secretive"});
b.push({"front":"la fillette","back":"little girl, girl"});
b.push({"front":"le genou","back":"knee"});
b.push({"front":"la sagesse","back":"wisdom, moderation"});
b.push({"front":"une industrie","back":"industry"});
b.push({"front":"le guerrier","back":"warrior; warlike"});
b.push({"front":"fragile","back":"fragile"});
b.push({"front":"la libération","back":"liberation"});
b.push({"front":"promettre","back":"to promise"});
b.push({"front":"un élément","back":"element"});
b.push({"front":"ramasser","back":"to pick up, collect, gather"});
b.push({"front":"un atelier","back":"workshop, studio"});
b.push({"front":"la destinée","back":"fate, destiny"});
b.push({"front":"accéder","back":"to access, reach, attain"});
b.push({"front":"la grossesse","back":"pregnancy"});
b.push({"front":"un usage","back":"use, usage"});
b.push({"front":"royal","back":"royal"});
b.push({"front":"la résidence","back":"residence, block of flats"});
b.push({"front":"quelconque","back":"any, some"});
b.push({"front":"suicider","back":"to commit suicide"});
b.push({"front":"communiquer","back":"to communicate"});
b.push({"front":"le trouble","back":"trouble"});
b.push({"front":"la dépression","back":"depression"});
b.push({"front":"le novembre","back":"November"});
b.push({"front":"la chaussure","back":"shoe, sneaker"});
b.push({"front":"un équilibre","back":"balance, equilibrium"});
b.push({"front":"un élu","back":"elected, elected member"});
b.push({"front":"endormir","back":"to put to sleep, fall asleep"});
b.push({"front":"le gras","back":"fatty, fat, greasy"});
b.push({"front":"la grève","back":"the strike (of workers)"});
b.push({"front":"confortable","back":"comfortable"});
b.push({"front":"le chant","back":"song"});
b.push({"front":"judiciaire","back":"judiciary"});
b.push({"front":"accrocher","back":"to hang up, hang on, put up"});
b.push({"front":"le jouet","back":"toy"});
b.push({"front":"augmenter","back":"to increase, raise"});
b.push({"front":"un automne","back":"fall, autumn"});
b.push({"front":"peindre","back":"to paint, depict, portray"});
b.push({"front":"une exposition","back":"exhibition, show"});
b.push({"front":"cesser","back":"to cease, stop"});
b.push({"front":"la vedette","back":"star, patrol boat"});
b.push({"front":"la curiosité","back":"curiosity"});
b.push({"front":"le débat","back":"debate"});
b.push({"front":"le citoyen","back":"citizen"});
b.push({"front":"le pape","back":"pope"});
b.push({"front":"une assiette","back":"plate, dish, bowl"});
b.push({"front":"le tennis","back":"tennis"});
b.push({"front":"la solitude","back":"solitude, loneliness"});
b.push({"front":"la destination","back":"destination"});
b.push({"front":"une ambiance","back":"the atmosphere (mood)"});
b.push({"front":"archives","back":"archives, records"});
b.push({"front":"la capitale","back":"capital"});
b.push({"front":"le spécialiste, la spécialiste","back":"specialist"});
b.push({"front":"le massacre","back":"massacre, slaughter"});
b.push({"front":"veiller","back":"to look after, stay up"});
b.push({"front":"parier","back":"to bet"});
b.push({"front":"racheter","back":"to repurchase, buy back, redeem"});
b.push({"front":"la description","back":"description"});
b.push({"front":"un irlandais","back":"Irish"});
b.push({"front":"la punition","back":"punishment"});
b.push({"front":"le poème","back":"poem"});
b.push({"front":"prêter","back":"to lend"});
b.push({"front":"dépenser","back":"to spend"});
b.push({"front":"échanger","back":"to exchange"});
b.push({"front":"une économie","back":"economy"});
b.push({"front":"la colonne","back":"column"});
b.push({"front":"la connexion","back":"connection"});
b.push({"front":"fonctionner","back":"to function, work"});
b.push({"front":"la feuille","back":"leaf, sheet, slip"});
b.push({"front":"le suisse","back":"Swiss"});
b.push({"front":"la répétition","back":"repetition, rehearsal"});
b.push({"front":"la météo","back":"weather forecast"});
b.push({"front":"anonyme","back":"anonymous"});
b.push({"front":"un immobilier","back":"property, real estate, property business, real estate business"});
b.push({"front":"la serre","back":"greenhouse"});
b.push({"front":"le plafond","back":"ceiling, roof, maximum"});
b.push({"front":"fournir","back":"to provide, supply"});
b.push({"front":"confier","back":"to entrust"});
b.push({"front":"le diamant","back":"diamond"});
b.push({"front":"le défaut","back":"fault, flaw, shortcoming"});
b.push({"front":"une inquiétude","back":"worry, anxiety"});
b.push({"front":"un août","back":"August"});
b.push({"front":"un acide","back":"acid"});
b.push({"front":"la dignité","back":"dignity"});
b.push({"front":"une ambassade","back":"embassy"});
b.push({"front":"guère","back":"hardly, scarcely"});
b.push({"front":"la tache","back":"stain, spot, mark"});
b.push({"front":"familier","back":"familiar, informal"});
b.push({"front":"saisir","back":"to seize, to grab"});
b.push({"front":"volontiers","back":"with pleasure, willingly, gladly"});
b.push({"front":"signaler","back":"to indicate, signal"});
b.push({"front":"le fixe","back":"fixed"});
b.push({"front":"la foire","back":"the fair"});
b.push({"front":"enregistrer","back":"to record, check in"});
b.push({"front":"le civil","back":"civil; civilian"});
b.push({"front":"une affection","back":"affection, ailment"});
b.push({"front":"la catastrophe","back":"catastrophe, disaster"});
b.push({"front":"le duc","back":"duke"});
b.push({"front":"la fermeture","back":"closing"});
b.push({"front":"buter","back":"to stumble, trip, run into, prop up, score"});
b.push({"front":"accorder","back":"to grant"});
b.push({"front":"le canal","back":"canal, channel"});
b.push({"front":"évacuer","back":"to evacuate, clear"});
b.push({"front":"un absent","back":"absent"});
b.push({"front":"la merveille","back":"marvel, wonder"});
b.push({"front":"la plaie","back":"wound"});
b.push({"front":"la clef","back":"key"});
b.push({"front":"le cinquième, la cinquième","back":"fifth"});
b.push({"front":"le désordre","back":"disorder, confusion"});
b.push({"front":"intime","back":"intimate, close, secret, private"});
b.push({"front":"un adversaire, une adversaire","back":"opponent, adversary"});
b.push({"front":"la réussite","back":"the success"});
b.push({"front":"effrayer","back":"to frighten, scare"});
b.push({"front":"quasiment","back":"almost, early"});
b.push({"front":"le fichier","back":"file"});
b.push({"front":"intervenir","back":"to intervene"});
b.push({"front":"le profit","back":"profit, benefit"});
b.push({"front":"le sou","back":"penny"});
b.push({"front":"une informatique","back":"computer science, computing"});
b.push({"front":"constamment","back":"constantly, continuously, consistent"});
b.push({"front":"désespéré","back":"desperate, hopeless"});
b.push({"front":"la recette","back":"recipe"});
b.push({"front":"la douceur","back":"softness, smoothness, mildness, gentleness,sweetness"});
b.push({"front":"la formule","back":"formula, expression"});
b.push({"front":"la montée","back":"climb, ascent, rise, raising"});
b.push({"front":"le bond","back":"leap, rebound"});
b.push({"front":"le verdict","back":"verdict"});
b.push({"front":"célébrer","back":"to celebrate"});
b.push({"front":"prétendre","back":"to pretend"});
b.push({"front":"la fréquence","back":"frequency"});
b.push({"front":"disputer","back":"to dispute"});
b.push({"front":"un exposé","back":"account, statement, talk"});
b.push({"front":"cuire","back":"to cook, bake, roast"});
b.push({"front":"une illusion","back":"illusion"});
b.push({"front":"le jet","back":"jet, throw, spray, nozzle"});
b.push({"front":"une antenne","back":"antenna"});
b.push({"front":"la compassion","back":"compassion"});
b.push({"front":"la quête","back":"quest, pursuit, collection"});
b.push({"front":"le photographe, la photographe","back":"photographer"});
b.push({"front":"déterminer","back":"to determine, find out, specify"});
b.push({"front":"un assaut","back":"assault, attack, bout"});
b.push({"front":"provoquer","back":"to provoke"});
b.push({"front":"coincer","back":"to jam, hinder, get stuck"});
b.push({"front":"le document","back":"document"});
b.push({"front":"la poésie","back":"poetry"});
b.push({"front":"délicat","back":"delicate, fine, gentle"});
b.push({"front":"piéger","back":"to trap, booby-trap"});
b.push({"front":"le syndicat","back":"union (of workers)"});
b.push({"front":"le tabac","back":"tobacco"});
b.push({"front":"un orchestre","back":"orchestra"});
b.push({"front":"discret","back":"discreet, tactful, quiet"});
b.push({"front":"la ère","back":"era"});
b.push({"front":"relever","back":"to raise"});
b.push({"front":"le décembre","back":"December"});
b.push({"front":"appuyer","back":"to lean, support"});
b.push({"front":"une évasion","back":"evasion, escape"});
b.push({"front":"réagir","back":"to react"});
b.push({"front":"la retenue","back":"deduction; restraint, self-control"});
b.push({"front":"glisser","back":"to slide, slip"});
b.push({"front":"la tristesse","back":"sadness, gloominess, dreariness"});
b.push({"front":"la fatigue","back":"tiredness, fatigue"});
b.push({"front":"la création","back":"creation"});
b.push({"front":"la planche","back":"plank, board"});
b.push({"front":"le voile, la voile","back":"veil, sail"});
b.push({"front":"la galerie","back":"gallery"});
b.push({"front":"le bétail","back":"livestock, cattle"});
b.push({"front":"le drame","back":"drama"});
b.push({"front":"une émotion","back":"emotion, feeling"});
b.push({"front":"la garantie","back":"guarantee"});
b.push({"front":"la terreur","back":"terror, dread"});
b.push({"front":"intense","back":"intense, severe, dense"});
b.push({"front":"le contenu","back":"contents"});
b.push({"front":"le sorcier","back":"sorcerer, witch"});
b.push({"front":"le fleuve","back":"river"});
b.push({"front":"la longueur","back":"length"});
b.push({"front":"vider","back":"to empty, vacate"});
b.push({"front":"certes","back":"indeed, certainly, of course"});
b.push({"front":"le thème","back":"theme, topic"});
b.push({"front":"le refuge","back":"refuge"});
b.push({"front":"le compliment","back":"compliment"});
b.push({"front":"la navette","back":"shuttle"});
b.push({"front":"la poursuite","back":"chase, pursuit"});
b.push({"front":"un ennui","back":"the boredom, trouble, worry"});
b.push({"front":"la sauvetage","back":"rescue, salvaging"});
b.push({"front":"lutter","back":"to struggle, fight"});
b.push({"front":"le reporter, la reporter","back":"to report; to postpone"});
b.push({"front":"britannique","back":"British"});
b.push({"front":"le janvier","back":"January"});
b.push({"front":"le représentant","back":"representative"});
b.push({"front":"ci","back":"this one, here"});
b.push({"front":"la référence","back":"reference"});
b.push({"front":"détester","back":"to hate, detest"});
b.push({"front":"le nettoyage","back":"cleaning, cleansing"});
b.push({"front":"généralement","back":"generally"});
b.push({"front":"la misère","back":"poverty, misery"});
b.push({"front":"une innocence","back":"innocence"});
b.push({"front":"la conclusion","back":"conclusion"});
b.push({"front":"un inverse","back":"opposite, reverse"});
b.push({"front":"coller","back":"to stick, paste"});
b.push({"front":"le plomb","back":"lead"});
b.push({"front":"noyer","back":"walnut; to drown, flood, blur, water down"});
b.push({"front":"attacher","back":"to attach"});
b.push({"front":"confus","back":"confused, embarrassed"});
b.push({"front":"insensé","back":"insane; nonsense"});
b.push({"front":"inhabituel","back":"unusual"});
b.push({"front":"le catholique, la catholique","back":"Catholic"});
b.push({"front":"pêcher","back":"to fish, go fishing; peach tree"});
b.push({"front":"la marchandise","back":"merchandise, commodity"});
b.push({"front":"moquer","back":"to mock, make fun of"});
b.push({"front":"le circuit","back":"circuit"});
b.push({"front":"la centaine","back":"hundred"});
b.push({"front":"spécialement","back":"especially, particularly"});
b.push({"front":"éternel","back":"eternal, everlasting"});
b.push({"front":"un hôte","back":"host, guest"});
b.push({"front":"le règne","back":"reign"});
b.push({"front":"un assassinat","back":"murder, assassination"});
b.push({"front":"fameux","back":"famous"});
b.push({"front":"la quarantaine","back":"forty"});
b.push({"front":"le relevé","back":"statement, list; relieved; put in relief; rolled up"});
b.push({"front":"la structure","back":"structure"});
b.push({"front":"le comptable, la comptable","back":"accountant, accountable"});
b.push({"front":"trahir","back":"to betray, give away"});
b.push({"front":"temporaire","back":"temporary"});
b.push({"front":"le relais","back":"shift, relay"});
b.push({"front":"le vif","back":"lively"});
b.push({"front":"international","back":"international"});
b.push({"front":"le développement","back":"development"});
b.push({"front":"le carton","back":"cardboard, card, score"});
b.push({"front":"impressionner","back":"to impress, upset"});
b.push({"front":"boucher","back":"butcher; to fill in, get clogged up"});
b.push({"front":"dénoncer","back":"to denounce"});
b.push({"front":"une identification","back":"identification"});
b.push({"front":"dégager","back":"to free, to clear_"});
b.push({"front":"la génétique","back":"genetic"});
b.push({"front":"lent","back":"slow"});
b.push({"front":"le cocktail","back":"cocktail, cocktail party"});
b.push({"front":"violer","back":"to rape, infringe"});
b.push({"front":"planter","back":"to plant, pitch"});
b.push({"front":"vain","back":"vain"});
b.push({"front":"la descente","back":"descent, raid, downward slope"});
b.push({"front":"le nuage","back":"cloud"});
b.push({"front":"la vitre","back":"pane, window_"});
b.push({"front":"la majorité","back":"majority"});
b.push({"front":"pénible","back":"hard, difficult, painful, tiresome"});
b.push({"front":"une élection","back":"election"});
b.push({"front":"le social","back":"social"});
b.push({"front":"la confession","back":"confession"});
b.push({"front":"le degré","back":"degree"});
b.push({"front":"une inspiration","back":"inspiration"});
b.push({"front":"dépêcher","back":"to dispatch, send, hurry"});
b.push({"front":"sacrifier","back":"to sacrifice, give away"});
b.push({"front":"le concept","back":"concept"});
b.push({"front":"le banc","back":"bench, workbench, pew"});
b.push({"front":"un engin","back":"machine, tool, vehicle, device"});
b.push({"front":"la spécialité","back":"specialty"});
b.push({"front":"biologique","back":"biological, nature"});
b.push({"front":"surprendre","back":"to surprise"});
b.push({"front":"hurler","back":"to scream, yell"});
b.push({"front":"un orage","back":"storm, thunderstorm"});
b.push({"front":"rassembler","back":"to gather together"});
b.push({"front":"mordre","back":"to bite, overlap into"});
b.push({"front":"le chantier","back":"construction site, roadworks"});
b.push({"front":"pendre","back":"to hang down"});
b.push({"front":"extrême","back":"extreme"});
b.push({"front":"le dépôt","back":"deposit, depot"});
b.push({"front":"un amateur, une amateur","back":"amateur"});
b.push({"front":"le commentaire","back":"comment, remark"});
b.push({"front":"la correction","back":"correction"});
b.push({"front":"la présentation","back":"presentation"});
b.push({"front":"sonner","back":"to ring"});
b.push({"front":"la flèche","back":"arrow"});
b.push({"front":"le tournoi","back":"tournament"});
b.push({"front":"une ordonnance","back":"prescription, organisation, edict, ruling"});
b.push({"front":"une élite","back":"elite"});
b.push({"front":"le trajet","back":"journey, route; traject"});
b.push({"front":"inventer","back":"to invent"});
b.push({"front":"la pompe","back":"pump"});
b.push({"front":"démarrer","back":"to start up"});
b.push({"front":"physiquement","back":"physically"});
b.push({"front":"la requête","back":"request, petition"});
b.push({"front":"habituer","back":"to accustom, get used to"});
b.push({"front":"le statut","back":"status"});
b.push({"front":"une augmentation","back":"the increase, the rise"});
b.push({"front":"développer","back":"to develop"});
b.push({"front":"le col","back":"collar, mountain pass"});
b.push({"front":"le carnet","back":"notebook, notepad"});
b.push({"front":"la gravité","back":"seriousness, solemnity, graveness, gravity"});
b.push({"front":"craquer","back":"to creak, squeak, crackle, give in, strike"});
b.push({"front":"la licence","back":"licence, permit"});
b.push({"front":"réunir","back":"to gather, reunite, raise"});
b.push({"front":"la troupe","back":"troup, troop"});
b.push({"front":"saluer","back":"to greet, salute"});
b.push({"front":"le conte","back":"tale"});
b.push({"front":"le chiffre","back":"figure, number"});
b.push({"front":"la tactique","back":"tactics, tactical"});
b.push({"front":"un hommage","back":"homage, tribute"});
b.push({"front":"nier","back":"to deny"});
b.push({"front":"commettre","back":"to commit"});
b.push({"front":"la flamme","back":"flame, fire, fervor, brilliance"});
b.push({"front":"le croisé","back":"twill; alternate; crusader; crossed"});
b.push({"front":"un impatient","back":"impatient"});
b.push({"front":"le quai","back":"platform, quay, embankment"});
b.push({"front":"le complot","back":"plot, conspiracy"});
b.push({"front":"consulter","back":"to consult"});
b.push({"front":"ultime","back":"ultimate; final"});
b.push({"front":"onze","back":"eleven"});
b.push({"front":"la poussée","back":"push, rise, upsurge"});
b.push({"front":"accompli","back":"accomplished"});
b.push({"front":"aussitôt","back":"as soon as"});
b.push({"front":"le poète","back":"poet"});
b.push({"front":"un inconscient","back":"unconscious, thoughtless"});
b.push({"front":"reculer","back":"to move back, back up"});
b.push({"front":"ralentir","back":"to slow down"});
b.push({"front":"le facteur","back":"postman, mailman; factor"});
b.push({"front":"le registre","back":"log, register, registry"});
b.push({"front":"pâle","back":"pale"});
b.push({"front":"la toile","back":"cloth, canvass, web"});
b.push({"front":"le filet","back":"dribble, trickle, wisp, streak, thread, fillet, net"});
b.push({"front":"le fardeau","back":"burden"});
b.push({"front":"honorable","back":"honorable"});
b.push({"front":"conclure","back":"to conclude"});
b.push({"front":"le compagnon","back":"companion, craftsman, journeyman"});
b.push({"front":"fixer","back":"to fix, arrange, set"});
b.push({"front":"le député","back":"deputy, parliamentary delegate"});
b.push({"front":"le montant","back":"upright, upwards, sum, total"});
b.push({"front":"le standard","back":"standard, switchboard"});
b.push({"front":"solaire","back":"solar"});
b.push({"front":"une évolution","back":"evolution"});
b.push({"front":"la maîtrise","back":"mastery, command, control, master’s degree"});
b.push({"front":"un institut","back":"institute"});
b.push({"front":"visiblement","back":"obviously, clearly, visibly"});
b.push({"front":"la mairie","back":"town hall, city hall"});
b.push({"front":"premièrement","back":"firstly"});
b.push({"front":"la civilisation","back":"civilization"});
b.push({"front":"la grille","back":"railings, gate, grid, scale"});
b.push({"front":"le chanteur","back":"singer"});
b.push({"front":"le gré","back":"liking"});
b.push({"front":"un investissement","back":"investment"});
b.push({"front":"un arrivant","back":"person who arrived"});
b.push({"front":"la discipline","back":"discipline"});
b.push({"front":"surprenant","back":"surprising"});
b.push({"front":"attentivement","back":"attentively, carefully, closely"});
b.push({"front":"âgé","back":"old"});
b.push({"front":"fabriquer","back":"to manufacture, invent, make"});
b.push({"front":"la levée","back":"raising, levying, levee"});
b.push({"front":"la barrière","back":"fence, barrier, gate"});
b.push({"front":"considérer","back":"to consider"});
b.push({"front":"la disposition","back":"arrangement, disposition"});
b.push({"front":"une affiche","back":"poster, public notice, bill"});
b.push({"front":"la correspondance","back":"correspondance, connection"});
b.push({"front":"le trottoir","back":"pavement"});
b.push({"front":"le championnat","back":"championship"});
b.push({"front":"soucier","back":"to care about, show concern for"});
b.push({"front":"le case, la case","back":"box, hut, field"});
b.push({"front":"plonger","back":"to dive"});
b.push({"front":"automatique","back":"automatic"});
b.push({"front":"le perdant","back":"losing, loser"});
b.push({"front":"visuel","back":"visual"});
b.push({"front":"décevoir","back":"to disappoint"});
b.push({"front":"le renfort","back":"help, back-up, support; reinforce"});
b.push({"front":"le cinquante","back":"fifty"});
b.push({"front":"approprié","back":"appropriate"});
b.push({"front":"artistique","back":"artistic"});
b.push({"front":"blâmer","back":"to blame, reprimand"});
b.push({"front":"le brouillard","back":"fog, mist, haze"});
b.push({"front":"le œuf","back":"egg"});
b.push({"front":"analyser","back":"to analyse"});
b.push({"front":"marquer","back":"to mark"});
b.push({"front":"le foudre, la foudre","back":"lightning"});
b.push({"front":"satisfaire","back":"to satisfy"});
b.push({"front":"habiter","back":"to live (in a place)"});
b.push({"front":"la patrie","back":"homeland, home country"});
b.push({"front":"vulnérable","back":"vulnerable"});
b.push({"front":"le domestique, la domestique","back":"servant, domestic"});
b.push({"front":"le ressort","back":"spring; resort; spirit"});
b.push({"front":"un individu","back":"individual"});
b.push({"front":"allonger","back":"to lengthen, extend, stretch out"});
b.push({"front":"la difficulté","back":"difficulty"});
b.push({"front":"impliquer","back":"to imply, implicate; involve"});
b.push({"front":"le marchand","back":"merchant"});
b.push({"front":"le rideau","back":"curtain"});
b.push({"front":"légèrement","back":"lightly, slightly"});
b.push({"front":"la défaite","back":"defeat"});
b.push({"front":"dramatique","back":"dramatic, tragic, drama"});
b.push({"front":"la détresse","back":"distress"});
b.push({"front":"typique","back":"typical"});
b.push({"front":"adopter","back":"to adopt"});
b.push({"front":"ennuyer","back":"to bore, worry, bother"});
b.push({"front":"la toilette","back":"washing, toilet, lavatory, bathroom, restroom"});
b.push({"front":"une insulte","back":"insult"});
b.push({"front":"la corruption","back":"corruption"});
b.push({"front":"fiable","back":"reliable, trustworthy"});
b.push({"front":"voire","back":"if ever; even; indeed"});
b.push({"front":"une allure","back":"speed, pace, walk, look, appearance"});
b.push({"front":"la démocratie","back":"democracy"});
b.push({"front":"rechercher","back":"to search for"});
b.push({"front":"un instrument","back":"instrument"});
b.push({"front":"pacifique","back":"peaceful, peace-loving"});
b.push({"front":"repérer","back":"to spot, pick out; locate, find"});
b.push({"front":"raser","back":"to shave, raze"});
b.push({"front":"un arabe","back":"Arabic, Arab"});
b.push({"front":"transmettre","back":"to forward, transmit"});
b.push({"front":"le désespoir","back":"despair"});
b.push({"front":"la fondation","back":"foundation"});
b.push({"front":"souhaiter","back":"to wish"});
b.push({"front":"le certificat","back":"certificate"});
b.push({"front":"la fraude","back":"fraud"});
b.push({"front":"rapprocher","back":"to bring closer, get closer"});
b.push({"front":"le carburant","back":"fuel"});
b.push({"front":"la fusion","back":"fusion, melting, merging"});
b.push({"front":"secondaire","back":"secondary"});
b.push({"front":"le février","back":"February"});
b.push({"front":"une amende","back":"fine (payment)"});
b.push({"front":"le syndrome","back":"syndrome"});
b.push({"front":"le grain","back":"grain, bean, bead; spot, mole"});
b.push({"front":"loyal","back":"loyal, faithful"});
b.push({"front":"guider","back":"to guide"});
b.push({"front":"vulgaire","back":"vulgar, common, popular"});
b.push({"front":"la séparation","back":"separation"});
b.push({"front":"la farce","back":"joke, prank, hoax, farce"});
b.push({"front":"gratuitement","back":"free, gratuitously"});
b.push({"front":"former","back":"to form"});
b.push({"front":"un héritier","back":"heir"});
b.push({"front":"la transmission","back":"transmission"});
b.push({"front":"torturer","back":"to torture"});
b.push({"front":"le rocher","back":"rock, boulder"});
b.push({"front":"un aîné","back":"oldest"});
b.push({"front":"téléphonique","back":"telephone"});
b.push({"front":"la profondeur","back":"depth"});
b.push({"front":"le triple","back":"triple"});
b.push({"front":"assassiner","back":"to murder, assassinate"});
b.push({"front":"une édition","back":"publishing, editing, edition"});
b.push({"front":"scolaire","back":"school, educational, academic"});
b.push({"front":"infiniment","back":"infinitely"});
b.push({"front":"la faille","back":"fault"});
b.push({"front":"le délai","back":"delay"});
b.push({"front":"le précédent","back":"precedent; previous"});
b.push({"front":"la profession","back":"profession"});
b.push({"front":"honorer","back":"to honour, do credit to"});
b.push({"front":"le raciste, la raciste","back":"racist"});
b.push({"front":"la réplique","back":"reply, retort; replica"});
b.push({"front":"prévoir","back":"to foresee, anticipate"});
b.push({"front":"la dimension","back":"dimension"});
b.push({"front":"le vice","back":"fault, defect, vice"});
b.push({"front":"sembler","back":"to seem"});
b.push({"front":"une angoisse","back":"distress, anguish, dread, fear"});
b.push({"front":"une ambition","back":"ambition"});
b.push({"front":"une observation","back":"observation"});
b.push({"front":"le vainqueur, la vainqueur","back":"winner"});
b.push({"front":"un aspect","back":"aspect"});
b.push({"front":"surmonter","back":"to overcome, top, surmount"});
b.push({"front":"repousser","back":"to push away, postpone"});
b.push({"front":"coopérer","back":"to cooperate"});
b.push({"front":"grossier","back":"unrefined, crude, coarse, rude, rough"});
b.push({"front":"le mineur","back":"minor; miner"});
b.push({"front":"comparer","back":"to compare"});
b.push({"front":"la durée","back":"length, duration"});
b.push({"front":"le parcours","back":"journey, course, route"});
b.push({"front":"le regret","back":"the regret, regretfully"});
b.push({"front":"électronique","back":"electronic"});
b.push({"front":"la faillite","back":"bankruptcy, collapse, failure"});
b.push({"front":"confidentiel","back":"confidential"});
b.push({"front":"le missile","back":"missile"});
b.push({"front":"modeste","back":"modest"});
b.push({"front":"représenter","back":"to represent"});
b.push({"front":"le chômage","back":"unemployment"});
b.push({"front":"renverser","back":"to knock down, turn over, overturn"});
b.push({"front":"alimentaire","back":"food"});
b.push({"front":"exister","back":"to exist"});
b.push({"front":"le favori","back":"favorite"});
b.push({"front":"dessiner","back":"to draw, design"});
b.push({"front":"décoller","back":"to take off; to loosen, unstick"});
b.push({"front":"transporter","back":"to transport, carry"});
b.push({"front":"exécuter","back":"to execute, carry out"});
b.push({"front":"manipuler","back":"to handle, manipulate"});
b.push({"front":"une impasse","back":"dead end, cul-de-sac"});
b.push({"front":"le détenu","back":"prisoner"});
b.push({"front":"le financier","back":"financial, financier"});
b.push({"front":"une égalité","back":"equality"});
b.push({"front":"capturer","back":"to capture, catch"});
b.push({"front":"le béton","back":"concrete"});
b.push({"front":"le distributeur","back":"distributor, machine"});
b.push({"front":"la location","back":"renting"});
b.push({"front":"le score","back":"score"});
b.push({"front":"la ruine","back":"ruin, ruins"});
b.push({"front":"la conviction","back":"conviction, belief"});
b.push({"front":"le pacte","back":"pact, treaty"});
b.push({"front":"le vœu","back":"vow, wish, will"});
b.push({"front":"une éthique","back":"ethical, ethics"});
b.push({"front":"le troupeau","back":"herd, flock"});
b.push({"front":"une obsession","back":"obsession"});
b.push({"front":"un emplacement","back":"site, location"});
b.push({"front":"grimper","back":"to climb, go up"});
b.push({"front":"la proie","back":"prey"});
b.push({"front":"le tiers","back":"third"});
b.push({"front":"le char, la char","back":"tank"});
b.push({"front":"le grec","back":"Greek"});
b.push({"front":"le prétexte","back":"pretext"});
b.push({"front":"épargner","back":"to save, spare"});
b.push({"front":"la démonstration","back":"demonstration"});
b.push({"front":"outre","back":"besides"});
b.push({"front":"une invasion","back":"invasion"});
b.push({"front":"dorénavant","back":"from now on, henceforth"});
b.push({"front":"valable","back":"valid"});
b.push({"front":"le barrage","back":"barrier, obstruction, dam, roadblock"});
b.push({"front":"la commune","back":"locality; common, joint"});
b.push({"front":"le latin","back":"Latin"});
b.push({"front":"la récolte","back":"harvest, crop"});
b.push({"front":"le diagnostic","back":"diagnosis"});
b.push({"front":"un isolé","back":"remote, isolated, insolated"});
b.push({"front":"démissionner","back":"to resign"});
b.push({"front":"le peintre, la peintre","back":"painter"});
b.push({"front":"la messe","back":"mass"});
b.push({"front":"la confusion","back":"confusion, mix-up"});
b.push({"front":"chimique","back":"chemical"});
b.push({"front":"le maigre","back":"thin, skinny, slim, lean"});
b.push({"front":"franchir","back":"to get over"});
b.push({"front":"pointer","back":"to mark off, clock in, clock out, aim"});
b.push({"front":"la violation","back":"violation, transgression"});
b.push({"front":"la vertu","back":"virtue"});
b.push({"front":"raccrocher","back":"to hang up"});
b.push({"front":"mexicain","back":"Mexican"});
b.push({"front":"inscrire","back":"to register, write down"});
b.push({"front":"le religieux","back":"religious"});
b.push({"front":"le stock","back":"stock, to supply"});
b.push({"front":"séduire","back":"to seduce, charm, captivate, appeal to"});
b.push({"front":"explorer","back":"to explore, investigate, examine"});
b.push({"front":"fondre","back":"to melt, merge"});
b.push({"front":"primaire","back":"primary"});
b.push({"front":"une assistance","back":"attendance, assistance"});
b.push({"front":"le rappel","back":"reminder, summary, recall, return, remember"});
b.push({"front":"sympathique","back":"likeable, nice, pleasant person"});
b.push({"front":"le passager","back":"passenger, temporary"});
b.push({"front":"stopper","back":"to stop, halt"});
b.push({"front":"le soulagement","back":"relief"});
b.push({"front":"déclarer","back":"to declare"});
b.push({"front":"instable","back":"unstable"});
b.push({"front":"le plancher","back":"floor"});
b.push({"front":"inévitable","back":"unavoidable, inevitable"});
b.push({"front":"justifier","back":"to justify"});
b.push({"front":"la confirmation","back":"confirmation"});
b.push({"front":"la séquence","back":"sequence"});
b.push({"front":"le voisinage","back":"neighborhood"});
b.push({"front":"insupportable","back":"intolerable"});
b.push({"front":"préserver","back":"to preserve"});
b.push({"front":"la performance","back":"performance"});
b.push({"front":"dépasser","back":"to pass, go beyond"});
b.push({"front":"le souhait","back":"wish"});
b.push({"front":"le dispositif","back":"device, apparatus"});
b.push({"front":"rude","back":"rough, harsh, hard, tough"});
b.push({"front":"sévère","back":"severe"});
b.push({"front":"la baie","back":"bay; berry"});
b.push({"front":"manifestement","back":"manifestly, clearly"});
b.push({"front":"la concentration","back":"concentration"});
b.push({"front":"le privilège","back":"privilege"});
b.push({"front":"humide","back":"moist, damp, humid, wet"});
b.push({"front":"exceptionnel","back":"exceptional"});
b.push({"front":"la préparation","back":"preparation"});
b.push({"front":"le réservoir","back":"tank, reservoir"});
b.push({"front":"le montage","back":"assembly, setting, pitching, putting, editing"});
b.push({"front":"le sixième, la sixième","back":"sixth"});
b.push({"front":"le rebelle","back":"rebel, rebellious"});
b.push({"front":"le pneu","back":"tire"});
b.push({"front":"naître","back":"to be born"});
b.push({"front":"divin","back":"divine, heavenly"});
b.push({"front":"menacer","back":"to threaten"});
b.push({"front":"le charbon","back":"coal"});
b.push({"front":"la coopération","back":"cooperation"});
b.push({"front":"une invention","back":"invention"});
b.push({"front":"néanmoins","back":"nevertheless"});
b.push({"front":"une expédition","back":"dispatch, shipping, shipment, expedition"});
b.push({"front":"raide","back":"stiff, straight"});
b.push({"front":"le pompier","back":"fireman, firefighter"});
b.push({"front":"déclencher","back":"to trigger, release, unleash"});
b.push({"front":"la détente","back":"release, relaxation, loosening"});
b.push({"front":"la philosophie","back":"philosophy"});
b.push({"front":"la croisière","back":"cruise"});
b.push({"front":"une adoption","back":"adoption, passing"});
b.push({"front":"une évaluation","back":"evaluation"});
b.push({"front":"un attentat","back":"attack, assassination attempt"});
b.push({"front":"une altitude","back":"altitude, height"});
b.push({"front":"authentique","back":"genuine, authentic"});
b.push({"front":"publier","back":"to publish"});
b.push({"front":"le capital","back":"major, chief, principal; capital, assets"});
b.push({"front":"le paiement","back":"payment"});
b.push({"front":"humble","back":"humble, lowly"});
b.push({"front":"un office","back":"office, bureau"});
b.push({"front":"le fermier","back":"farmer"});
b.push({"front":"la photographie","back":"photography"});
b.push({"front":"le communiste, la communiste","back":"communist"});
b.push({"front":"une hypothèse","back":"hypothesis"});
b.push({"front":"le calendrier","back":"calendar"});
b.push({"front":"le mental","back":"mental"});
b.push({"front":"ressortir","back":"to go out again, come out again, take out again"});
b.push({"front":"psychologique","back":"psychological"});
b.push({"front":"investir","back":"to invest"});
b.push({"front":"régulièrement","back":"regularly"});
b.push({"front":"exposer","back":"to display, exhibit, expose"});
b.push({"front":"le musicien","back":"musician"});
b.push({"front":"via","back":"via"});
b.push({"front":"le plume, la plume","back":"feather"});
b.push({"front":"la substance","back":"substance"});
b.push({"front":"la chimie","back":"chemistry"});
b.push({"front":"assumer","back":"to assume"});
b.push({"front":"un agenda","back":"diary, planner"});
b.push({"front":"le moine","back":"monk, friar"});
b.push({"front":"actuel","back":"current, present"});
b.push({"front":"le refus","back":"refusal"});
b.push({"front":"habituel","back":"customary, habitual"});
b.push({"front":"renseigner","back":"to give information, get information"});
b.push({"front":"la suggestion","back":"suggestion"});
b.push({"front":"le réaliste, la réaliste","back":"realist, realistic"});
b.push({"front":"familial","back":"family"});
b.push({"front":"féliciter","back":"to congratulate"});
b.push({"front":"le stage","back":"internship, training course"});
b.push({"front":"un abus","back":"abuse, misuse, breach"});
b.push({"front":"le carré","back":"square, broad, plain"});
b.push({"front":"juridique","back":"legal, judicial"});
b.push({"front":"vaste","back":"vast, immense"});
b.push({"front":"relâcher","back":"to loosen, release, let go"});
b.push({"front":"un établissement","back":"establishment, organization"});
b.push({"front":"un achat","back":"the purchase"});
b.push({"front":"la proximité","back":"proximity, nearness, closeness"});
b.push({"front":"atroce","back":"atrocious"});
b.push({"front":"redevenir","back":"to become again"});
b.push({"front":"le cycle","back":"cycle"});
b.push({"front":"une immigration","back":"immigration"});
b.push({"front":"débarquer","back":"to unload, land, disembark"});
b.push({"front":"une alimentation","back":"diet, food, groceries, supply"});
b.push({"front":"le recours","back":"resort, recourse"});
b.push({"front":"une inspection","back":"inspection"});
b.push({"front":"le coton","back":"cotton"});
b.push({"front":"le féminin","back":"feminine"});
b.push({"front":"intégrer","back":"to integrate"});
b.push({"front":"le créateur","back":"creator"});
b.push({"front":"comporter","back":"to comprise, include; to behave"});
b.push({"front":"prononcer","back":"to pronounce"});
b.push({"front":"étouffer","back":"to suffocate, smother, muffle"});
b.push({"front":"maîtriser","back":"to control, overcome, master"});
b.push({"front":"supprimer","back":"to remove, withdraw_"});
b.push({"front":"insulter","back":"to insult"});
b.push({"front":"une ironie","back":"irony"});
b.push({"front":"habituellement","back":"usually, generally"});
b.push({"front":"envisager","back":"to view, contemplate"});
b.push({"front":"le régiment","back":"regiment"});
b.push({"front":"transférer","back":"to transfer"});
b.push({"front":"le vapeur, la vapeur","back":"vapor, steam, steamship"});
b.push({"front":"décrocher","back":"to take down, take off, pick up, lift"});
b.push({"front":"un éditeur","back":"publisher, editor"});
b.push({"front":"imposer","back":"to impose"});
b.push({"front":"la guise","back":"wish; like, by way of"});
b.push({"front":"un écho","back":"echo"});
b.push({"front":"pénétrer","back":"to penetrate"});
b.push({"front":"la tonne","back":"ton"});
b.push({"front":"le comique","back":"comical; comic, comedian"});
b.push({"front":"formé","back":"formed"});
b.push({"front":"la colonie","back":"colony"});
b.push({"front":"élégant","back":"elegant, stylish"});
b.push({"front":"rigoler","back":"to laugh,"});
b.push({"front":"un obstacle","back":"obstacle"});
b.push({"front":"le confort","back":"comfort"});
b.push({"front":"obliger","back":"to require, force, oblige"});
b.push({"front":"imaginaire","back":"imaginary"});
b.push({"front":"revivre","back":"to live again, come back life, revive"});
b.push({"front":"céder","back":"to give up, give way"});
b.push({"front":"un acheteur","back":"buyer, purchaser"});
b.push({"front":"échouer","back":"to fail"});
b.push({"front":"la littérature","back":"literature"});
b.push({"front":"embarquer","back":"to embark, board, take on board, load"});
b.push({"front":"la démission","back":"resignation"});
b.push({"front":"le coude","back":"elbow"});
b.push({"front":"la permanence","back":"permanence, duty, service"});
b.push({"front":"mentionner","back":"to mention"});
b.push({"front":"repasser","back":"to cross again, retake, show again, iron"});
b.push({"front":"la conséquence","back":"consequence"});
b.push({"front":"la réflexion","back":"reflection"});
b.push({"front":"le ski","back":"ski, skiing"});
b.push({"front":"le bœuf","back":"ox, steer, beef"});
b.push({"front":"la sûreté","back":"safety, reliability"});
b.push({"front":"le phénomène","back":"phenomenon"});
b.push({"front":"soulever","back":"to lift up"});
b.push({"front":"déterminé","back":"determined, resolute, specific"});
b.push({"front":"le logiciel","back":"software, program, application"});
b.push({"front":"une étiquette","back":"label, ticket, etiquette, sticker, tag"});
b.push({"front":"la coupure","back":"the cut, the cutting"});
b.push({"front":"la clôture","back":"enclosure; termination, closure"});
b.push({"front":"la prudence","back":"prudence, care, caution"});
b.push({"front":"apparaître","back":"to appear"});
b.push({"front":"procéder","back":"to proceed"});
b.push({"front":"mériter","back":"to deserve, merit"});
b.push({"front":"une intégrité","back":"integrity"});
b.push({"front":"un actif","back":"active"});
b.push({"front":"un enthousiasme","back":"enthusiasm, enthusiastically"});
b.push({"front":"un atout","back":"trump, asset"});
b.push({"front":"le calcul","back":"calculation"});
b.push({"front":"le volume","back":"volume"});
b.push({"front":"une alternative","back":"alternative, choice"});
b.push({"front":"adapter","back":"to adapt"});
b.push({"front":"la condamnation","back":"condemnation"});
b.push({"front":"une utilisation","back":"the use"});
b.push({"front":"une apparition","back":"appearance, apparition"});
b.push({"front":"le chrétien","back":"Christian"});
b.push({"front":"encourager","back":"to encourage"});
b.push({"front":"soulager","back":"to relieve, soothe, ease"});
b.push({"front":"entretenir","back":"to maintain"});
b.push({"front":"la définition","back":"definition"});
b.push({"front":"gai","back":"cheerful, merry, gay"});
b.push({"front":"supplémentaire","back":"additional"});
b.push({"front":"un arbitre, une arbitre","back":"referee, arbitrer, arbitrator"});
b.push({"front":"spatial","back":"spatial, space"});
b.push({"front":"honteux","back":"ashamed, shameful"});
b.push({"front":"la gestion","back":"management"});
b.push({"front":"économiser","back":"to save, save on, conserve"});
b.push({"front":"nuire","back":"to harm"});
b.push({"front":"le retrait","back":"the withdrawal"});
b.push({"front":"un éclat","back":"splinter, fragment, brightness, burst"});
b.push({"front":"mécanique","back":"mechanical"});
b.push({"front":"un architecte, une architecte","back":"architect"});
b.push({"front":"une épidémie","back":"epidemic"});
b.push({"front":"le mou","back":"soft"});
b.push({"front":"déchirer","back":"to tear up, tear, rip"});
b.push({"front":"la richesse","back":"wealth, richness"});
b.push({"front":"une indépendance","back":"independence"});
b.push({"front":"la dépense","back":"expense, expenditure"});
b.push({"front":"le sportif","back":"sports, athletic, competitive"});
b.push({"front":"reprocher","back":"to blame, reproach"});
b.push({"front":"un exemplaire","back":"exemplary; copy"});
b.push({"front":"la catégorie","back":"category"});
b.push({"front":"le terrorisme","back":"terrorism"});
b.push({"front":"une assemblée","back":"assembly, meeting"});
b.push({"front":"un égard","back":"consideration, respect, regard"});
b.push({"front":"le mètre","back":"meter"});
b.push({"front":"le décor","back":"scenery, décor, set"});
b.push({"front":"un horizon","back":"horizon, skyline"});
b.push({"front":"épouvantable","back":"terrible, appalling, dreadful"});
b.push({"front":"la grandeur","back":"size, greatness"});
b.push({"front":"écarter","back":"to separate, move apart, keep away"});
b.push({"front":"agressif","back":"aggressive"});
b.push({"front":"le prophète","back":"prophet"});
b.push({"front":"aérien","back":"aerial"});
b.push({"front":"une initiative","back":"initiative"});
b.push({"front":"garantir","back":"to guarantee"});
b.push({"front":"noter","back":"to note, notice"});
b.push({"front":"le logement","back":"accommodation"});
b.push({"front":"bloquer","back":"to block"});
b.push({"front":"muet","back":"mute, silent, dumb"});
b.push({"front":"le semestre","back":"semester, six-month period"});
b.push({"front":"le brutal","back":"brutal"});
b.push({"front":"quelquefois","back":"sometimes"});
b.push({"front":"plaisanter","back":"to joke"});
b.push({"front":"le mythe","back":"myth"});
b.push({"front":"parvenir","back":"to reach, achieve"});
b.push({"front":"un optimiste, une optimiste","back":"optimistic"});
b.push({"front":"la représentation","back":"representation"});
b.push({"front":"le fouet","back":"whip"});
b.push({"front":"économique","back":"economic, economical"});
b.push({"front":"enfoncer","back":"to ram, drive in, hammer in, sink in"});
b.push({"front":"haïr","back":"to detest, hate, abhor"});
b.push({"front":"la racine","back":"root"});
b.push({"front":"la patte","back":"paw, foot, leg"});
b.push({"front":"posséder","back":"to possess, own, have"});
b.push({"front":"un outil","back":"tool"});
b.push({"front":"le reportage","back":"report, reporting"});
b.push({"front":"récent","back":"recent"});
b.push({"front":"la constitution","back":"constitution"});
b.push({"front":"contenir","back":"to contain"});
b.push({"front":"doubler","back":"to double, pass; to dub"});
b.push({"front":"pleuvoir","back":"to rain"});
b.push({"front":"la certitude","back":"certainty"});
b.push({"front":"le conséquent","back":"logical, rational, consistent"});
b.push({"front":"adresser","back":"to address"});
b.push({"front":"le bilan","back":"balance sheet, outcome"});
b.push({"front":"gravement","back":"seriously, solemnly, gravely"});
b.push({"front":"un argument","back":"argument"});
b.push({"front":"la banlieue","back":"suburbs, outskirts"});
b.push({"front":"le curé","back":"parish priest"});
b.push({"front":"la convention","back":"agreement, convention"});
b.push({"front":"un excès","back":"excess, surplus, abuse"});
b.push({"front":"le rassemblement","back":"gathering, collecting, assembling"});
b.push({"front":"souffler","back":"to blow, puff"});
b.push({"front":"accélérer","back":"to speed up, accelerate"});
b.push({"front":"le quotidien","back":"daily"});
b.push({"front":"encaisser","back":"to receive, collect, cash"});
b.push({"front":"jurer","back":"to swear"});
b.push({"front":"ironique","back":"ironic"});
b.push({"front":"croiser","back":"to cross"});
b.push({"front":"le paysage","back":"landscape, scenery, countryside"});
b.push({"front":"la province","back":"province"});
b.push({"front":"spirituel","back":"witty, spiritual, sacred"});
b.push({"front":"supplier","back":"to beg, implore"});
b.push({"front":"mesurer","back":"to measure"});
b.push({"front":"le convoi","back":"convoy, train"});
b.push({"front":"touchant","back":"with regard to, concerning, touching, moving"});
b.push({"front":"la psychologie","back":"psychology"});
b.push({"front":"un isolement","back":"loneliness, isolation, insulation"});
b.push({"front":"contenter","back":"to satisfy, please"});
b.push({"front":"la perspective","back":"perspective, viewpoint"});
b.push({"front":"la discrétion","back":"discretion"});
b.push({"front":"largement","back":"widely"});
b.push({"front":"modifier","back":"to modify, adjust"});
b.push({"front":"le visiteur","back":"visitor"});
b.push({"front":"une obligation","back":"obligation, bond"});
b.push({"front":"la pâte","back":"paste, dough, pasta"});
b.push({"front":"le combattant","back":"fighter"});
b.push({"front":"percer","back":"to pierce, drill, break into"});
b.push({"front":"corriger","back":"to correct"});
b.push({"front":"le contexte","back":"context"});
b.push({"front":"poster","back":"poster; to post, mail"});
b.push({"front":"la conception","back":"conception"});
b.push({"front":"le dépit","back":"spite, heartache"});
b.push({"front":"le bassin","back":"bowl, basin"});
b.push({"front":"le continent","back":"continent"});
b.push({"front":"la fiction","back":"fiction"});
b.push({"front":"le trait","back":"line, feature"});
b.push({"front":"le tournant","back":"revolving, swivel, encircling, bend, turning point"});
b.push({"front":"une avancée","back":"advanced, overhung"});
b.push({"front":"le mouton","back":"sheep"});
b.push({"front":"le croyant","back":"believer"});
b.push({"front":"la croissance","back":"growth"});
b.push({"front":"le commencement","back":"beginning, start"});
b.push({"front":"la compréhension","back":"understanding, comprehension"});
b.push({"front":"le porteur","back":"carrier, holder"});
b.push({"front":"la réduction","back":"reduction"});
b.push({"front":"le triomphe","back":"triumph"});
b.push({"front":"fortement","back":"strongly"});
b.push({"front":"piloter","back":"to fly, pilot, drive"});
b.push({"front":"le majeur","back":"major"});
b.push({"front":"vanter","back":"to vaunt, boast, brag"});
b.push({"front":"viser","back":"to aim"});
b.push({"front":"le flux","back":"flow"});
b.push({"front":"le nœud","back":"knot"});
b.push({"front":"municipal","back":"municipal"});
b.push({"front":"la distribution","back":"distribution"});
b.push({"front":"le renseignement","back":"information"});
b.push({"front":"la fidélité","back":"loyalty, faithfulness, accuracy, reliability"});
b.push({"front":"la trêve","back":"truce"});
b.push({"front":"secouer","back":"to shake"});
b.push({"front":"le bijou","back":"jewel"});
b.push({"front":"la satisfaction","back":"satisfaction"});
b.push({"front":"toutefois","back":"however"});
b.push({"front":"la concurrence","back":"competition"});
b.push({"front":"visible","back":"visible, obvious"});
b.push({"front":"la signification","back":"significance"});
b.push({"front":"suggérer","back":"to suggest"});
b.push({"front":"le survivant","back":"survivor, surviving"});
b.push({"front":"le vieillard","back":"old man"});
b.push({"front":"nommer","back":"to call, name, appoint"});
b.push({"front":"un horaire","back":"schedule, timetable, hourly"});
b.push({"front":"le réacteur","back":"reactor, jet engine"});
b.push({"front":"rétablir","back":"to restore, re-establish"});
b.push({"front":"le bénéfice","back":"benefit, profit"});
b.push({"front":"un organisme","back":"organism"});
b.push({"front":"condamner","back":"to condemn"});
b.push({"front":"librement","back":"freely"});
b.push({"front":"une harmonie","back":"harmony"});
b.push({"front":"défaire","back":"to undo, dismantle, strip, break up"});
b.push({"front":"la diffusion","back":"diffusion, spreading, circulation"});
b.push({"front":"le visa","back":"visa, stamp"});
b.push({"front":"la déception","back":"disappointment, let-down"});
b.push({"front":"le milliard","back":"billion, thousand million"});
b.push({"front":"envoler","back":"to fly away, fly off, take off"});
b.push({"front":"la générosité","back":"generosity, generously"});
b.push({"front":"plaider","back":"to plead"});
b.push({"front":"reproduire","back":"to reproduce, repeat"});
b.push({"front":"deuxièmement","back":"secondly"});
b.push({"front":"le péril","back":"peril"});
b.push({"front":"le tremblement","back":"shiver, trembling, shaking"});
b.push({"front":"rassurer","back":"to reassure, calm down"});
b.push({"front":"romain","back":"Roman"});
b.push({"front":"toxique","back":"toxic, toxin"});
b.push({"front":"la vérification","back":"check, verification"});
b.push({"front":"le reproche","back":"reproach"});
b.push({"front":"le protecteur","back":"protective, protector, guardian"});
b.push({"front":"presser","back":"to squeeze, press"});
b.push({"front":"une impatience","back":"impatience"});
b.push({"front":"verser","back":"to pour, deposit, shed"});
b.push({"front":"un infini","back":"inifinite, infinity"});
b.push({"front":"amical","back":"friendly"});
b.push({"front":"flou","back":"blurred, fuzzy, vague"});
b.push({"front":"le danseur","back":"dancer"});
b.push({"front":"semer","back":"to sow, scatter, spread"});
b.push({"front":"appliquer","back":"to apply"});
b.push({"front":"indiquer","back":"to indicate, signal"});
b.push({"front":"un acquis","back":"acquired, experience"});
b.push({"front":"le sinistre","back":"disaster, sinister"});
b.push({"front":"jadis","back":"formerly, long ago"});
b.push({"front":"supposer","back":"to suppose, assume"});
b.push({"front":"le climat","back":"climate"});
b.push({"front":"soviétique","back":"Soviet"});
b.push({"front":"un intermédiaire, une intermédiaire","back":"intermediate, intermediary"});
b.push({"front":"le séminaire","back":"seminar, seminary"});
b.push({"front":"principalement","back":"principally, mainly, primarily"});
b.push({"front":"conserver","back":"to keep, preserve"});
b.push({"front":"quarante","back":"forty"});
b.push({"front":"le bulletin","back":"bulletin, report"});
b.push({"front":"un extrait","back":"extract, excerpt"});
b.push({"front":"défier","back":"to challenge, defy, distrust"});
b.push({"front":"boucler","back":"to fasten, loop, resolve"});
b.push({"front":"la pauvreté","back":"poverty"});
b.push({"front":"une embauche","back":"job vacancy, hiring"});
b.push({"front":"le recul","back":"backward movement, setback, slip"});
b.push({"front":"valoir","back":"to be worth"});
b.push({"front":"la précision","back":"precision"});
b.push({"front":"indispensable","back":"essential"});
b.push({"front":"harceler","back":"to harass, plague"});
b.push({"front":"le comble","back":"despair; summit, overmeasure; roof"});
b.push({"front":"le cliché","back":"cliché; negative"});
b.push({"front":"anormal","back":"abnormal"});
b.push({"front":"crédible","back":"credible"});
b.push({"front":"un ouvrier","back":"worker"});
b.push({"front":"procurer","back":"to get, bring"});
b.push({"front":"une installation","back":"installation, setup"});
b.push({"front":"la révélation","back":"diclosure, revelation"});
b.push({"front":"un immédiat","back":"immediate"});
b.push({"front":"introduire","back":"to introduce"});
b.push({"front":"hostile","back":"hostile"});
b.push({"front":"le préfet","back":"prefect"});
b.push({"front":"insister","back":"to insist"});
b.push({"front":"soumettre","back":"to submit"});
b.push({"front":"une inscription","back":"registration, enrolment; engraving"});
b.push({"front":"épais","back":"thick, pitch dark, thickly"});
b.push({"front":"anéantir","back":"to annihilate, wipe out, ruin, vanish"});
b.push({"front":"lier","back":"to link, join"});
b.push({"front":"embaucher","back":"to hire"});
b.push({"front":"étendre","back":"to spread out, stretch out"});
b.push({"front":"citer","back":"to quote"});
b.push({"front":"la marée","back":"tide"});
b.push({"front":"indépendant","back":"independent"});
b.push({"front":"le culte","back":"worship, cult"});
b.push({"front":"le mépris","back":"contempt, scorn, disdain"});
b.push({"front":"une utilité","back":"use, usefulness,"});
b.push({"front":"emmerder","back":"to bug, bother"});
b.push({"front":"préférable","back":"preferable"});
b.push({"front":"une épargne","back":"savings, saving"});
b.push({"front":"la sympathie","back":"liking, warmth, friendship, sympathie"});
b.push({"front":"bancaire","back":"banking"});
b.push({"front":"un exclu, une exclu","back":"outcast"});
b.push({"front":"aborder","back":"to reach, approach"});
b.push({"front":"la motivation","back":"motivation, application"});
b.push({"front":"la gamme","back":"range, scale"});
b.push({"front":"massacrer","back":"to slaughter, massacre"});
b.push({"front":"conquérir","back":"to conquer"});
b.push({"front":"suffire","back":"to be sufficient, suffice"});
b.push({"front":"le pavillon","back":"country house, villa, wing pavilliion, flag"});
b.push({"front":"jouir","back":"to enjoy"});
b.push({"front":"exercer","back":"to exercise, exert, practise, carry out"});
b.push({"front":"tenant","back":"tenant; incumbent, holder"});
b.push({"front":"plier","back":"to fold, fold up, fold back, bend"});
b.push({"front":"une application","back":"application"});
b.push({"front":"la librairie","back":"bookstore, bookshop"});
b.push({"front":"une opposition","back":"opposition"});
b.push({"front":"atomique","back":"atomic"});
b.push({"front":"convenable","back":"suitable, appropriate, correct, proper, acceptable"});
b.push({"front":"la précaution","back":"precaution"});
b.push({"front":"la contribution","back":"contribution"});
b.push({"front":"volontairement","back":"voluntarily, willingly"});
b.push({"front":"asiatique","back":"Asian"});
b.push({"front":"le communiqué","back":"communiqué, release, statement"});
b.push({"front":"répandre","back":"to spread, spill"});
b.push({"front":"passionnant","back":"fascinating, exciting"});
b.push({"front":"rejeter","back":"to reject"});
b.push({"front":"le semblable, la semblable","back":"similar"});
b.push({"front":"reconstruire","back":"to rebuild, reconstruct"});
b.push({"front":"le poumon","back":"lung"});
b.push({"front":"distribuer","back":"to distribute, give out"});
b.push({"front":"pratiquer","back":"to practice"});
b.push({"front":"le banquier","back":"banker"});
b.push({"front":"le globe","back":"globe"});
b.push({"front":"achever","back":"to complete, finish, end"});
b.push({"front":"le repère","back":"reference, benchmark, landmark"});
b.push({"front":"équitable","back":"equitable, fair"});
b.push({"front":"admirer","back":"to admire"});
b.push({"front":"la tranche","back":"slice, edge, section, bracket, slot"});
b.push({"front":"la thèse","back":"thesis, argument"});
b.push({"front":"un orgueil","back":"pride"});
b.push({"front":"baigner","back":"to bathe, wash, get a bath, go for a swim"});
b.push({"front":"le millier","back":"thousand"});
b.push({"front":"briller","back":"to shine"});
b.push({"front":"ambitieux","back":"ambitious, man with ambition"});
b.push({"front":"le cheveu","back":"hair"});
b.push({"front":"une onde","back":"wave"});
b.push({"front":"inacceptable","back":"unacceptabe"});
b.push({"front":"un explosif","back":"explosive"});
b.push({"front":"la distorsion","back":"distortion"});
b.push({"front":"le septième, la septième","back":"seventh"});
b.push({"front":"la bulle","back":"bubble"});
b.push({"front":"une ignorance","back":"ignorance"});
b.push({"front":"inattendu","back":"unexpected"});
b.push({"front":"la franchise","back":"frankness, exemption, duty-free, franchise, deductible"});
b.push({"front":"évaluer","back":"to evaluate"});
b.push({"front":"similaire","back":"similar"});
b.push({"front":"un itinéraire","back":"itinerary, route"});
b.push({"front":"disposer","back":"to arrange, set"});
b.push({"front":"extraire","back":"to extract, mine, quarry, pull out, remove"});
b.push({"front":"allié","back":"allied; ally"});
b.push({"front":"fréquenter","back":"to frequent, go around with"});
b.push({"front":"la citation","back":"quote, quotation, citation"});
b.push({"front":"détourner","back":"to redirect"});
b.push({"front":"le reflet","back":"reflection, glint, highlight"});
b.push({"front":"le lecteur","back":"reader"});
b.push({"front":"le nazi","back":"Nazi"});
b.push({"front":"tracer","back":"to draw, write, mark out"});
b.push({"front":"la cote","back":"rating, share index, quoted value"});
b.push({"front":"éclairer","back":"to light up"});
b.push({"front":"la vingtaine","back":"about twenty"});
b.push({"front":"le révolutionnaire, la révolutionnaire","back":"revolutionary"});
b.push({"front":"un aire, une aire","back":"surface, area"});
b.push({"front":"mélanger","back":"to mix, mix up, confuse"});
b.push({"front":"naïf","back":"naïve, innocent"});
b.push({"front":"méfier","back":"to distrust, mistrust"});
b.push({"front":"le phare","back":"lighthouse, headlight"});
b.push({"front":"un adolescent","back":"teenager, adolescent"});
b.push({"front":"le coût","back":"cost"});
b.push({"front":"le gène","back":"gene"});
b.push({"front":"la session","back":"session"});
b.push({"front":"un envoi","back":"sending, dispatching"});
b.push({"front":"la consultation","back":"consultation"});
b.push({"front":"un universitaire, une universitaire","back":"university, academic"});
b.push({"front":"exploiter","back":"to exploit"});
b.push({"front":"absolu","back":"absolute"});
b.push({"front":"creux","back":"hollow, empty, hole"});
b.push({"front":"la notion","back":"notion"});
b.push({"front":"prétendu","back":"so-called, alleged"});
b.push({"front":"bâtir","back":"to build"});
b.push({"front":"découper","back":"to carve, cut,"});
b.push({"front":"spécifique","back":"specific"});
b.push({"front":"contourner","back":"to bypass, go round"});
b.push({"front":"un enseignement","back":"education, teaching"});
b.push({"front":"la coutume","back":"custom"});
b.push({"front":"une étendue","back":"area, expanse, duration, extent, range"});
b.push({"front":"ôter","back":"to remove, take away, take off, take out"});
b.push({"front":"le blond","back":"blond, fair-haired"});
b.push({"front":"un infirmier","back":"nurse"});
b.push({"front":"barrer","back":"to close, block, bar, cross"});
b.push({"front":"un entrepreneur","back":"contractor, entrepreneur"});
b.push({"front":"permanent","back":"permanent"});
b.push({"front":"la devise","back":"currency, motto, slogan"});
b.push({"front":"identique","back":"identical"});
b.push({"front":"la réparation","back":"repair, repairing, correction, compensation"});
b.push({"front":"musical","back":"musical"});
b.push({"front":"la prostitution","back":"prostitution"});
b.push({"front":"banal","back":"banal, trite, commonplace, ordinary"});
b.push({"front":"le cordon","back":"cord, string, lead"});
b.push({"front":"critiquer","back":"to criticize"});
b.push({"front":"seize","back":"sixteen"});
b.push({"front":"la brèche","back":"breach, gap"});
b.push({"front":"un appui","back":"support"});
b.push({"front":"une entrevue","back":"meeting, interview"});
b.push({"front":"inculper","back":"to charge"});
b.push({"front":"financer","back":"to finance"});
b.push({"front":"persuader","back":"to convince, persuade"});
b.push({"front":"la candidature","back":"application, candidacy, candidature"});
b.push({"front":"la cruauté","back":"cruelty"});
b.push({"front":"unir","back":"to unite"});
b.push({"front":"la transaction","back":"transaction"});
b.push({"front":"le fondé, la fondé","back":"founded, justified; agent, clerk"});
b.push({"front":"un amendement","back":"amendment"});
b.push({"front":"une atteinte","back":"reach; attack, blow"});
b.push({"front":"fatal","back":"fatal, deadly, fateful"});
b.push({"front":"isoler","back":"to isolate, insulate"});
b.push({"front":"traduire","back":"to translate"});
b.push({"front":"la vitrine","back":"window, display cabinet"});
b.push({"front":"le correspondant","back":"correspondent"});
b.push({"front":"une approbation","back":"approval"});
b.push({"front":"mondial","back":"world, global"});
b.push({"front":"la transition","back":"transition"});
b.push({"front":"le consentement","back":"consent"});
b.push({"front":"le parlement","back":"parliament"});
b.push({"front":"spectaculaire","back":"spectacular"});
b.push({"front":"le pêcheur","back":"fisherman"});
b.push({"front":"le détour","back":"bend, curve, detour"});
b.push({"front":"terrestre","back":"land, earth"});
b.push({"front":"une institution","back":"institution"});
b.push({"front":"le polonais","back":"Polish"});
b.push({"front":"immobile","back":"still, motionless"});
b.push({"front":"la tentation","back":"temptation"});
b.push({"front":"la participation","back":"participation"});
b.push({"front":"insensible","back":"insensitive"});
b.push({"front":"une injustice","back":"injustice, unfairness"});
b.push({"front":"nécessairement","back":"necessarily"});
b.push({"front":"réclamer","back":"to ask for, call for; to claim"});
b.push({"front":"le cahier","back":"notebook"});
b.push({"front":"relier","back":"to connect"});
b.push({"front":"enthousiaste","back":"enthusiastic"});
b.push({"front":"une interdiction","back":"ban, banning"});
b.push({"front":"le nocturne","back":"nocturnal, nocturne"});
b.push({"front":"retarder","back":"to delay, hold up"});
b.push({"front":"la suspension","back":"hanging, suspending, breaking off, postponement, suspension"});
b.push({"front":"confiant","back":"trusting, confident"});
b.push({"front":"réserver","back":"to reserve, keep"});
b.push({"front":"strictement","back":"strictly"});
b.push({"front":"le solde, la solde","back":"balance; pay; sale"});
b.push({"front":"un athlète, une athlète","back":"athlete"});
b.push({"front":"un élan","back":"momentum, surge, rush; elk, moose"});
b.push({"front":"une orientation","back":"orientation, trend"});
b.push({"front":"le mécanisme","back":"mechanism"});
b.push({"front":"le masculin","back":"male, masculine"});
b.push({"front":"affirmer","back":"to affirm, maintain, declare, allege"});
b.push({"front":"la négociation","back":"negotiation"});
b.push({"front":"compréhensible","back":"comprehensible, understandable"});
b.push({"front":"effondrer","back":"to collapse, cave in, fall down"});
b.push({"front":"le pôle","back":"pole"});
b.push({"front":"la manifestation","back":"demonstration, event"});
b.push({"front":"la sélection","back":"selection"});
b.push({"front":"un abandon","back":"abandonment, desertion, withdrawal"});
b.push({"front":"obscur","back":"dark, vague, obscure"});
b.push({"front":"obligatoire","back":"mandatory, compulsory"});
b.push({"front":"le paysan","back":"farmer, peasant"});
b.push({"front":"trembler","back":"to shiver, tremble, shake, flicker"});
b.push({"front":"opposer","back":"to oppose"});
b.push({"front":"le désaccord","back":"disagreement, discord, conflict"});
b.push({"front":"le schéma","back":"diagram, outline"});
b.push({"front":"le dirigeant","back":"leader"});
b.push({"front":"une émeute","back":"riot, rioting"});
b.push({"front":"treize","back":"thirteen"});
b.push({"front":"vieillir","back":"to grow old"});
b.push({"front":"un enquêteur","back":"investigator, pollster"});
b.push({"front":"provisoire","back":"temporary, provisional"});
b.push({"front":"amer","back":"bitter"});
b.push({"front":"le fournisseur","back":"supplier, provider"});
b.push({"front":"la fédération","back":"federation"});
b.push({"front":"la recommandation","back":"recommendation"});
b.push({"front":"convaincant","back":"convincing"});
b.push({"front":"détacher","back":"to untie, detach, remove"});
b.push({"front":"gêner","back":"to bother, trouble"});
b.push({"front":"la résolution","back":"resolution"});
b.push({"front":"la juridiction","back":"jurisdiction, court of law"});
b.push({"front":"le fossé","back":"ditch"});
b.push({"front":"intact","back":"intact"});
b.push({"front":"un évêque, une évêque","back":"bishop"});
b.push({"front":"la comparaison","back":"comparison"});
b.push({"front":"la présidence","back":"presidency"});
b.push({"front":"la nécessité","back":"necessity, need"});
b.push({"front":"le malaise","back":"uneasiness, discomfort"});
b.push({"front":"un exil","back":"exile"});
b.push({"front":"consacrer","back":"to devote, consecrate"});
b.push({"front":"une impulsion","back":"impulse, pulse"});
b.push({"front":"une interprétation","back":"interpretation"});
b.push({"front":"délibérément","back":"deliberately"});
b.push({"front":"le terminal","back":"terminal"});
b.push({"front":"affecter","back":"to affect"});
b.push({"front":"le récit","back":"account, narrative"});
b.push({"front":"la clientèle","back":"customers, clientele"});
b.push({"front":"le procédé","back":"processus"});
b.push({"front":"un employeur","back":"employer"});
b.push({"front":"la rive","back":"shore, bank"});
b.push({"front":"divers","back":"diverse, various"});
b.push({"front":"la finance","back":"finance"});
b.push({"front":"gigantesque","back":"gigantic, immense"});
b.push({"front":"une agitation","back":"agitation, excitement"});
b.push({"front":"expulser","back":"to expel, evict, deport, throw out"});
b.push({"front":"le voyageur","back":"traveler"});
b.push({"front":"le suédois","back":"Swedish, Swede"});
b.push({"front":"acceptable","back":"acceptable, satisfactory"});
b.push({"front":"le travailleur","back":"worker"});
b.push({"front":"emparer","back":"to seize, grab, snatch"});
b.push({"front":"neutre","back":"neutral"});
b.push({"front":"une infraction","back":"offence, infrigement, infraction"});
b.push({"front":"parcourir","back":"to cover, travel"});
b.push({"front":"le pair","back":"peer, pair, even"});
b.push({"front":"pleinement","back":"fully, thoroughly"});
b.push({"front":"la collaboration","back":"collaboration"});
b.push({"front":"la transformation","back":"transformation, change"});
b.push({"front":"lointain","back":"distant, faraway"});
b.push({"front":"la faculté","back":"ability, right, option; faculty, university"});
b.push({"front":"le seuil","back":"doorstep, threshold"});
b.push({"front":"faciliter","back":"to make easier, facilitate"});
b.push({"front":"la vocation","back":"vocation, calling"});
b.push({"front":"régulier","back":"regular"});
b.push({"front":"le support","back":"support, stand"});
b.push({"front":"encontre","back":"contrary to"});
b.push({"front":"le néant","back":"nothingness"});
b.push({"front":"la considération","back":"consideration"});
b.push({"front":"le frein","back":"brake"});
b.push({"front":"le déplacement","back":"movement, displacement, trip, travel"});
b.push({"front":"hésiter","back":"to hesitate"});
b.push({"front":"le descendant","back":"downward, descending, descendant"});
b.push({"front":"influencer","back":"to influence"});
b.push({"front":"une aviation","back":"aviation"});
b.push({"front":"dévoiler","back":"to unveil, reveal, disclose"});
b.push({"front":"un autobus","back":"bus"});
b.push({"front":"purement","back":"purely"});
b.push({"front":"manuscrit","back":"manuscript, handwritten"});
b.push({"front":"étroit","back":"narrow, tight"});
b.push({"front":"le kilo","back":"kilo"});
b.push({"front":"audacieux","back":"daring, audacious, bold"});
b.push({"front":"une occupation","back":"occupation, pastime"});
b.push({"front":"défiler","back":"to unthread, parade"});
b.push({"front":"compromettre","back":"to compromise"});
b.push({"front":"planifier","back":"to plan"});
b.push({"front":"activer","back":"to activate, speed up, stoke, get moving"});
b.push({"front":"global","back":"global"});
b.push({"front":"le fonctionnaire, la fonctionnaire","back":"state employee, public servant"});
b.push({"front":"éclaircir","back":"to brighten up, clear up"});
b.push({"front":"delà","back":"beyond, above, over"});
b.push({"front":"la projection","back":"projection, ejection, discharge"});
b.push({"front":"réviser","back":"to review, revise, overhaul"});
b.push({"front":"imiter","back":"to imitate"});
b.push({"front":"la dizaine","back":"approximately ten"});
b.push({"front":"la composition","back":"composition, essay, dialling"});
b.push({"front":"une allusion","back":"allusion"});
b.push({"front":"la lèvre","back":"lip"});
b.push({"front":"un impuissant","back":"powerless, helpless"});
b.push({"front":"envahir","back":"to invade, overrun"});
b.push({"front":"la révolte","back":"revolt"});
b.push({"front":"le cynique, la cynique","back":"cynical, cynic"});
b.push({"front":"une implication","back":"implication"});
b.push({"front":"débattre","back":"to discuss, debate"});
b.push({"front":"le spectre","back":"spectrum, ghost"});
b.push({"front":"le contrôleur","back":"inspector, controller"});
b.push({"front":"la fabrication","back":"manufacture, production"});
b.push({"front":"la préférence","back":"preference, preferably"});
b.push({"front":"la réalisation","back":"realization, achievement"});
b.push({"front":"renforcer","back":"to reinforce, strengthen"});
b.push({"front":"la sensibilité","back":"sensitivity, sensibility"});
b.push({"front":"le soupçon","back":"suspicion"});
b.push({"front":"le rédacteur","back":"editor, writer, drafter, compiler"});
b.push({"front":"odieux","back":"hateful, odious"});
b.push({"front":"la rébellion","back":"rebellion"});
b.push({"front":"une esthétique","back":"aesthetics, attractiveness; attractive"});
b.push({"front":"féroce","back":"ferocious, fierce"});
b.push({"front":"un homosexuel","back":"homosexual"});
b.push({"front":"le trimestre","back":"quarter; three months"});
b.push({"front":"le pourcentage","back":"percentage, commission, cut"});
b.push({"front":"autoriser","back":"to authorize"});
b.push({"front":"chaleureux","back":"warm"});
b.push({"front":"une extraction","back":"extraction"});
b.push({"front":"un organe","back":"organ"});
b.push({"front":"lumineux","back":"luminous, illuminated; light"});
b.push({"front":"quatorze","back":"fourteen"});
b.push({"front":"la navigation","back":"navigation"});
b.push({"front":"la maintenance","back":"maintenance, servicing"});
b.push({"front":"la reprise","back":"resumption, renewal; time"});
b.push({"front":"un armement","back":"arms, weapons, armament"});
b.push({"front":"fonder","back":"to found, set"});
b.push({"front":"vital","back":"vital"});
b.push({"front":"connecter","back":"to connect, go on-line"});
b.push({"front":"préciser","back":"to state, specify, clarify"});
b.push({"front":"le boulevard","back":"boulevard"});
b.push({"front":"le gel","back":"frost, freezing, gel"});
b.push({"front":"un aveu","back":"confession"});
b.push({"front":"un émetteur","back":"transmitter, issuer"});
b.push({"front":"régner","back":"to reign"});
b.push({"front":"le slogan","back":"slogan"});
b.push({"front":"circuler","back":"to drive, circulate"});
b.push({"front":"la pente","back":"slope"});
b.push({"front":"une exploitation","back":"operation, exploitation"});
b.push({"front":"trancher","back":"to cut, sever, settle, decide"});
b.push({"front":"un emprunt","back":"loan"});
b.push({"front":"un opérateur","back":"operator"});
b.push({"front":"la querelle","back":"quarrel"});
b.push({"front":"effectuer","back":"to carry out, undergo"});
b.push({"front":"la tendresse","back":"tenderness, fondness"});
b.push({"front":"annuel","back":"annual"});
b.push({"front":"autrui","back":"others"});
b.push({"front":"la firme","back":"firm"});
b.push({"front":"numérique","back":"numerical"});
b.push({"front":"la consommation","back":"consumption"});
b.push({"front":"un entourage","back":"circle, entourage"});
b.push({"front":"regagner","back":"to win again, regain, get back, make up"});
b.push({"front":"le technicien","back":"technician"});
b.push({"front":"le chancelier","back":"chancellor"});
b.push({"front":"la complicité","back":"complicity"});
b.push({"front":"la trentaine","back":"about thirty"});
b.push({"front":"délivrer","back":"to set free, rid, relieve"});
b.push({"front":"une automobile","back":"automobile"});
b.push({"front":"dresser","back":"to draw up, put up, raise"});
b.push({"front":"un handicapé","back":"disabled, handicapped"});
b.push({"front":"crucial","back":"crucial, critical"});
b.push({"front":"la mutation","back":"transfer, transformation, mutation"});
b.push({"front":"le fondateur","back":"founder"});
b.push({"front":"récolter","back":"to harvest, gather"});
b.push({"front":"une entente","back":"understanding, agreement"});
b.push({"front":"le turc","back":"Turk, Turkish"});
b.push({"front":"un oubli","back":"forgetting, leaving behind, missing"});
b.push({"front":"la mention","back":"mention, note, comment, notice"});
b.push({"front":"le chronique, la chronique","back":"chronic, column, page, chronicle"});
b.push({"front":"dynamique","back":"dynamic"});
b.push({"front":"la maternité","back":"maternity, motherhood"});
b.push({"front":"apercevoir","back":"to see, notice"});
b.push({"front":"scandaleux","back":"scandalous, outrageous"});
b.push({"front":"quasi","back":"almost, nearly"});
b.push({"front":"inquiétant","back":"worrying, disturbing"});
b.push({"front":"brancher","back":"to plug in, connect"});
b.push({"front":"durement","back":"harshly, severely"});
b.push({"front":"hautement","back":"highly"});
b.push({"front":"le kilomètre","back":"kilometer"});
b.push({"front":"abuser","back":"to abuse, mislead, take advantage"});
b.push({"front":"une hausse","back":"rise, raise, increase"});
b.push({"front":"une annulation","back":"cancellation, annulment"});
b.push({"front":"fâcher","back":"to anger, make angry, get angry"});
b.push({"front":"la démarche","back":"walk, process"});
b.push({"front":"susceptible","back":"sensitive, touchy"});
b.push({"front":"mutuellement","back":"mutually, one another"});
b.push({"front":"doré","back":"golden"});
b.push({"front":"le musulman","back":"Muslim, Moslem"});
b.push({"front":"atlantique","back":"Atlantic"});
b.push({"front":"dominer","back":"to dominate"});
b.push({"front":"la motion","back":"motion"});
b.push({"front":"distinguer","back":"to distinguish"});
b.push({"front":"définir","back":"to define"});
b.push({"front":"loger","back":"to put up, accommodate, stay, find accommodation"});
b.push({"front":"clandestin","back":"underground, clandestine"});
b.push({"front":"un axe","back":"axis, axle, main line"});
b.push({"front":"diplomatique","back":"diplomatic"});
b.push({"front":"une architecture","back":"architecture"});
b.push({"front":"vivement","back":"sharply, brusquely, lively"});
b.push({"front":"le républicain","back":"republican"});
b.push({"front":"la détermination","back":"determination, resolution"});
b.push({"front":"photographier","back":"to photograph"});
b.push({"front":"naviguer","back":"to navigate, sail"});
b.push({"front":"le noyau","back":"core, nucleus, pit"});
b.push({"front":"une efficacité","back":"efficiency, effectiveness"});
b.push({"front":"la réciproque","back":"mutual, reciprocal, the opposite"});
b.push({"front":"la provenance","back":"origin, strange"});
b.push({"front":"le dialogue","back":"dialogue"});
b.push({"front":"pertinent","back":"pertinent, relevant"});
b.push({"front":"le touriste, la touriste","back":"tourist"});
b.push({"front":"subtil","back":"subtle, nice"});
b.push({"front":"le politicien","back":"politician"});
b.push({"front":"réjouir","back":"to delight, rejoice"});
b.push({"front":"redoutable","back":"fearsome, formidable"});
b.push({"front":"difficilement","back":"with difficulty"});
b.push({"front":"le fléau","back":"scourge, plague"});
b.push({"front":"le collectif","back":"collective"});
b.push({"front":"la perception","back":"perception, collection"});
b.push({"front":"claquer","back":"to flap, bang, slam, snap"});
b.push({"front":"menaçant","back":"threatening, menacing"});
b.push({"front":"la dépendance","back":"dependence, dependency"});
b.push({"front":"un enseignant","back":"teacher"});
b.push({"front":"prévisible","back":"predictable, forseeable"});
b.push({"front":"le financement","back":"financing"});
b.push({"front":"le savant","back":"scientist, scholar, learned, scholarly, clever, skilfull"});
b.push({"front":"diviser","back":"to divide"});
b.push({"front":"la comptabilité","back":"accountancy, accounting, book-keeping"});
b.push({"front":"le jumeau","back":"twin"});
b.push({"front":"priver","back":"to deprive"});
b.push({"front":"la larme","back":"tear"});
b.push({"front":"assurément","back":"most certainly"});
b.push({"front":"la totalité","back":"totality, entirety"});
b.push({"front":"inférieur","back":"inferior"});
b.push({"front":"un équivalent","back":"equivalent"});
b.push({"front":"le revers","back":"back, reverse, setback"});
b.push({"front":"le supplément","back":"supplement, extra"});
b.push({"front":"imprimer","back":"to print, print out"});
b.push({"front":"intimider","back":"to intimidate"});
b.push({"front":"attentif","back":"attentive, scrupulous, careful"});
b.push({"front":"la crédibilité","back":"credibility"});
b.push({"front":"improbable","back":"unlikely, improbable"});
b.push({"front":"recruter","back":"to recruit"});
b.push({"front":"parallèle","back":"parallel, similar"});
b.push({"front":"une aspiration","back":"aspiration"});
b.push({"front":"le prometteur","back":"promising"});
b.push({"front":"la milice","back":"militia"});
b.push({"front":"la façade","back":"front, façade"});
b.push({"front":"une instruction","back":"instruction, direction"});
b.push({"front":"publiquement","back":"publicly"});
b.push({"front":"un hymne, une hymne","back":"hymn, anthem"});
b.push({"front":"employer","back":"to use, employ"});
b.push({"front":"strict","back":"strict, absolute"});
b.push({"front":"la clause","back":"clause"});
b.push({"front":"interdire","back":"to forbid, prohibit, ban"});
b.push({"front":"exclure","back":"to exclude"});
b.push({"front":"éventuellement","back":"possibly"});
b.push({"front":"antique","back":"antique, ancient"});
b.push({"front":"confondre","back":"to mix up, confuse"});
b.push({"front":"un handicap","back":"handicap"});
b.push({"front":"la famine","back":"famine"});
b.push({"front":"le barreau","back":"bar"});
b.push({"front":"interpréter","back":"to interpret"});
b.push({"front":"le danois","back":"Danish, Dane"});
b.push({"front":"la concession","back":"concession"});
b.push({"front":"une équation","back":"equation"});
b.push({"front":"le golfe","back":"gulf"});
b.push({"front":"rassurant","back":"reassuring, comforting"});
b.push({"front":"caresser","back":"to fondle, caress"});
b.push({"front":"la légion","back":"legion"});
b.push({"front":"désirer","back":"to desire"});
b.push({"front":"le fonctionnement","back":"operation, functioning"});
b.push({"front":"diffuser","back":"to diffuse, broadcast"});
b.push({"front":"concevoir","back":"to conceive"});
b.push({"front":"redire","back":"to say again, repeat"});
b.push({"front":"le sursis","back":"reprieve, deferment"});
b.push({"front":"le monument","back":"monument"});
b.push({"front":"un observateur","back":"observer, observant"});
b.push({"front":"un industriel","back":"industrial"});
b.push({"front":"dissimuler","back":"to conceal, hide"});
b.push({"front":"le préliminaire","back":"preliminary, introductory"});
b.push({"front":"inspirer","back":"to inspire"});
b.push({"front":"précipiter","back":"to quicken, hasten, precipitate"});
b.push({"front":"pencher","back":"to lean, tilt"});
b.push({"front":"évoluer","back":"to evolve"});
b.push({"front":"contrarier","back":"to annoy, bother, thwart"});
b.push({"front":"la propagande","back":"propaganda"});
b.push({"front":"la crête","back":"crest, top, ridge"});
b.push({"front":"une expertise","back":"expertise"});
b.push({"front":"le flot","back":"floodtide, stream of, flood of"});
b.push({"front":"clarifier","back":"to clarify"});
b.push({"front":"la facilité","back":"easiness, ease, aptitude"});
b.push({"front":"le tarif","back":"price, rate, fare, tariff"});
b.push({"front":"tailler","back":"to cut, carve, engrave, sharpen, trim"});
b.push({"front":"la traversée","back":"crossing"});
b.push({"front":"le rival","back":"rival"});
b.push({"front":"compenser","back":"to compensate for, make up for"});
b.push({"front":"le partenariat","back":"partnership"});
b.push({"front":"appartenir","back":"to belong"});
b.push({"front":"le dilemme","back":"dilemma"});
b.push({"front":"remédier","back":"to cure, remedy, put right"});
b.push({"front":"traditionnel","back":"traditional"});
b.push({"front":"subit","back":"sudden"});
b.push({"front":"apaiser","back":"to calm, appease, calm down"});
b.push({"front":"une offensive","back":"offensive, offence"});
b.push({"front":"la conquête","back":"conquest"});
b.push({"front":"prédire","back":"to predict"});
b.push({"front":"proprement","back":"cleanly, neatly, properly"});
b.push({"front":"limiter","back":"to limit"});
b.push({"front":"droguer","back":"to drug, take drugs"});
b.push({"front":"le fabricant, la fabricant","back":"manufacturer"});
b.push({"front":"questionner","back":"to question"});
b.push({"front":"barbare","back":"barbaric; barbarian"});
b.push({"front":"combler","back":"to fill, fill in, fulfill"});
b.push({"front":"un apprentissage","back":"learning, apprenticeship"});
b.push({"front":"le vêtement","back":"garment, item or article of clothing"});
b.push({"front":"fermement","back":"firmly"});
b.push({"front":"définitif","back":"definitive, final"});
b.push({"front":"externe","back":"external, outer"});
b.push({"front":"la succession","back":"succession"});
b.push({"front":"décharger","back":"to unload"});
b.push({"front":"essuyer","back":"to wipe, dry, mop, dust"});
b.push({"front":"canadien","back":"Canadian"});
b.push({"front":"décent","back":"decent, proper"});
b.push({"front":"une admiration","back":"admiration"});
b.push({"front":"le stupéfiant","back":"drug, narcotic; stunning, astounding"});
b.push({"front":"soigneusement","back":"tidily, neatly, carefully"});
b.push({"front":"une ampleur","back":"extent, scope, range"});
b.push({"front":"la tolérance","back":"tolerance"});
b.push({"front":"le yen","back":"yen"});
b.push({"front":"copier","back":"to copy, reproduce"});
b.push({"front":"la probabilité","back":"probability, likelihood"});
b.push({"front":"détecter","back":"to detect"});
b.push({"front":"préoccuper","back":"to worry, preoccupy"});
b.push({"front":"le bagage","back":"luggage, baggage"});
b.push({"front":"un enjeu","back":"stake"});
b.push({"front":"regrettable","back":"unfortunate, regrettable"});
b.push({"front":"blindé","back":"armoured"});
b.push({"front":"la croyance","back":"belief"});
b.push({"front":"concret","back":"concrete"});
b.push({"front":"essentiellement","back":"essentially"});
b.push({"front":"le rejet","back":"rejection"});
b.push({"front":"la rubrique","back":"column, heading, rubric"});
b.push({"front":"agrandir","back":"to enlarge, extend"});
b.push({"front":"ouvertement","back":"openly, overtly"});
b.push({"front":"un islam","back":"Islam"});
b.push({"front":"le renvoi","back":"dismissal, expulsion, suspension, cross-reference"});
b.push({"front":"la prospérité","back":"prosperity"});
b.push({"front":"perturber","back":"to disrupt, disturb"});
b.push({"front":"optique","back":"optical, optic, perspective"});
b.push({"front":"la frustration","back":"frustration"});
b.push({"front":"un exploit","back":"exploit"});
b.push({"front":"la rédaction","back":"writing, composition"});
b.push({"front":"le sonore","back":"sound, resonant, sonorous, voiced"});
b.push({"front":"le souverain","back":"sovereign, supreme ruler, monarch"});
b.push({"front":"inclure","back":"to include"});
b.push({"front":"etc","back":"etc., et cetera"});
b.push({"front":"résumer","back":"to summarize, sum up"});
b.push({"front":"réconcilier","back":"to reconcile"});
b.push({"front":"la perturbation","back":"disruption, disturbance"});
b.push({"front":"brusquement","back":"abruptly, suddenly"});
b.push({"front":"un inconvénient","back":"snag, drawback, disadvantage, inconvenience"});
b.push({"front":"une agriculture","back":"agriculture"});
b.push({"front":"la restauration","back":"restoration; catering"});
b.push({"front":"une amélioration","back":"improvement"});
b.push({"front":"le rétablissement","back":"restoring, re-establishment, recovery"});
b.push({"front":"le titulaire, la titulaire","back":"holder, with tenure, occupant"});
b.push({"front":"une interruption","back":"interruption, break"});
b.push({"front":"le manœuvre, la manœuvre","back":"manoeuvre"});
b.push({"front":"le souterrain","back":"underground, underground passage"});
b.push({"front":"geler","back":"to freeze, ice over, suspend"});
b.push({"front":"le réflexe","back":"reflex"});
b.push({"front":"la rigueur","back":"harshness, severity, rigidness, rigor strictness"});
b.push({"front":"une hiérarchie","back":"hierarchy"});
b.push({"front":"hormis","back":"save, but"});
b.push({"front":"restaurer","back":"to restore, feed"});
b.push({"front":"redonner","back":"to give back, return, give more"});
b.push({"front":"la courbe","back":"curve, curved"});
b.push({"front":"remporter","back":"to take away, win"});
b.push({"front":"retomber","back":"to fall again, fall down again"});
b.push({"front":"le comédien","back":"comedian, comedy"});
b.push({"front":"correspondre","back":"to correspond"});
b.push({"front":"la reproduction","back":"reproduction"});
b.push({"front":"déguiser","back":"to disguise"});
b.push({"front":"le vocabulaire","back":"vocabulary"});
b.push({"front":"flotter","back":"to float, hang, stream"});
b.push({"front":"comparaître","back":"to appear"});
b.push({"front":"une estimation","back":"appraisal, valuation, assessment, estimate"});
b.push({"front":"la douane","back":"customs, duty"});
b.push({"front":"souple","back":"supple, agile, soft, floppy, flexible"});
b.push({"front":"la manipulation","back":"handling, manipulation"});
b.push({"front":"tolérer","back":"to tolerate, access, put up, bear, endure"});
b.push({"front":"constater","back":"to note, notice; to establish, certify"});
b.push({"front":"un analyste, une analyste","back":"analyst"});
b.push({"front":"grandissant","back":"growing, increasing"});
b.push({"front":"la contrainte","back":"constraint"});
b.push({"front":"médiocre","back":"mediocre, second-rate"});
b.push({"front":"la dérive","back":"drift"});
b.push({"front":"automatiquement","back":"automatically"});
b.push({"front":"le philosophe, la philosophe","back":"philosopher"});
b.push({"front":"le diplomate, la diplomate","back":"diplomat, diplomatic"});
b.push({"front":"la pétition","back":"petition"});
b.push({"front":"le conservateur","back":"conservative"});
b.push({"front":"suspendre","back":"to suspend, postpone"});
b.push({"front":"le radical","back":"radical"});
b.push({"front":"improviser","back":"to improvise"});
b.push({"front":"organique","back":"organic"});
b.push({"front":"le recrutement","back":"recruiting, recruitment"});
b.push({"front":"une hésitation","back":"hesitation"});
b.push({"front":"le défenseur, la défenseur","back":"defender"});
b.push({"front":"peser","back":"to weigh"});
b.push({"front":"africain","back":"African"});
b.push({"front":"le tourisme","back":"tourism, sightseeing"});
b.push({"front":"écrouler","back":"to collapse, tumble"});
b.push({"front":"le démocrate, la démocrate","back":"democrat, democratic"});
b.push({"front":"associer","back":"to associate"});
b.push({"front":"le soixante","back":"sixty"});
b.push({"front":"compétent","back":"competent"});
b.push({"front":"une intensité","back":"intensity"});
b.push({"front":"la sincérité","back":"sincerity"});
b.push({"front":"artificiel","back":"artificial"});
b.push({"front":"le symptôme","back":"symptom"});
b.push({"front":"opérationnel","back":"operational, operating"});
b.push({"front":"démontrer","back":"to demonstrate"});
b.push({"front":"la nomination","back":"appointment, nomination"});
b.push({"front":"flagrant","back":"blatant, glaring"});
b.push({"front":"le portugais","back":"Portuguese"});
b.push({"front":"grossir","back":"to get larger"});
b.push({"front":"le magistrat","back":"magistrate, judge"});
b.push({"front":"rédiger","back":"to write, draw up"});
b.push({"front":"recommander","back":"to recommend"});
b.push({"front":"le détachement","back":"detachment"});
b.push({"front":"la formalité","back":"formality"});
b.push({"front":"acquérir","back":"to acquire"});
b.push({"front":"le dixième, la dixième","back":"tenth"});
b.push({"front":"le parquet","back":"parquet floor, hardwood floor, prosecutor’s office"});
b.push({"front":"composer","back":"to compose, dial"});
b.push({"front":"olympique","back":"Olympic"});
b.push({"front":"la compétence","back":"competence"});
b.push({"front":"applaudir","back":"to clap, applaud"});
b.push({"front":"le délinquant","back":"delinquent, offender"});
b.push({"front":"le litre, la litre","back":"litre"});
b.push({"front":"le légume, la légume","back":"vegetable"});
b.push({"front":"le publicitaire, la publicitaire","back":"advertising, promotional"});
b.push({"front":"la reconstruction","back":"reconstruction"});
b.push({"front":"exécutif","back":"executive"});
b.push({"front":"le prélèvement","back":"imposition, levying, withdrawal, removal, deduction"});
b.push({"front":"le tirage","back":"drawing, circulation, run"});
b.push({"front":"européen","back":"European"});
b.push({"front":"le bourgeois","back":"middle class"});
b.push({"front":"le sondage","back":"poll"});
b.push({"front":"stratégique","back":"strategic"});
b.push({"front":"oser","back":"to dare"});
b.push({"front":"agiter","back":"to shake, disturb"});
b.push({"front":"favorable","back":"favorable"});
b.push({"front":"alerter","back":"to alert, inform, warn"});
b.push({"front":"la criminalité","back":"crime"});
b.push({"front":"insignifiant","back":"insignificant, unimportant"});
b.push({"front":"brut","back":"raw, crude"});
b.push({"front":"une actualité","back":"current events, news"});
b.push({"front":"tantôt","back":"this afternoon, sometimes"});
b.push({"front":"recueillir","back":"to collect, gather"});
b.push({"front":"le dictionnaire","back":"dictionary"});
b.push({"front":"le remplacement","back":"replacement, standing in"});
b.push({"front":"culturel","back":"cultural"});
b.push({"front":"le chercheur","back":"researcher"});
b.push({"front":"la défaillance","back":"fault, failure, breakdown, blackout, weakness"});
b.push({"front":"inverser","back":"to reverse, invert"});
b.push({"front":"manifester","back":"to show, demonstrate, display"});
b.push({"front":"cultiver","back":"to cultivate, grow"});
b.push({"front":"la stabilité","back":"stability"});
b.push({"front":"confronter","back":"to confront"});
b.push({"front":"un huitième, une huitième","back":"eighth"});
b.push({"front":"repenser","back":"to rethink"});
b.push({"front":"décevant","back":"disappointing"});
b.push({"front":"un effondrement","back":"collapse, caving-in, falling-in, breaking-down"});
b.push({"front":"signifier","back":"to mean"});
b.push({"front":"relance","back":"boost, reminder, recovery"});
b.push({"front":"balayer","back":"to sweep up, sweep out"});
b.push({"front":"la compensation","back":"compensation, clearing"});
b.push({"front":"la confrontation","back":"confrontation"});
b.push({"front":"gonfler","back":"to inflate, blow up, swell"});
b.push({"front":"le gain","back":"gain"});
b.push({"front":"le partiel","back":"partial"});
b.push({"front":"la clarté","back":"lightness, brightness clearness, clarity"});
b.push({"front":"relativement","back":"relatively"});
b.push({"front":"convertir","back":"to convert"});
b.push({"front":"poétique","back":"poetic, poetical, poetics"});
b.push({"front":"compliquer","back":"to complicate"});
b.push({"front":"une expansion","back":"expansion"});
b.push({"front":"continu","back":"continuous"});
b.push({"front":"le résident","back":"foreign national, foreign resident"});
b.push({"front":"planer","back":"to glide, soar"});
b.push({"front":"le routier","back":"road, long-distance lorry or truck driver"});
b.push({"front":"hanter","back":"to haunt"});
b.push({"front":"une introduction","back":"introduction"});
b.push({"front":"diminuer","back":"to diminish, decrease"});
b.push({"front":"le sceptique, la sceptique","back":"sceptical, sceptic"});
b.push({"front":"rouvrir","back":"to reopen"});
b.push({"front":"la vigueur","back":"vigor"});
b.push({"front":"le paragraphe","back":"paragraph"});
b.push({"front":"respectueux","back":"respectful"});
b.push({"front":"infliger","back":"to inflict"});
b.push({"front":"apte","back":"capable"});
b.push({"front":"une extension","back":"extension, stretching, expansion"});
b.push({"front":"maternel","back":"motherly, maternal"});
b.push({"front":"le bénévole, la bénévole","back":"volunteer, voluntary, unpaid"});
b.push({"front":"bénéfique","back":"beneficial"});
b.push({"front":"notamment","back":"notably"});
b.push({"front":"constant","back":"constant"});
b.push({"front":"littéraire","back":"literary"});
b.push({"front":"la tribune","back":"platform, forum, gallery"});
b.push({"front":"sévèrement","back":"severely, harshly"});
b.push({"front":"troublant","back":"disturbing"});
b.push({"front":"brièvement","back":"briefly"});
b.push({"front":"le bombardement","back":"bombing, shelling"});
b.push({"front":"la récupération","back":"recovery, retrieval, salvage"});
b.push({"front":"le classement","back":"classification, ranking"});
b.push({"front":"le résistant","back":"robust, sturdy, resistance fighter"});
b.push({"front":"le remboursement","back":"reimbursement"});
b.push({"front":"promouvoir","back":"to promote"});
b.push({"front":"un impôt","back":"tax"});
b.push({"front":"contredire","back":"to contradict"});
b.push({"front":"longuement","back":"at length"});
b.push({"front":"le forum","back":"forum, newsgroup"});
b.push({"front":"le successeur","back":"successor"});
b.push({"front":"le placement","back":"investment, placing"});
b.push({"front":"brutalement","back":"brutally"});
b.push({"front":"gouverner","back":"to govern, rule, steer, helm"});
b.push({"front":"sanglant","back":"bloody, cruel, covered in blood"});
b.push({"front":"calculer","back":"to calculate"});
b.push({"front":"la distinction","back":"distinction"});
b.push({"front":"une exploration","back":"exploration, investigation, examination"});
b.push({"front":"originaire","back":"original, first, native to"});
b.push({"front":"aspirer","back":"to breathe in, inhale, aspire to"});
b.push({"front":"le blocage","back":"block"});
b.push({"front":"superficiel","back":"superficial, shallow"});
b.push({"front":"la vieillesse","back":"old age"});
b.push({"front":"le timbre","back":"to stamp"});
b.push({"front":"injecter","back":"to inject"});
b.push({"front":"le croissant","back":"growing, crescent, crescent-shape"});
b.push({"front":"pénal","back":"penal"});
b.push({"front":"le concurrent","back":"competitor, rival"});
b.push({"front":"prioritaire","back":"priority, having priority, having right of way"});
b.push({"front":"la taxe","back":"tax"});
b.push({"front":"autoritaire","back":"authoritarian"});
b.push({"front":"exiger","back":"to require, demand"});
b.push({"front":"la trame","back":"weft, framework; tram"});
b.push({"front":"exciter","back":"to arouse, waken, excite, turn on"});
b.push({"front":"la discrimination","back":"discrimination"});
b.push({"front":"refermer","back":"to close again, shut again, close up"});
b.push({"front":"le pilier","back":"pillar"});
b.push({"front":"miser","back":"to bet, stake"});
b.push({"front":"approuver","back":"to approve"});
b.push({"front":"distant","back":"far-off, distant, faraway"});
b.push({"front":"alimenter","back":"to feed, supply"});
b.push({"front":"user","back":"to wear out, wear away, use up"});
b.push({"front":"intellectuel","back":"intellectual"});
b.push({"front":"une insuffisance","back":"inadequacy, insufficiency"});
b.push({"front":"liquider","back":"to liquidate, sell off, clear"});
b.push({"front":"collaborer","back":"to collaborate, contribute"});
b.push({"front":"stabiliser","back":"to stabilize"});
b.push({"front":"un administrateur","back":"administrator"});
b.push({"front":"le raisonnement","back":"reasoning"});
b.push({"front":"un ouvrage","back":"work"});
b.push({"front":"le massif","back":"massive"});
b.push({"front":"la félicitation","back":"congratulation"});
b.push({"front":"la nouveauté","back":"novelty, new release"});
b.push({"front":"débuter","back":"to start"});
b.push({"front":"une uni","back":"united"});
b.push({"front":"aggraver","back":"to worsen, aggravate"});
b.push({"front":"excessif","back":"excessive, inordinate"});
b.push({"front":"exigeant","back":"demanding, difficult"});
b.push({"front":"éprouver","back":"to feel, experience"});
b.push({"front":"la décennie","back":"decade"});
b.push({"front":"émettre","back":"to emit, issue"});
b.push({"front":"classer","back":"to classify, file, grade, rate"});
b.push({"front":"ajuster","back":"to adjust, alter, aim, aim at"});
b.push({"front":"une incapacité","back":"incompetence, incapability"});
b.push({"front":"considérable","back":"considerable, significant"});
b.push({"front":"le racisme","back":"racism"});
b.push({"front":"relancer","back":"to throw back, restart, relaunch"});
b.push({"front":"politiquement","back":"politically, diplomatically"});
b.push({"front":"une annexe","back":"annex, appendix, related issue"});
b.push({"front":"un instituteur","back":"school teacher"});
b.push({"front":"une affectation","back":"appointment, allocation; show, pretence"});
b.push({"front":"une entité","back":"entity"});
b.push({"front":"songer","back":"to dream"});
b.push({"front":"un éloge","back":"praise"});
b.push({"front":"le meuble","back":"piece of furniture"});
b.push({"front":"la solidarité","back":"solidarity"});
b.push({"front":"une espérance","back":"hope"});
b.push({"front":"le délégué","back":"delegate"});
b.push({"front":"la réforme","back":"reform"});
b.push({"front":"prolonger","back":"to prolong, extend"});
b.push({"front":"contrer","back":"to counter"});
b.push({"front":"protester","back":"to protest"});
b.push({"front":"prochainement","back":"shortly, soon"});
b.push({"front":"symbolique","back":"symbolic"});
b.push({"front":"une élimination","back":"elimination"});
b.push({"front":"enrichir","back":"to expand, enrich, make somebody rich"});
b.push({"front":"primitif","back":"primitive"});
b.push({"front":"un uranium","back":"uranium"});
b.push({"front":"la sérénité","back":"serenity, peacefulness"});
b.push({"front":"démocratique","back":"democratic"});
b.push({"front":"ordonner","back":"to ordain, organize, order"});
b.push({"front":"le retraité","back":"retired"});
b.push({"front":"la préoccupation","back":"worry, concern"});
b.push({"front":"pharmaceutique","back":"pharmaceutical"});
b.push({"front":"redresser","back":"to straighten, set right, redress, turn around"});
b.push({"front":"la progression","back":"progression"});
b.push({"front":"progresser","back":"to progress"});
b.push({"front":"contribuer","back":"to contribute"});
b.push({"front":"choquer","back":"to shock, offend, shake, disturb"});
b.push({"front":"la consigne","back":"deposit, orders, detention"});
b.push({"front":"le dictateur","back":"dictator"});
b.push({"front":"une extrémité","back":"end, extremity"});
b.push({"front":"expérimental","back":"experimental"});
b.push({"front":"fréquent","back":"frequent"});
b.push({"front":"précoce","back":"early, precocious"});
b.push({"front":"compléter","back":"to complete"});
b.push({"front":"régional","back":"regional"});
b.push({"front":"capter","back":"to pick up, capture, tap"});
b.push({"front":"le communisme","back":"communism"});
b.push({"front":"récompenser","back":"to reward, recompense"});
b.push({"front":"la pollution","back":"pollution"});
b.push({"front":"évoquer","back":"to recall, evoke"});
b.push({"front":"une hostilité","back":"hostility, hostilities"});
b.push({"front":"énergétique","back":"energic, vigorous"});
b.push({"front":"le licenciement","back":"dismissal, sacking"});
b.push({"front":"prématuré","back":"premature"});
b.push({"front":"mécontent","back":"discontented, dissatisfied, displeased"});
b.push({"front":"décisif","back":"decisive"});
b.push({"front":"la circonstance","back":"circumstance"});
b.push({"front":"une inondation","back":"flood, deluge"});
b.push({"front":"le déploiement","back":"deployment, spreading, unfurling, display"});
b.push({"front":"le millénaire","back":"millennium, thousand-year- old"});
b.push({"front":"le maintien","back":"holding, maintaining"});
b.push({"front":"une interrogation","back":"question, interviewing, interrogation, questioning, test"});
b.push({"front":"virtuel","back":"virtual, potential"});
b.push({"front":"une hépatite","back":"hepatitis"});
b.push({"front":"universel","back":"universal"});
b.push({"front":"afficher","back":"to display"});
b.push({"front":"la variété","back":"variety"});
b.push({"front":"le décret","back":"decree"});
b.push({"front":"un optimisme","back":"optimism"});
b.push({"front":"rentable","back":"profitable"});
b.push({"front":"un abbé","back":"abbot, priest"});
b.push({"front":"bousculer","back":"to knock over, knock into"});
b.push({"front":"la prestation","back":"benefit"});
b.push({"front":"une éventualité","back":"eventuality, possibility"});
b.push({"front":"le spectateur","back":"member of the audience, spectator, onlooker"});
b.push({"front":"le terrien","back":"earthling; landowner, countryman"});
b.push({"front":"un investisseur","back":"investor"});
b.push({"front":"génétiquement","back":"genetically"});
b.push({"front":"la sphère","back":"sphere"});
b.push({"front":"renouveler","back":"to renew"});
b.push({"front":"la rapidité","back":"speed, quickness"});
b.push({"front":"élémentaire","back":"elementary, rudimentary, basic"});
b.push({"front":"élargir","back":"to widen, expand"});
b.push({"front":"comparable","back":"comparable"});
b.push({"front":"communautaire","back":"community, communal"});
b.push({"front":"éveiller","back":"to arouse, stimulate, awaken"});
b.push({"front":"la réconciliation","back":"reconciliation"});
b.push({"front":"rationnel","back":"rational"});
b.push({"front":"le fondement","back":"foundation"});
b.push({"front":"le capitalisme","back":"capitalism"});
b.push({"front":"un ancêtre, une ancêtre","back":"ancestor, forerunner"});
b.push({"front":"durable","back":"durable, long-lasting"});
b.push({"front":"la domination","back":"domination, dominion, rule"});
b.push({"front":"la révision","back":"review, revision, overhaul"});
b.push({"front":"indifférent","back":"indifferent, unconcerned, unimportant"});
b.push({"front":"la publication","back":"publication"});
b.push({"front":"vigilant","back":"vigilant, watchful"});
b.push({"front":"un habitant","back":"inhabitant"});
b.push({"front":"la censure","back":"censorship"});
b.push({"front":"le transparent","back":"transparent, see-through, evident"});
b.push({"front":"la mœurs","back":"morals, customs, habits, manners, ways"});
b.push({"front":"absorber","back":"to absorb, remove, take up, take over"});
b.push({"front":"maritime","back":"maritime"});
b.push({"front":"naval","back":"naval"});
b.push({"front":"une envergure","back":"wingspan, breadth, scope"});
b.push({"front":"la simplicité","back":"simplicity, straightforwardness"});
b.push({"front":"brouiller","back":"to mix-up, confuse, scramble"});
b.push({"front":"le dépens","back":"expense"});
b.push({"front":"un approvisionnement","back":"supply, supplies, stock, supplying, stocking"});
b.push({"front":"veuf","back":"surviving spouse"});
b.push({"front":"vocal","back":"vocal"});
b.push({"front":"lourdement","back":"heavily"});
b.push({"front":"belge","back":"Belgian"});
b.push({"front":"rayer","back":"to scratch, streak, stripe; to erase, strike out"});
b.push({"front":"satisfaisant","back":"satisfactory, satisfying"});
b.push({"front":"le déclin","back":"decline, deterioration"});
b.push({"front":"humanitaire","back":"humanitarian"});
b.push({"front":"fatiguer","back":"to tire, get tired"});
b.push({"front":"invoquer","back":"to call upon"});
b.push({"front":"véritablement","back":"truly, really"});
b.push({"front":"coûteux","back":"expensive, costly"});
b.push({"front":"une aptitude","back":"ability"});
b.push({"front":"la délégation","back":"delegation"});
b.push({"front":"la minorité","back":"minority"});
b.push({"front":"le promoteur","back":"promoter, instigator, developer"});
b.push({"front":"désigner","back":"to designate"});
b.push({"front":"le patrimoine","back":"heritage, assets"});
b.push({"front":"le loisir","back":"leisure"});
b.push({"front":"imminent","back":"imminent, impending"});
b.push({"front":"le combustible","back":"fuel, combustible"});
b.push({"front":"ménager","back":"to handle, arrange; domestic"});
b.push({"front":"nettement","back":"clearly, distinctly"});
b.push({"front":"motiver","back":"to justify, account for, motivate"});
b.push({"front":"hériter","back":"to inherit"});
b.push({"front":"un accessoire","back":"accessory"});
b.push({"front":"programmer","back":"to program, schedule"});
b.push({"front":"élire","back":"to elect"});
b.push({"front":"un intervalle","back":"space, distance, interval"});
b.push({"front":"expédier","back":"to send, dispatch"});
b.push({"front":"viable","back":"viable, workable"});
b.push({"front":"réputé","back":"famous, renowned"});
b.push({"front":"exagérer","back":"to exaggerate, overdo"});
b.push({"front":"conforme","back":"conform"});
b.push({"front":"la programmation","back":"programming"});
b.push({"front":"reconduire","back":"to renew, drive back"});
b.push({"front":"accessible","back":"accessible, approachable"});
b.push({"front":"le passif","back":"passive, liabilities"});
b.push({"front":"une intégration","back":"integration"});
b.push({"front":"anticiper","back":"to anticipate, foresee, look or think ahead"});
b.push({"front":"estimer","back":"to estimate; to consider, deem"});
b.push({"front":"la rénovation","back":"renovation, restoration"});
b.push({"front":"prélever","back":"to impose, levy, withdraw, remove"});
b.push({"front":"encourageant","back":"encouraging"});
b.push({"front":"dépendre","back":"to depend"});
b.push({"front":"corrompre","back":"to corrupt, bribe"});
b.push({"front":"bombarder","back":"to bomb"});
b.push({"front":"conformément","back":"in accordance"});
b.push({"front":"initial","back":"initial"});
b.push({"front":"le déchet","back":"scrap, waste, trash, garbage"});
b.push({"front":"la rhétorique","back":"rhetorical, rhetoric"});
b.push({"front":"le génocide","back":"genocide"});
b.push({"front":"climatique","back":"climatic"});
b.push({"front":"consommer","back":"to eat, consume, drink, use, consummate"});
b.push({"front":"un encouragement","back":"encouragement"});
b.push({"front":"la provocation","back":"provocation"});
b.push({"front":"reconstituer","back":"to reconstitute, restore, reconstruct"});
b.push({"front":"incompréhensible","back":"incomprehensible"});
b.push({"front":"attribuer","back":"to award, grant, attribute"});
b.push({"front":"le biais","back":"way, device; bias"});
b.push({"front":"la dictature","back":"dictatorship"});
b.push({"front":"catastrophique","back":"catastrophic, disastrous"});
b.push({"front":"chuter","back":"to fall"});
b.push({"front":"le socialiste, la socialiste","back":"socialist"});
b.push({"front":"prescrire","back":"to order, command, prescribe, stipulate"});
b.push({"front":"abriter","back":"to shelter, shade"});
b.push({"front":"sanitaire","back":"health, sanitary, medical"});
b.push({"front":"la diplomatie","back":"diplomacy"});
b.push({"front":"exclusivement","back":"exclusively, solely"});
b.push({"front":"le suspens","back":"suspension, abeyance"});
b.push({"front":"la norme","back":"norm, standard"});
b.push({"front":"un aval","back":"downstream, downhill"});
b.push({"front":"le graphique, la graphique","back":"graph, graphic"});
b.push({"front":"une indifférence","back":"indifference"});
b.push({"front":"intolérable","back":"intolerable"});
b.push({"front":"médiatique","back":"media"});
b.push({"front":"propice","back":"favorable, auspicious propitious"});
b.push({"front":"la portion","back":"portion, share"});
b.push({"front":"une interface","back":"interface"});
b.push({"front":"purger","back":"to purge, bleed, drain"});
b.push({"front":"sombrer","back":"to darken; to sink, lapse"});
b.push({"front":"expérimenter","back":"to experiment"});
b.push({"front":"la fixation","back":"fixation, fixing"});
b.push({"front":"le commerçant","back":"shopkeeper, merchant, commercial"});
b.push({"front":"théoriquement","back":"theoretically"});
b.push({"front":"le quota","back":"quota"});
b.push({"front":"le composant","back":"component, constituent"});
b.push({"front":"la mortalité","back":"mortality, death rate"});
b.push({"front":"le déficit","back":"deficit"});
b.push({"front":"la sécheresse","back":"dryness, drought"});
b.push({"front":"le palier","back":"landing, level, flat"});
b.push({"front":"la cinquantaine","back":"about fifty"});
b.push({"front":"la protestation","back":"protest, protestation"});
b.push({"front":"la nationalité","back":"nationality"});
b.push({"front":"un animateur","back":"animator, host"});
b.push({"front":"relire","back":"to reread, proofread"});
b.push({"front":"appliqué","back":"assiduous, industrious, careful"});
b.push({"front":"soucieux","back":"concerned, worried"});
b.push({"front":"heurter","back":"to strike, hit, collide"});
b.push({"front":"convenir","back":"to agree, be suitable"});
b.push({"front":"stimuler","back":"to stimulate"});
b.push({"front":"issu","back":"descended from"});
b.push({"front":"dicter","back":"to dictate, lay down"});
b.push({"front":"dépendant","back":"answerable, responsible, dependent"});
b.push({"front":"défini","back":"definite"});
b.push({"front":"touristique","back":"holiday, tourist"});
b.push({"front":"ficher","back":"to file; to make fun of, not care, not give a damn"});
b.push({"front":"la coalition","back":"coalition"});
b.push({"front":"déduire","back":"to deduct, deduce, infer, figure out"});
b.push({"front":"occidental","back":"western"});
b.push({"front":"spontané","back":"spontaneous"});
b.push({"front":"cerner","back":"to surround, encircle, delimit"});
b.push({"front":"disperser","back":"to scatter, spread, disperse"});
b.push({"front":"fondamentalement","back":"basically, fundamentally, inherently"});
b.push({"front":"le pessimiste, la pessimiste","back":"pessimistic; pessimist"});
b.push({"front":"entamer","back":"to start"});
b.push({"front":"périr","back":"to perish"});
b.push({"front":"cohérent","back":"coherent"});
b.push({"front":"urbain","back":"urban"});
b.push({"front":"le rail","back":"rail, track"});
b.push({"front":"la mentalité","back":"mentality"});
b.push({"front":"un oral","back":"oral"});
b.push({"front":"rigide","back":"rigid, stiff"});
b.push({"front":"conjugal","back":"conjugal, married"});
b.push({"front":"une avalanche","back":"avalanche"});
b.push({"front":"le négociateur","back":"negotiator"});
b.push({"front":"un égyptien","back":"Egyptian"});
b.push({"front":"la mathématique","back":"mathematical; mathematics"});
b.push({"front":"formel","back":"formal, definite"});
b.push({"front":"dominant","back":"dominant, prevailing"});
b.push({"front":"troubler","back":"to disturb, disrupt, cloud"});
b.push({"front":"qualifier","back":"to qualify"});
b.push({"front":"la justesse","back":"accuracy, precision"});
b.push({"front":"un attachement","back":"attachment, affection"});
b.push({"front":"transit","back":"transit"});
b.push({"front":"un hebdomadaire","back":"weekly"});
b.push({"front":"freiner","back":"to brake, slow down"});
b.push({"front":"épuiser","back":"to exhaust, tire out, wear out, use up"});
b.push({"front":"le repli","back":"bend, twist, wrinkle, fold, fallback"});
b.push({"front":"une acquisition","back":"acquisition, acquire, purchase"});
b.push({"front":"la spéculation","back":"speculation"});
b.push({"front":"incertain","back":"uncertain, unsure"});
b.push({"front":"contester","back":"to contest, question"});
b.push({"front":"le démarrage","back":"start, moving off"});
b.push({"front":"inciter","back":"to incite, encourage"});
b.push({"front":"mutuel","back":"mutual"});
b.push({"front":"une indication","back":"indication"});
b.push({"front":"souligner","back":"to underline, stress"});
b.push({"front":"le gendarme, la gendarme","back":"policeman"});
b.push({"front":"masquer","back":"to mask, conceal, put on a mask"});
b.push({"front":"étonner","back":"to astonish, amaze"});
b.push({"front":"le débit","back":"debit, turnover, delivery, rate"});
b.push({"front":"une acceptation","back":"acceptance"});
b.push({"front":"étaler","back":"to spread, display, apply"});
b.push({"front":"un impératif","back":"need, necessity, urgent, imperative"});
b.push({"front":"commenter","back":"to comment"});
b.push({"front":"agricole","back":"agricultural, farming"});
b.push({"front":"visée","back":"aim, design, sighting"});
b.push({"front":"administratif","back":"administrative"});
b.push({"front":"réfugier","back":"to take refuge"});
b.push({"front":"clore","back":"to close"});
b.push({"front":"un édifice","back":"building"});
b.push({"front":"ravir","back":"to delight, rob"});
b.push({"front":"le préjudice","back":"loss, harm, damage"});
b.push({"front":"la fraction","back":"fraction"});
b.push({"front":"le récepteur","back":"receiver, receiving"});
b.push({"front":"la répression","back":"repression, suppression, crack-down"});
b.push({"front":"la lunette","back":"telescope, glasses"});
b.push({"front":"une incertitude","back":"uncertainty"});
b.push({"front":"dérouler","back":"to unwind, enroll"});
b.push({"front":"technologique","back":"technological"});
b.push({"front":"abstenir","back":"to abstain, refrain"});
b.push({"front":"différencier","back":"to differentiate"});
b.push({"front":"enclin","back":"enclined, prone"});
b.push({"front":"la conversion","back":"conversion"});
b.push({"front":"le surplus","back":"surplus"});
b.push({"front":"le prédécesseur","back":"predecessor"});
b.push({"front":"basculer","back":"to topple, fall over, knock off"});
b.push({"front":"la méfiance","back":"distrust, mistrust, suspicion"});
b.push({"front":"significatif","back":"significative"});
b.push({"front":"autonome","back":"autonomous, independent"});
b.push({"front":"un organisateur","back":"organiser, organising"});
b.push({"front":"exclusif","back":"exclusive, sole"});
b.push({"front":"administrer","back":"to manage, run, administer; to give"});
b.push({"front":"insuffisant","back":"insufficient, inadequate"});
b.push({"front":"convoquer","back":"to call, summon"});
b.push({"front":"le serbe","back":"Serbian"});
b.push({"front":"soupçonner","back":"to suspect"});
b.push({"front":"bénéficier","back":"to benefit"});
b.push({"front":"une échéance","back":"expiration date, date of payment, deadline"});
b.push({"front":"le libéral","back":"liberal"});
b.push({"front":"aligner","back":"to lign up, align"});
b.push({"front":"la caractéristique","back":"characteristic"});
b.push({"front":"simultanément","back":"simultaneously"});
b.push({"front":"adéquat","back":"appropriate, suitable, adequate"});
b.push({"front":"armer","back":"to arm"});
b.push({"front":"la diversité","back":"diversity"});
b.push({"front":"recouvrir","back":"to cover, hide, conceal"});
b.push({"front":"déployer","back":"to deploy, open"});
b.push({"front":"décourager","back":"to discourage, dishearten, lose heart"});
b.push({"front":"allier","back":"to ally, match, unite"});
b.push({"front":"la coordination","back":"coordination"});
b.push({"front":"la précipitation","back":"haste, precipitation"});
b.push({"front":"projeter","back":"to plan, project, throw out"});
b.push({"front":"considérablement","back":"considerably, significantly, extensively"});
b.push({"front":"dépouiller","back":"to skin, strip away, deprive, analyze"});
b.push({"front":"notoire","back":"notorious, well-known"});
b.push({"front":"théorique","back":"theoretical"});
b.push({"front":"prestigieux","back":"prestigious"});
b.push({"front":"partiellement","back":"partly"});
b.push({"front":"élaborer","back":"to work out, develop"});
b.push({"front":"renier","back":"to disown, repudiate, go back on"});
b.push({"front":"postal","back":"postal, mail"});
b.push({"front":"insérer","back":"to insert"});
b.push({"front":"négliger","back":"to neglect"});
b.push({"front":"bouleverser","back":"to upset, distress, disturb, turn upside down"});
b.push({"front":"emprisonner","back":"to imprison, jail, put in jail, trap"});
b.push({"front":"propager","back":"to propagate, spread"});
b.push({"front":"abaisser","back":"to pull down, lower, reduce"});
b.push({"front":"le versement","back":"payment"});
b.push({"front":"présidentiel","back":"presidential"});
b.push({"front":"natal","back":"native, home"});
b.push({"front":"un affrontement","back":"clash, confrontation"});
b.push({"front":"le format","back":"format"});
b.push({"front":"opportun","back":"timely,"});
b.push({"front":"dissoudre","back":"to dissolve, disband, break up"});
b.push({"front":"la sanction","back":"sanction"});
b.push({"front":"un utilisateur","back":"user"});
b.push({"front":"le paradoxe","back":"paradox"});
b.push({"front":"un occupant","back":"occupant, occupier, occupying"});
b.push({"front":"radioactif","back":"radioactive"});
b.push({"front":"surgir","back":"to spring up"});
b.push({"front":"un éventail","back":"fan, range"});
b.push({"front":"avérer","back":"to prove to be, turn out"});
b.push({"front":"affaiblir","back":"to weaken"});
b.push({"front":"le bénéficiaire, la bénéficiaire","back":"beneficiary"});
b.push({"front":"appréhender","back":"to dread, apprehend"});
b.push({"front":"la contrepartie","back":"counterpart, opposite, alternative"});
b.push({"front":"la pénurie","back":"shortage"});
b.push({"front":"éminent","back":"eminent, distinguished"});
b.push({"front":"enchaîner","back":"to chain up, connect, string together"});
b.push({"front":"contaminer","back":"to contaminate, infect"});
b.push({"front":"le synonyme","back":"synonymous; synonym"});
b.push({"front":"préférer","back":"to prefer"});
b.push({"front":"déborder","back":"to overflow, boil over, go out, go over"});
b.push({"front":"la compression","back":"compression; cutback, reduction"});
b.push({"front":"aboutir","back":"to succeed, end up at"});
b.push({"front":"la charte","back":"charter"});
b.push({"front":"primordial","back":"primordial, basic, vital, primary"});
b.push({"front":"la ressource","back":"resource"});
b.push({"front":"la quinzaine","back":"about fifteen, two weeks"});
b.push({"front":"singulier","back":"unique, singular"});
b.push({"front":"couramment","back":"fluently, commonly"});
b.push({"front":"la vigilance","back":"vigilance, watchfulness"});
b.push({"front":"pourvoir","back":"to provide, equip, supply, furnish"});
b.push({"front":"générer","back":"to generate"});
b.push({"front":"une accélération","back":"acceleration"});
b.push({"front":"écouler","back":"to sell, run off, flow out"});
b.push({"front":"la borne","back":"milestone, boundary stone"});
b.push({"front":"le rapprochement","back":"bringing together, coming closer, parallel"});
b.push({"front":"baptiser","back":"to name, christen, baptize"});
b.push({"front":"bannir","back":"to banish, ban"});
b.push({"front":"vraisemblablement","back":"most probably"});
b.push({"front":"couronner","back":"to crown, award"});
b.push({"front":"peut-être","back":"perhaps, maybe"});
b.push({"front":"aujourd’hui","back":"today"});
b.push({"front":"concerner","back":"to concern"});
b.push({"front":"d’abord","back":"first of all"});
b.push({"front":"importer","back":"to import; to be important"});
b.push({"front":"constituer","back":"to constitute"});
b.push({"front":"lui-même","back":"himself"});
b.push({"front":"c’est-à-dire","back":"in other words"});
b.push({"front":"d’ailleurs","back":"moreover, besides, for that matter"});
b.push({"front":"d’après","back":"according to"});
b.push({"front":"d’accord","back":"okay, alright"});
b.push({"front":"demeurer","back":"to remain, live"});
b.push({"front":"quelqu’un","back":"somebody, someone"});
b.push({"front":"situer","back":"to situate, locate"});
b.push({"front":"figurer","back":"to represent, appear"});
b.push({"front":"le mai","back":"May"});
b.push({"front":"susciter","back":"to arouse, provoke"});
b.push({"front":"consister","back":"to consist"});
b.push({"front":"destiner","back":"to intend, be used"});
b.push({"front":"relatif","back":"relative"});
b.push({"front":"entreprendre","back":"to begin, start, undertake"});
b.push({"front":"au-delà","back":"beyond"});
b.push({"front":"parlementaire","back":"parliamentary; member of parliament"});
b.push({"front":"palestinien","back":"Palestinian"});
b.push({"front":"fondamental","back":"fundamental"});
b.push({"front":"une exigence","back":"demand, strictness"});
b.push({"front":"après-midi","back":"afternoon"});
b.push({"front":"vis-à-vis","back":"face to face, regarding"});
b.push({"front":"elle-même","back":"herself, itself"});
b.push({"front":"législatif","back":"legislative"});
b.push({"front":"favoriser","back":"to favor"});
b.push({"front":"précéder","back":"to precede"});
b.push({"front":"israélien","back":"Israeli"});
b.push({"front":"au-dessus","back":"above"});
b.push({"front":"d’autant","back":"since"});
b.push({"front":"entourer","back":"to surround"});
b.push({"front":"accroître","back":"to increase"});
b.push({"front":"moi-même","back":"myself"});
b.push({"front":"provenir","back":"to be from, come from"});
b.push({"front":"la modification","back":"modification"});
b.push({"front":"la prévision","back":"forecast, prediction, expectation"});
b.push({"front":"fiscal","back":"fiscal"});
b.push({"front":"une exportation","back":"export"});
b.push({"front":"percevoir","back":"to perceive"});
b.push({"front":"le consommateur","back":"consumer, customer"});
b.push({"front":"un abri","back":"shelter"});
b.push({"front":"baser","back":"to base"});
b.push({"front":"électoral","back":"electoral"});
b.push({"front":"porte-parole","back":"spokesperson, spokes- woman, spokesman"});
b.push({"front":"la vacance","back":"vacancy; vacation"});
b.push({"front":"monétaire","back":"monetary"});
b.push({"front":"un euro","back":"euro"});
b.push({"front":"là-bas","back":"over there, out there"});
b.push({"front":"doter","back":"to endow, provide"});
b.push({"front":"vice-président","back":"vice-president"});
b.push({"front":"un effectif","back":"effective; size, workforce"});
b.push({"front":"individuel","back":"individual"});
b.push({"front":"rendez-vous","back":"appointment"});
b.push({"front":"refléter","back":"to reflect"});
b.push({"front":"animer","back":"to lead, conduct, animate"});
b.push({"front":"la statistique","back":"statistics, statistical"});
b.push({"front":"gouvernemental","back":"governmental"});
b.push({"front":"irakien","back":"Iraqi"});
b.push({"front":"la proportion","back":"proportion"});
b.push({"front":"le critère","back":"criterion, criteria"});
b.push({"front":"illustrer","back":"to illustrate"});
b.push({"front":"formuler","back":"to formulate"});
b.push({"front":"un électeur","back":"elector, voter"});
b.push({"front":"varier","back":"to vary, change"});
b.push({"front":"québécois","back":"Quebecker, Quebecer, Québécois"});
b.push({"front":"multiplier","back":"to multiply"});
b.push({"front":"budgétaire","back":"budgetary"});
b.push({"front":"spécialiser","back":"to specialize"});
b.push({"front":"éventuel","back":"possible"});
b.push({"front":"le partisan","back":"partisan, supporter"});
b.push({"front":"efforcer","back":"endeavor"});
b.push({"front":"détenir","back":"to hold, detain"});
b.push({"front":"le multiple","back":"multiple"});
b.push({"front":"désoler","back":"to upset, sadden"});
b.push({"front":"résider","back":"to reside"});
b.push({"front":"le volet","back":"shutter"});
b.push({"front":"résulter","back":"to result"});
b.push({"front":"survenir","back":"to occur, take place, appear"});
b.push({"front":"le salarié, la salarié","back":"wage-earning, employee"});
b.push({"front":"orienter","back":"to position, give advice, direct, orientate"});
b.push({"front":"croître","back":"to grow, increase"});
b.push({"front":"contraindre","back":"to compel, force"});
b.push({"front":"le réformiste, la réformiste","back":"reformist"});
b.push({"front":"hausser","back":"to raise"});
b.push({"front":"le provincial","back":"provincial"});
b.push({"front":"répartir","back":"to distribute, spread out, share out, divide up"});
b.push({"front":"là-dessus","back":"on top, about it"});
b.push({"front":"nécessiter","back":"to require, necessitate"});
b.push({"front":"la revendication","back":"claim, demand"});
b.push({"front":"constitutionnel","back":"constitutional"});
b.push({"front":"une importation","back":"import"});
b.push({"front":"le référendum","back":"referendum"});
b.push({"front":"une instance","back":"authority, proceedings, hearing"});
b.push({"front":"recourir","back":"to turn to, run again"});
b.push({"front":"engendrer","back":"to father, breed, generate"});
b.push({"front":"une infrastructure","back":"infrastructure"});
b.push({"front":"la cotisation","back":"subscription"});
b.push({"front":"une affirmation","back":"assertion, affirmation"});
b.push({"front":"requérir","back":"to require"});
b.push({"front":"un agriculteur","back":"farmer"});
b.push({"front":"une inflation","back":"inflation"});
b.push({"front":"une autonomie","back":"autonomy"});
b.push({"front":"la contradiction","back":"contradiction"});
b.push({"front":"la souveraineté","back":"sovereignty"});
b.push({"front":"restreindre","back":"to restrict, cut down, decrease"});
b.push({"front":"présider","back":"to preside"});
b.push({"front":"un autochtone, une autochtone","back":"native, indigenous peoples"});
b.push({"front":"le rendement","back":"yield, output"});
b.push({"front":"une innovation","back":"innovation"});
b.push({"front":"la collectivité","back":"community, group"});
b.push({"front":"modalité","back":"mode, method, modality"});
b.push({"front":"le préalable","back":"prior, previous, preliminary, prerequisite"});
b.push({"front":"caractériser","back":"to characterize"});
b.push({"front":"intituler","back":"to entitle, call"});
b.push({"front":"le collaborateur","back":"associate, fellow worker, contributor, collaborator"});
b.push({"front":"accumuler","back":"to accumulate, amass, store, stockpile"});
b.push({"front":"week-end","back":"weekend"});
b.push({"front":"regrouper","back":"to group together, regroup"});
b.push({"front":"le militant","back":"militant"});
b.push({"front":"le participant","back":"participant"});
b.push({"front":"privilégier","back":"to favour"});
b.push({"front":"dater","back":"to date"});
b.push({"front":"la circonscription","back":"district, constituency"});
b.push({"front":"la subvention","back":"subsidy"});
b.push({"front":"équilibrer","back":"to balance"});
b.push({"front":"quelques-uns","back":"some, a few"});
b.push({"front":"solliciter","back":"to request, solicit, appeal"});
b.push({"front":"la prévention","back":"prevention, custody"});
b.push({"front":"complémentaire","back":"complementary, supplementary"});
b.push({"front":"parisien","back":"Parisian"});
b.push({"front":"respectif","back":"respective"});
b.push({"front":"contemporain","back":"contemporary"});
b.push({"front":"le pétrolier","back":"oil; oil tanker"});
b.push({"front":"la suppression","back":"deletion, suppression"});
b.push({"front":"existant","back":"existing"});
b.push({"front":"la restriction","back":"restriction"});
b.push({"front":"un indicateur","back":"indicator"});
b.push({"front":"la législation","back":"legislation"});
b.push({"front":"approprier","back":"to adapt, appropriate, take over"});
b.push({"front":"le chômeur","back":"unemployed person"});
b.push({"front":"succéder","back":"to succeed, take over"});
b.push({"front":"le paramètre","back":"parameter"});
b.push({"front":"déboucher","back":"to unblock, uncork"});
b.push({"front":"la répartition","back":"distribution, spreading"});
b.push({"front":"combiner","back":"to combine, devise"});
b.push({"front":"le contribuable, la contribuable","back":"taxpayer"});
b.push({"front":"progressivement","back":"progressively"});
b.push({"front":"antérieur","back":"previous, earlier, front"});
b.push({"front":"progressif","back":"progressive"});
b.push({"front":"une adhésion","back":"membership, support"});
b.push({"front":"détailler","back":"to detail"});
b.push({"front":"présumer","back":"to presume, assume"});
b.push({"front":"rigoureux","back":"rigorous, harsh, strict"});
b.push({"front":"revêtir","back":"to take on, assume"});
b.push({"front":"distinct","back":"distinct"});
b.push({"front":"la directive","back":"guideline"});
b.push({"front":"rural","back":"rural"});
b.push({"front":"persister","back":"to persist, keep up, linger"});
b.push({"front":"oriental","back":"Oriental"});
b.push({"front":"consentir","back":"to consent, agree"});
b.push({"front":"la variable","back":"variable"});
b.push({"front":"contradictoire","back":"contradictory, conflicting"});
b.push({"front":"instaurer","back":"to institute, introduce"});
b.push({"front":"revendiquer","back":"to claim"});
b.push({"front":"un accroissement","back":"increase"});
b.push({"front":"la diminution","back":"reduction, decreasing"});
b.push({"front":"la privatisation","back":"privatization"});
b.push({"front":"la réglementation","back":"regulation"});
b.push({"front":"déplorer","back":"to deplore"});
b.push({"front":"mobiliser","back":"to mobilize, call up"});
b.push({"front":"encadrer","back":"to frame, train"});
b.push({"front":"la télécommunication","back":"telecommunication"});
b.push({"front":"un aliment","back":"food"});
b.push({"front":"coordonner","back":"to coordinate"});
b.push({"front":"différer","back":"to differ, vary"});
b.push({"front":"découler","back":"to ensue, follow"});
b.push({"front":"mixte","back":"mixed"});
b.push({"front":"siéger","back":"to sit"});
b.push({"front":"grand-chose","back":"not very much"});
b.push({"front":"la transparence","back":"transparency"});
b.push({"front":"amorcer","back":"to bait, prime, begin, initiate"});
b.push({"front":"la productivité","back":"productivity"});
b.push({"front":"simplifier","back":"to simplify"});
b.push({"front":"le scrutin","back":"ballot, poll"});
b.push({"front":"passionner","back":"to fascinate, grip"});
b.push({"front":"généraliser","back":"to generalize"});
b.push({"front":"un économiste, une économiste","back":"economist"});
b.push({"front":"vouer","back":"to devote, dedicate to, vow to"});
b.push({"front":"proclamer","back":"to proclaim, declare"});
b.push({"front":"le monopole","back":"monopoly"});
b.push({"front":"approfondir","back":"to deepen, make deeper, go further into"});
b.push({"front":"syndical","back":"(trade-) union"});
b.push({"front":"un abonné","back":"subscribed, subscriber"});
b.push({"front":"structurel","back":"structural"});
b.push({"front":"dispenser","back":"to exempt, avoid"});
b.push({"front":"le déroulement","back":"development, progress"});
b.push({"front":"régir","back":"to govern"});
b.push({"front":"ministériel","back":"ministerial; minister"});
b.push({"front":"systématiquement","back":"systematically"});
b.push({"front":"équiper","back":"to equip, kit out, fit out, tool up"});
b.push({"front":"le détriment","back":"detriment"});
b.push({"front":"unanime","back":"unanimous"});
b.push({"front":"islamique","back":"Islamic"});
b.push({"front":"une attribution","back":"awarding, allocation, assignment, attribution"});
b.push({"front":"ethnique","back":"ethnic"});
b.push({"front":"un interlocuteur","back":"speaker"});
b.push({"front":"spécifier","back":"to specify"});
b.push({"front":"la rémunération","back":"remuneration, payment, pay"});
b.push({"front":"adhérer","back":"to stick to, support, join, be a member of"});
b.push({"front":"systématique","back":"systematic"});
b.push({"front":"parallèlement","back":"in parallel, similarly"});
b.push({"front":"francophone","back":"French-speaking, French speaker, francophone"});
b.push({"front":"émaner","back":"to issue from, emanate from, come from, radiate from"});
b.push({"front":"prévaloir","back":"to prevail"});
b.push({"front":"apprêter","back":"to prepare, get ready, dress"});
b.push({"front":"cibler","back":"to target"});
b.push({"front":"additionnel","back":"additional"});
b.push({"front":"le consensus","back":"consensus"});
b.push({"front":"un excédent","back":"surplus"});
b.push({"front":"la mondialisation","back":"internationalisation, globalisation"});
b.push({"front":"le conventionnel","back":"conventional"});
b.push({"front":"une unanimité","back":"unanimity"});
b.push({"front":"une inégalité","back":"difference, uneveness, inequality"});
b.push({"front":"accentuer","back":"to stress, to emphasize, become more pronounced"});
b.push({"front":"rattacher","back":"to attach, join, tie"});
b.push({"front":"contracter","back":"to contract, take out, tense"});
b.push({"front":"territorial","back":"territorial, land"});
b.push({"front":"subsister","back":"to subsist, remain"});
b.push({"front":"un usager","back":"user"});
b.push({"front":"la continuité","back":"continuity, continuation"});
b.push({"front":"maximal","back":"maximal"});
b.push({"front":"une idéologie","back":"ideology"});
b.push({"front":"le demandeur","back":"seeker, complainant"});
b.push({"front":"homologue","back":"counterpart, homologue"});
b.push({"front":"successif","back":"successive"});
b.push({"front":"le matériau","back":"material"});
b.push({"front":"la divergence","back":"divergence, difference"});
b.push({"front":"la municipalité","back":"municipality"});
b.push({"front":"consécutif","back":"consecutive"});
b.push({"front":"institutionnel","back":"institutional"});
b.push({"front":"la confédération","back":"confederation"});
b.push({"front":"acquitter","back":"to acquit, pay, settle, pay off"});
b.push({"front":"référer","back":"to refer, consult, refer to"});
b.push({"front":"substantiel","back":"substantial"});
b.push({"front":"une exclusion","back":"exclusion, expulsion"});
b.push({"front":"préconiser","back":"to recommend, advocate"});
b.push({"front":"un historien","back":"historian"});
b.push({"front":"atténuer","back":"to lessen, diminish, dim, subdue, reduce"});
b.push({"front":"applicable","back":"applicable"});
b.push({"front":"sud-est","back":"south-east"});
b.push({"front":"le conjoint","back":"spouse, joint"});
b.push({"front":"assortir","back":"to match, accompany"});
b.push({"front":"la restructuration","back":"restructure, restructuring"});
b.push({"front":"demi-heure","back":"half an hour"});
b.push({"front":"un actionnaire, une actionnaire","back":"shareholder"});
b.push({"front":"redouter","back":"to dread, fear"});
b.push({"front":"acheminer","back":"to forward, dispatch, transport"});
b.push({"front":"conformer","back":"to model, conform"});
b.push({"front":"délibérer","back":"to deliberate, debate"});
b.push({"front":"puiser","back":"to draw, take"});
b.push({"front":"géographique","back":"geographic, geographical"});
b.push({"front":"œuvrer","back":"to work"});
b.push({"front":"la contestation","back":"questioning, protest"});
b.push({"front":"iranien","back":"Iranian"});
b.push({"front":"conférer","back":"to confer"});
b.push({"front":"interpeller","back":"to call out to, question"});
b.push({"front":"fréquemment","back":"frequently"});
b.push({"front":"la légitimité","back":"legitimacy"});
b.push({"front":"dériver","back":"to divert, derive"});
b.push({"front":"respectivement","back":"respectively"});
b.push({"front":"induire","back":"to infer, induce, result in , lead to"});
b.push({"front":"un arbitrage","back":"refereeing, umpiring, arbitration"});
b.push({"front":"déléguer","back":"to delegate"});
b.push({"front":"miner","back":"to mine, erode"});
b.push({"front":"composante","back":"component"});
b.push({"front":"instituer","back":"to introduce, impose, establish, institute"});
b.push({"front":"marocain","back":"Moroccan"});
b.push({"front":"le nominal","back":"nominal"});
b.push({"front":"peiner","back":"to toil, labor, struggle"});
b.push({"front":"le renouvellement","back":"replacement, recurrence, repetition"});
b.push({"front":"le protestant","back":"Protestant"});
b.push({"front":"le faisceau","back":"bundle, beam, stack"});
b.push({"front":"le dégât","back":"damage"});
b.push({"front":"multinational","back":"multinational"});
b.push({"front":"étroitement","back":"closely"});
b.push({"front":"faillir","back":"to have almost, fail, fail to"});
b.push({"front":"nous-mêmes","back":"ourselves"});
b.push({"front":"coter","back":"to quote, rate"});
b.push({"front":"bien-être","back":"well being"});
b.push({"front":"énoncer","back":"to state, set out, express"});
b.push({"front":"un islamiste, une islamiste","back":"Islamist"});
b.push({"front":"bilatéral","back":"bilateral"});
b.push({"front":"environnemental","back":"environmental"});
b.push({"front":"le constructeur","back":"builder, manufacturer"});
b.push({"front":"déceler","back":"to discover, detect"});
b.push({"front":"acharner","back":"to go at fiercely and unrelentingly"});
b.push({"front":"assimiler","back":"to assimilate, take in"});
b.push({"front":"incarner","back":"to embody, incarnate"});
b.push({"front":"opter","back":"to opt, decide"});
b.push({"front":"décréter","back":"to declare, decree"});
b.push({"front":"dix-huit","back":"eighteen"});
b.push({"front":"coïncider","back":"to coincide, correspond"});
b.push({"front":"le renforcement","back":"reinforcement, strengthening"});
b.push({"front":"une élaboration","back":"working-out, development"});
b.push({"front":"une habitation","back":"residence, home, dwelling, housing"});
b.push({"front":"représentatif","back":"representative"});
b.push({"front":"une imposition","back":"taxation"});
b.push({"front":"un ajustement","back":"adjustment"});
b.push({"front":"la répercussion","back":"repercussion"});
b.push({"front":"soi-disant","back":"so-called, supposedly"});
b.push({"front":"salarial","back":"salary"});
b.push({"front":"abolir","back":"to abolish, do away with"});
b.push({"front":"la cohésion","back":"cohesion"});
b.push({"front":"minimal","back":"minimal, minimum"});
b.push({"front":"implanter","back":"to implant, set up, establish"});
b.push({"front":"exhorter","back":"to exhort, urge"});
b.push({"front":"sélectionner","back":"to select"});
b.push({"front":"paralyser","back":"to paralyze"});
b.push({"front":"le préjugé","back":"prejudice, bias"});
b.push({"front":"nord-ouest","back":"north-west"});
b.push({"front":"un affaiblissement","back":"weakening"});
b.push({"front":"peupler","back":"to populate, inhabit"});
b.push({"front":"resserrer","back":"to tighten up, strengthen"});
b.push({"front":"activement","back":"actively"});
b.push({"front":"incompatible","back":"incompatible"});
b.push({"front":"la synthèse","back":"summary, synthesis"});
b.push({"front":"la conjoncture","back":"situation, climate"});
b.push({"front":"réformer","back":"to re-form, reform, discharge"});
b.push({"front":"reléguer","back":"to relegate"});
b.push({"front":"un intervenant","back":"contributor, intervener"});
b.push({"front":"arbitraire","back":"arbitrary"});
b.push({"front":"la propagation","back":"propagation, spreading"});
b.push({"front":"grand-père","back":"grandfather"});
b.push({"front":"décliner","back":"to decline, refuse, turn down"});
b.push({"front":"un écu","back":"ecu"});
b.push({"front":"indirect","back":"indirect"});
b.push({"front":"démentir","back":"to deny, refute, contradict"});
b.push({"front":"sud-ouest","back":"south-west"});
b.push({"front":"le déterminant","back":"determining, deciding, crucial"});
b.push({"front":"sous-marin","back":"submarine, underwater"});
b.push({"front":"un acheminement","back":"routing, shipment"});
b.push({"front":"le notable","back":"notable, noteworthy"});
b.push({"front":"le tchèque","back":"Czech"});
b.push({"front":"là-dedans","back":"inside, in it"});
b.push({"front":"le différend","back":"disagreement, controversy"});
b.push({"front":"explicite","back":"explicitly"});
b.push({"front":"par-dessus","back":"over"});
b.push({"front":"apparent","back":"apparent, obvious"});
b.push({"front":"une allocation","back":"allocation, granting, allotment, allowance"});
b.push({"front":"décéder","back":"to die, pass away, pass on"});
b.push({"front":"dix-sept","back":"seventeen"});
b.push({"front":"une ambiguïté","back":"ambiguity"});
b.push({"front":"consultatif","back":"advisory"});
b.push({"front":"la complexité","back":"complexity"});
b.push({"front":"brandir","back":"to brandish, wield, wave"});
b.push({"front":"précaire","back":"precarious, makeshift"});
b.push({"front":"la justification","back":"justification, proof"});
b.push({"front":"la conservation","back":"preservation, preserving, retention"});
b.push({"front":"un aménagement","back":"development, planning, fitting, adjustment"});
b.push({"front":"le manifestant","back":"protester, demonstrator"});
b.push({"front":"prôner","back":"to laud, extol, advocate, commend"});
b.push({"front":"radicalement","back":"radically"});
b.push({"front":"ultérieur","back":"later, subsequent"});
b.push({"front":"axer","back":"to center"});
b.push({"front":"rectifier","back":"to rectify, correct"});
b.push({"front":"émouvoir","back":"to move, touch"});
b.push({"front":"alléger","back":"to lighten, alleviate,"});
b.push({"front":"la dégradation","back":"degrading, damaging, erosion; demotion"});
b.push({"front":"le vingtième, la vingtième","back":"twentieth"});
b.push({"front":"grand-mère","back":"grandmother"});
b.push({"front":"la citoyenneté","back":"citizenship"});
b.push({"front":"attester","back":"to attest, confirm"});
b.push({"front":"nullement","back":"not in the least"});
b.push({"front":"incorporer","back":"to incorporate, insert, merge"});
b.push({"front":"débloquer","back":"to free, unfreeze, unjam, release, unblock"});
b.push({"front":"la linguistique","back":"linguistic, linguistics"});
b.push({"front":"main-d’œuvre","back":"manpower, labor, workforce"});
b.push({"front":"rallier","back":"to rally, win over, join"});
b.push({"front":"réaffirmer","back":"to reaffirm, reassert"});
b.push({"front":"assigner","back":"to assign, allocate, attach, attribute"});
b.push({"front":"souhaitable","back":"desirable"});
b.push({"front":"le constat","back":"report, statement"});
b.push({"front":"le dynamisme","back":"dynamism"});
b.push({"front":"concerter","back":"to devise, consult"});
b.push({"front":"désespérer","back":"to despair"});
b.push({"front":"exporter","back":"to export"});
b.push({"front":"ériger","back":"to erect, set up"});
b.push({"front":"transitoire","back":"transient, interim, provisional"});
b.push({"front":"tardif","back":"late"});
b.push({"front":"un apport","back":"supply, contribution"});
b.push({"front":"un échelon","back":"rung, step, grade, echelon"});
b.push({"front":"une occurrence","back":"instance, case, occurrence"});
b.push({"front":"au-dessous","back":"underneath"});
b.push({"front":"fonctionnel","back":"functional"});
b.push({"front":"entre-temps","back":"meanwhile, in the meantime"});
b.push({"front":"le confrère","back":"colleague"});
b.push({"front":"la variation","back":"variation, change"});
b.push({"front":"productif","back":"productive"});
b.push({"front":"le groupement","back":"grouping, group, categorization"});
b.push({"front":"la modernisation","back":"modernization"});
b.push({"front":"souscrire","back":"to subscribe"});
b.push({"front":"le suffrage","back":"vote"});
b.push({"front":"concilier","back":"to reconcile"});
b.push({"front":"libanais","back":"Lebanese"});
b.push({"front":"le rapporteur","back":"telltale, rapporteur"});
b.push({"front":"le dix-neuvième, la dix-neuvième","back":"nineteenth"});
b.push({"front":"une indemnisation","back":"indemnification, compensation"});
b.push({"front":"le leadership","back":"leadership"});
b.push({"front":"la qualification","back":"qualification"});
b.push({"front":"dédier","back":"to dedicate"});
b.push({"front":"un artisan","back":"craftsman, self-employed"});
b.push({"front":"économiquement","back":"economically"});
b.push({"front":"industrialiser","back":"to industrialize"});
b.push({"front":"efficacement","back":"efficiently, effectively"});
b.push({"front":"le marginal","back":"marginal"});
b.push({"front":"modérer","back":"to restrain, moderate, reduce"});
b.push({"front":"une appartenance","back":"membership, belonging"});
b.push({"front":"constructif","back":"constructive"});
b.push({"front":"minime","back":"minor, minimal"});
b.push({"front":"le ralentissement","back":"slowing down"});
b.push({"front":"la mobilisation","back":"mobilization"});
b.push({"front":"tâcher","back":"to endeavor"});
b.push({"front":"la récession","back":"recession"});
b.push({"front":"sensiblement","back":"approximately, more or less, noticeably"});
b.push({"front":"léguer","back":"to bequeath, hand down, pass on"});
b.push({"front":"problématique","back":"problematic; problem"});
b.push({"front":"voiler","back":"to veil"});
b.push({"front":"erroné","back":"erroneous"});
b.push({"front":"yougoslave","back":"Yugoslav, Yugoslavian"});
b.push({"front":"explicitement","back":"explicitly"});
b.push({"front":"la souplesse","back":"suppleness, flexibility"});
b.push({"front":"le contingent","back":"contingent, draft, quota"});
b.push({"front":"émerger","back":"to emerge, rise up, come out"});
b.push({"front":"instruire","back":"to teach, educate, inform"});
b.push({"front":"une équité","back":"equity, fairly"});
b.push({"front":"soustraire","back":"to substract, remove, shield, escape from"});
b.push({"front":"téléviser","back":"to televise"});
b.push({"front":"consolider","back":"to strengthen, reinforce"});
b.push({"front":"le contrevenant","back":"offender, offending"});
b.push({"front":"coder","back":"to code, encode"});
b.push({"front":"la controverse","back":"controversy"});
b.push({"front":"filial","back":"filial; branch office"});
b.push({"front":"un opposant","back":"opponent, opposing"});
b.push({"front":"le sommaire","back":"summary, brief, cursory"});
b.push({"front":"le versant","back":"hillside, mountainside"});
b.push({"front":"la réticence","back":"reluctance, hesitation"});
b.push({"front":"un élargissement","back":"widening, letting-out, stretching, broadening"});
b.push({"front":"dégrader","back":"to degrade, debase, damage, erode"});
b.push({"front":"colonial","back":"colonial"});
b.push({"front":"le pourparler","back":"talk, discussion, negotiation"});
b.push({"front":"un incidence","back":"effect, incidence"});
b.push({"front":"vingt-quatre","back":"twenty four"});
b.push({"front":"le teneur, la teneur","back":"content"});
b.push({"front":"centrer","back":"to center"});
b.push({"front":"algérien","back":"Algerian"});
b.push({"front":"alentour","back":"around, round about"});
b.push({"front":"perpétuer","back":"to perpetuate, carry on"});
b.push({"front":"la doctrine","back":"doctrine"});
b.push({"front":"compétitif","back":"competitive"});
b.push({"front":"omettre","back":"to leave out, miss out, omit"});
b.push({"front":"concurrentiel","back":"competitive"});
b.push({"front":"le désarmement","back":"disarmament, disarming"});
b.push({"front":"quotidiennement","back":"daily, every day"});
b.push({"front":"état-major","back":"staff, staff headquarters"});
b.push({"front":"attarder","back":"to linger"});
b.push({"front":"englober","back":"to include, encompass, incorporate"});
b.push({"front":"le séparatiste, la séparatiste","back":"separatist"});
b.push({"front":"le surcroît","back":"extra, additional"});
b.push({"front":"nationaliste","back":"nationalist"});
b.push({"front":"un exportateur","back":"exportateur, exporting"});
b.push({"front":"ratifier","back":"to ratify"});
b.push({"front":"aviser","back":"to notice, advise"});
b.push({"front":"écologique","back":"ecological"});
b.push({"front":"sanctionner","back":"to sanction, punish, approve"});
b.push({"front":"aisé","back":"easy, well off, well-to-do"});
b.push({"front":"défavoriser","back":"to put at a disadvantage"});
b.push({"front":"civiliser","back":"to civilze"});
b.push({"front":"octroyer","back":"to grant, bestow"});
b.push({"front":"la limitation","back":"limitation, restriction, limit"});
b.push({"front":"irréversible","back":"irreversible"});
b.push({"front":"verbal","back":"verbal"});
b.push({"front":"une appréciation","back":"appreciation, assessment, appraisal"});
b.push({"front":"le complément","back":"complement"});
b.push({"front":"initialement","back":"initially"});
b.push({"front":"replier","back":"to fold, roll up, fold up, withdraw"});
b.push({"front":"le vérificateur","back":"checker, inspector, auditor"});
b.push({"front":"la prétention","back":"claim"});
b.push({"front":"la stabilisation","back":"stabilisation"});
b.push({"front":"la lacune","back":"gap, deficiency"});
b.push({"front":"mépriser","back":"to scorn, look down, spurn, disdain"});
b.push({"front":"minoritaire","back":"minority"});
b.push({"front":"idéologique","back":"ideological"});
b.push({"front":"le compatriote, la compatriote","back":"compatriot"});
b.push({"front":"majoritaire","back":"majority"});
b.push({"front":"le redressement","back":"straightening up, upturn, righting"});
b.push({"front":"chiffrer","back":"to put a figure to, assess, quantify, number"});
b.push({"front":"la compétitivité","back":"competitiveness"});
b.push({"front":"sous-sol","back":"basement, lower ground floor, subsoil, underground"});
b.push({"front":"indépendamment","back":"independently, irrespective of, regardless of"});
b.push({"front":"le rayonnement","back":"radiance"});
b.push({"front":"minier","back":"mining"});
b.push({"front":"ébranler","back":"to shake, rattle"});
b.push({"front":"unilatéral","back":"unilateral"});
b.push({"front":"tisser","back":"to weave"});
b.push({"front":"la cohérence","back":"coherence, consistency"});
b.push({"front":"modéré","back":"moderate, restrained, reasonable"});
b.push({"front":"négligeable","back":"negligible, trivial"});
b.push({"front":"symboliser","back":"to symbolize"});
b.push({"front":"substituer","back":"to substitute"});
b.push({"front":"le gestionnaire, la gestionnaire","back":"administrator, administrative"});
b.push({"front":"un immigrant","back":"immigrant"});
b.push({"front":"la polémique","back":"controversial, controversy"});
b.push({"front":"alourdir","back":"to weigh down, make heavy"});
b.push({"front":"sévir","back":"to act ruthlessly, be rife"});
b.push({"front":"la localité","back":"town, village"});
b.push({"front":"vigoureux","back":"vigorous"});
b.push({"front":"la rentabilité","back":"profitability"});
b.push({"front":"incliner","back":"to tilt, tend towards"});
b.push({"front":"révolter","back":"to revolt, rebel, outrage"});
b.push({"front":"philosophique","back":"philosophical"});
b.push({"front":"la parenthèse","back":"parenthesis, bracket, aside"});
b.push({"front":"le boursier","back":"grant-holder, scholarship holder; stock"});
b.push({"front":"déformer","back":"to bend, distort, deform"});
b.push({"front":"nord-est","back":"north-east"});
b.push({"front":"la substitution","back":"substitution, mix-up"});
b.push({"front":"parer","back":"to adorn, put on; to ward off, parry"});
b.push({"front":"avantageux","back":"profitable, worthwhile, advantageous, attractive"});
b.push({"front":"handicaper","back":"to handicap"});
b.push({"front":"imputer","back":"to impute to, attribute to"});
b.push({"front":"desservir","back":"to clear, go against, harm, serve"});
b.push({"front":"le mensuel","back":"monthly"});
b.push({"front":"le report","back":"postponement, deferment"});
b.push({"front":"aucunement","back":"in no way, not in the least, not at all"});
b.push({"front":"globalement","back":"globally"});
b.push({"front":"alternatif","back":"alternate, alternating"});
b.push({"front":"réglementaire","back":"regulation, control, statutory"});
b.push({"front":"une incitation","back":"incitement, incentive"});
b.push({"front":"un éditorial","back":"editorial"});
b.push({"front":"vingt-cinq","back":"twenty five"});
b.push({"front":"le déséquilibre","back":"imbalance"});
b.push({"front":"entraver","back":"to hinder, hamper, get in the way of"});
b.push({"front":"sous-estimer","back":"to underestimate"});
b.push({"front":"un embargo","back":"embargo"});
b.push({"front":"syrien","back":"Syrian"});
b.push({"front":"ponctuel","back":"punctual"});
b.push({"front":"la fermeté","back":"firmness, solidness, steadiness"});
b.push({"front":"véhiculer","back":"to transport, convey"});
b.push({"front":"répliquer","back":"to reply"});
b.push({"front":"la théologie","back":"theology"});
b.push({"front":"advenir","back":"to happen that, happen to"});
b.push({"front":"immigrer","back":"to immigrate"});
b.push({"front":"le privilégié","back":"privileged"});
b.push({"front":"controversé","back":"much debated, controversial"});
b.push({"front":"nouer","back":"to knot, tie"});
b.push({"front":"la gendarmerie","back":"police force, police station"});
b.push({"front":"analogue","back":"similar, analogous"});
b.push({"front":"initier","back":"to initiate, introduce"});
b.push({"front":"cessez-le-feu","back":"ceasefire"});
b.push({"front":"dissiper","back":"to dispel, disperse, clear away"});
b.push({"front":"entrevoir","back":"to make out, catch a glimpse of, foresee"});
b.push({"front":"stipuler","back":"to state, stipulate, specify"});
b.push({"front":"une impossibilité","back":"impossibility"});
b.push({"front":"le conditionnel","back":"conditional"});
b.push({"front":"la nuance","back":"shade, hue, nuance"});
b.push({"front":"conjointement","back":"jointly"});
b.push({"front":"articuler","back":"to articulate"});
b.push({"front":"successivement","back":"successively"});
b.push({"front":"la provision","back":"stock, supply"});
b.push({"front":"amplifier","back":"to amplify, magnify, expand"});
b.push({"front":"intergouvernemental","back":"intergovernmental"});
b.push({"front":"la délibération","back":"deliberation, debate, consideration"});
b.push({"front":"saisonnier","back":"seasonal"});
b.push({"front":"restituer","back":"to return, restore, refund"});
b.push({"front":"la disponibilité","back":"availability"});
b.push({"front":"le glissement","back":"sliding, slipping, skidding"});
b.push({"front":"un auditeur","back":"auditor, listener"});
b.push({"front":"un indigène, une indigène","back":"native, local"});
b.push({"front":"indirectement","back":"indirectly"});
b.push({"front":"une obtention","back":"obtaining, achievement"});
b.push({"front":"le prostitué","back":"prostitute"});
b.push({"front":"le concitoyen","back":"fellow citizen"});
b.push({"front":"libéralisation","back":"liberalization"});
b.push({"front":"le signataire, la signataire","back":"signatory"});
b.push({"front":"le douanier","back":"customs officer"});
b.push({"front":"borner","back":"to limit, confine"});
b.push({"front":"triompher","back":"to triumph, beat"});
b.push({"front":"concrétiser","back":"to materialise"});
b.push({"front":"la soumission","back":"submission"});
b.push({"front":"continuellement","back":"continually, continuously"});
b.push({"front":"dérober","back":"to steal, hide"});
b.push({"front":"le romancier","back":"novelist"});
b.push({"front":"déplaire","back":"to displease, be unhappy"});
b.push({"front":"innombrable","back":"innumerable, countless"});
b.push({"front":"inédit","back":"unpublished; original, new"});
b.push({"front":"désireux","back":"avid for, anxious to, desirous of"});
b.push({"front":"diversifier","back":"to vary, diversify"});
b.push({"front":"une instabilité","back":"instability"});
b.push({"front":"pénaliser","back":"to penalize, punish"});
b.push({"front":"foncier","back":"land-related, land, fundamental"});
b.push({"front":"envelopper","back":"to wrap, surround, veil"});
b.push({"front":"irrégulier","back":"irregular, uneven"});
b.push({"front":"un encadrement","back":"training, framing, supervision"});
b.push({"front":"moderniser","back":"to modernize"});
b.push({"front":"incomber","back":"to be incumbent upon"});
b.push({"front":"la retombée","back":"fallout, consequences, effects"});
b.push({"front":"équivaloir","back":"to be equivalent, amount to"});
b.push({"front":"le chiite, la chiite","back":"Shiite"});
b.push({"front":"le bouleversement","back":"upheaval"});
b.push({"front":"relater","back":"to relate, recount"});
b.push({"front":"concrètement","back":"in concrete terms"});
b.push({"front":"la coulisse","back":"backstage, wings, behind the scenes"});
b.push({"front":"la ratification","back":"ratification"});
b.push({"front":"le renouveau","back":"renewal"});
b.push({"front":"le néerlandais","back":"Dutch"});
b.push({"front":"intégral","back":"complete, unabridged"});
b.push({"front":"spécification","back":"specification"});
b.push({"front":"la documentation","back":"documentation, literature"});
b.push({"front":"logiquement","back":"logically"});
b.push({"front":"harmoniser","back":"to harmonize, harmonize with"});
b.push({"front":"le débouché","back":"prospect, opportunity, opening"});
b.push({"front":"le secrétariat","back":"secretaryship, secretariat, secretarial offices, secretary’s office"});
b.push({"front":"le détenteur","back":"holder, possessor, bearer"});
b.push({"front":"le basque, la basque","back":"Basque"});
b.push({"front":"une accumulation","back":"accumulation, amassing, storage, stockpiling, build-up"});
b.push({"front":"un essor","back":"expansion, development, flight"});
b.push({"front":"obséder","back":"to obsess, haunt"});
b.push({"front":"préventif","back":"preventive"});
b.push({"front":"la désignation","back":"designation"});
b.push({"front":"la conformité","back":"conformity"});
b.push({"front":"inhérent","back":"inherent"});
b.push({"front":"une illustration","back":"illustration"});
b.push({"front":"néfaste","back":"harmful, ill-fated"});
b.push({"front":"lasser","back":"to tire, weary, grow weary"});
b.push({"front":"influer","back":"to influence, have an influence on"});
b.push({"front":"présentement","back":"at present, presently"});
b.push({"front":"plate-forme","back":"platform"});
b.push({"front":"le kurde","back":"Kurd, Kurdish"});
b.push({"front":"inchangé","back":"unchanged"});
b.push({"front":"la multiplication","back":"multiplication"});
b.push({"front":"camoufler","back":"to cover up, conceal, camouflage"});
b.push({"front":"figer","back":"to clot, coagulate, congeal, set"});
b.push({"front":"la planification","back":"planning"});
b.push({"front":"le regroupement","back":"regrouping, reassembly"});
b.push({"front":"désastreux","back":"disastrous"});
b.push({"front":"la configuration","back":"configuration, layout"});
b.push({"front":"escompter","back":"to discount; to expect"});
b.push({"front":"intensif","back":"intensive"});
b.push({"front":"le scepticisme","back":"scepticism"});
b.push({"front":"plénier","back":"plenary, full"});
b.push({"front":"épanouir","back":"to bloom, blossom"});
b.push({"front":"minimiser","back":"to minimize, play down"});
b.push({"front":"inévitablement","back":"inevitably"});
b.push({"front":"échéant","back":"if need be"});
b.push({"front":"murmurer","back":"to murmur"});
b.push({"front":"une implantation","back":"implanting, setting up, establishment, implantation, installation"});
b.push({"front":"décerner","back":"to award, give, issue"});
b.push({"front":"replacer","back":"to replace, put back"});
b.push({"front":"vêtir","back":"to clothe, dress, put on"});
b.push({"front":"enchanter","back":"to delight, enchant, rejoice"});
b.push({"front":"démographique","back":"demographic"});
b.push({"front":"la fourniture","back":"supply, provision"});
b.push({"front":"taxer","back":"to tax"});
b.push({"front":"dévouer","back":"to devote, sacrifice oneself"});
b.push({"front":"hâter","back":"to quicken, hasten"});
b.push({"front":"la mobilité","back":"mobility"});
b.push({"front":"la dénonciation","back":"denunciation"});
b.push({"front":"exiler","back":"to exile"});
b.push({"front":"forger","back":"to forge, contrive, make up"});
b.push({"front":"le textile","back":"textile"});
b.push({"front":"la médiation","back":"mediation, arbitration"});
b.push({"front":"réprimer","back":"to suppress, repress"});
b.push({"front":"rémunérer","back":"to remunerate, pay"});
b.push({"front":"fasciner","back":"to fascinate"});
b.push({"front":"le progressiste, la progressiste","back":"progressive"});
b.push({"front":"excéder","back":"to exceed"});
b.push({"front":"inexistant","back":"non-existent"});
b.push({"front":"concéder","back":"to grant, concede"});
b.push({"front":"retrancher","back":"to deduct, remove; to entrench"});
b.push({"front":"renfermer","back":"to contain, shut, lock, enclose"});
b.push({"front":"traditionnellement","back":"traditionally"});
b.push({"front":"le mécontentement","back":"displeasure, dissatisfaction"});
b.push({"front":"inaugurer","back":"to unveil, open"});
b.push({"front":"proportionnel","back":"proportional"});
b.push({"front":"un aboutissement","back":"outcome, result"});
b.push({"front":"libre-échange","back":"free trade"});
b.push({"front":"maltraiter","back":"to manhandle, ill-treat, misuse, slight"});
b.push({"front":"continental","back":"continental"});
b.push({"front":"réitérer","back":"to reiterate, repeat"});
b.push({"front":"énumérer","back":"to enumerate"});
b.push({"front":"dix-neuf","back":"nineteen"});
b.push({"front":"guetter","back":"to watch over, watch out for"});
b.push({"front":"frustrer","back":"to frustrate"});
b.push({"front":"anglo-saxon","back":"Anglo-Saxon"});
b.push({"front":"sécuritaire","back":"safe"});
b.push({"front":"écrier","back":"to exclaim, cry out"});
b.push({"front":"la rente","back":"annuity, pension"});
b.push({"front":"résolument","back":"resolutely"});
b.push({"front":"soixante-dix","back":"seventy"});
b.push({"front":"perpétuel","back":"perpetual, everlasting, never-ending"});
b.push({"front":"militer","back":"to militate"});
b.push({"front":"procès-verbal","back":"minutes, statement"});
b.push({"front":"énergique","back":"energetic"});
b.push({"front":"défavorable","back":"unfavorable"});
b.push({"front":"un albanais","back":"Albanian"});
b.push({"front":"savoir-faire","back":"know-how"});
b.push({"front":"écrasant","back":"crushing, overwhelming"});
b.push({"front":"la munition","back":"ammunition, supplies"});
b.push({"front":"allouer","back":"to allocate"});
b.push({"front":"scandaliser","back":"to shock, scandalize"});
b.push({"front":"empresser","back":"to bustle about, hasten to do"});
b.push({"front":"inonder","back":"to flood"});
b.push({"front":"réglementer","back":"to regulate, control"});
b.push({"front":"sonder","back":"to probe, poll, sound out"});
b.push({"front":"le téléspectateur","back":"TV viewer"});
b.push({"front":"le forestier","back":"forest, forester"});
b.push({"front":"ravager","back":"to ravage, devastate"});
b.push({"front":"racial","back":"racial"});
b.push({"front":"ensuivre","back":"to follow, result, ensue"});
b.push({"front":"ajourner","back":"to adjourn, defer, postpone"});
b.push({"front":"la détérioration","back":"deterioration"});
b.push({"front":"civique","back":"civil; civics"});
b.push({"front":"ancrer","back":"to anchor"});
b.push({"front":"la législature","back":"legislature"});
b.push({"front":"audiovisuel","back":"audio-visual"});
b.push({"front":"confiner","back":"to confine"});
b.push({"front":"occasionner","back":"to cause, give rise to"});
b.push({"front":"allégement","back":"lightening, unweighting, reduction"});
b.push({"front":"performant","back":"productive, efficient"});
b.push({"front":"la concertation","back":"meeting, consultation"});
b.push({"front":"une interaction","back":"interaction"});
b.push({"front":"le sillage","back":"wake, slipstream"});
b.push({"front":"hisser","back":"to hoist, raise up"});
b.push({"front":"agréer","back":"to accept, approve of"});
b.push({"front":"le bosniaque","back":"Bosnian"});
b.push({"front":"solidaire","back":"interdependent, jointly dependent"});
b.push({"front":"ferroviaire","back":"railway, rail"});
b.push({"front":"la céréale","back":"cereal"});
b.push({"front":"aménager","back":"to develop, plan, fit, adjust"});
b.push({"front":"un exode","back":"exodus"});
b.push({"front":"le socialisme","back":"socialism"});
b.push({"front":"harmonisation","back":"harmonization"});
b.push({"front":"provisoirement","back":"temporarily, provisionally"});
b.push({"front":"détériorer","back":"to deteriorate"});
b.push({"front":"de","back":"of, from, some, any"});
b.push({"front":"je","back":"I"});
b.push({"front":"pas","back":"not, no"});
b.push({"front":"le","back":"the; him, her, it, them"});
b.push({"front":"que","back":"that, which, who, whom"});
b.push({"front":"tu","back":"you"});
b.push({"front":"vous","back":"you(pl)"});
b.push({"front":"un","back":"a, an, one"});
b.push({"front":"et","back":"and"});
b.push({"front":"à","back":"to, at, in"});
b.push({"front":"il","back":"he, it"});
b.push({"front":"ne","back":"not"});
b.push({"front":"en","back":"in, by"});
b.push({"front":"on","back":"one, we"});
b.push({"front":"ce","back":"this, that"});
b.push({"front":"pour","back":"for, in order to"});
b.push({"front":"qui","back":"who, whom"});
b.push({"front":"mais","back":"but"});
b.push({"front":"dans","back":"in, into, from"});
b.push({"front":"nous","back":"we, us"});
b.push({"front":"elle","back":"she, her"});
b.push({"front":"bien","back":"well"});
b.push({"front":"me","back":"me, to me, myself"});
b.push({"front":"si","back":"if, whether"});
b.push({"front":"y","back":"there"});
b.push({"front":"non","back":"no, not"});
b.push({"front":"avec","back":"with"});
b.push({"front":"tout","back":"all, very"});
b.push({"front":"plus","back":"more, no more"});
b.push({"front":"mon","back":"my"});
b.push({"front":"te","back":"you, to you, from you"});
b.push({"front":"fait","back":"done, fact"});
b.push({"front":"moi","back":"me"});
b.push({"front":"oui","back":"yes"});
b.push({"front":"faire","back":"to do, make"});
b.push({"front":"sur","back":"on, upon"});
b.push({"front":"quoi","back":"what"});
b.push({"front":"se","back":"oneself, himself, herself, itself, themselves"});
b.push({"front":"comme","back":"like, as"});
b.push({"front":"être","back":"to be; being"});
b.push({"front":"ici","back":"here"});
b.push({"front":"toi","back":"you, yourself"});
b.push({"front":"dit","back":"said, so-called; tale"});
b.push({"front":"lui","back":"him, her"});
b.push({"front":"votre","back":"your"});
b.push({"front":"pourquoi","back":"why"});
b.push({"front":"où","back":"where"});
b.push({"front":"rien","back":"nothing"});
b.push({"front":"là","back":"there, here"});
b.push({"front":"quand","back":"when"});
b.push({"front":"dire","back":"to say"});
b.push({"front":"son","back":"his, her, its; sound"});
b.push({"front":"ton","back":"your"});
b.push({"front":"alors","back":"then, so"});
b.push({"front":"comment","back":"how"});
b.push({"front":"par","back":"by"});
b.push({"front":"ou","back":"or"});
b.push({"front":"la chose","back":"thing"});
b.push({"front":"bon","back":"good"});
b.push({"front":"le merci, la merci","back":"thank you; favor"});
b.push({"front":"juste","back":"just, only; fair"});
b.push({"front":"très","back":"very"});
b.push({"front":"jamais","back":"never"});
b.push({"front":"un été","back":"summer; past particle of être (to be)"});
b.push({"front":"avoir","back":"to have"});
b.push({"front":"vraiment","back":"truly, really, very"});
b.push({"front":"aussi","back":"too, also, as"});
b.push({"front":"voir","back":"to see"});
b.push({"front":"oh","back":"oh"});
b.push({"front":"même","back":"same, even, self"});
b.push({"front":"maintenant","back":"now"});
b.push({"front":"le deux","back":"two"});
b.push({"front":"autre","back":"other"});
b.push({"front":"peu","back":"little"});
b.push({"front":"quelque","back":"some"});
b.push({"front":"le temps","back":"time"});
b.push({"front":"toujours","back":"always"});
b.push({"front":"encore","back":"again, yet"});
b.push({"front":"notre","back":"our"});
b.push({"front":"besoin","back":"need"});
b.push({"front":"un accord","back":"agreement"});
b.push({"front":"la vie","back":"life"});
b.push({"front":"aller","back":"to go"});
b.push({"front":"la fois","back":"time, times"});
b.push({"front":"sans","back":"without"});
b.push({"front":"donc","back":"so, then, therefore, thus"});
b.push({"front":"le monde","back":"world, people"});
b.push({"front":"avant","back":"before; forward"});
b.push({"front":"sûr","back":"sure"});
b.push({"front":"trop","back":"too much, too many"});
b.push({"front":"parler","back":"to speak"});
b.push({"front":"le père","back":"father"});
b.push({"front":"la personne","back":"person, people, anybody, anyone, nobody"});
b.push({"front":"après","back":"after"});
b.push({"front":"ouais","back":"yeah"});
b.push({"front":"le dieu","back":"god"});
b.push({"front":"un homme","back":"man"});
b.push({"front":"la femme","back":"woman, wife"});
b.push({"front":"leur","back":"them, their, theirs"});
b.push({"front":"vrai","back":"true"});
b.push({"front":"mal","back":"bad"});
b.push({"front":"chez","back":"at, with; home"});
b.push({"front":"depuis","back":"since, for"});
b.push({"front":"déjà","back":"already"});
b.push({"front":"beaucoup","back":"a lot of, many"});
b.push({"front":"le mort, la mort","back":"dead; death"});
b.push({"front":"le mieux","back":"better"});
b.push({"front":"la mère","back":"mother"});
b.push({"front":"la fille","back":"girl, daughter"});
b.push({"front":"le gens","back":"people"});
b.push({"front":"quel","back":"which, what"});
b.push({"front":"voilà","back":"right, there, here"});
b.push({"front":"le petit","back":"small, little"});
b.push({"front":"la maison","back":"house"});
b.push({"front":"soit","back":"either...or"});
b.push({"front":"le soir","back":"evening"});
b.push({"front":"cela","back":"that, it"});
b.push({"front":"le passé","back":"past"});
b.push({"front":"le jour","back":"day"});
b.push({"front":"prendre","back":"to take"});
b.push({"front":"le monsieur","back":"mister, sir, gentleman"});
b.push({"front":"savoir","back":"to know"});
b.push({"front":"un argent","back":"money; silver"});
b.push({"front":"le salut","back":"salute, hi, bye"});
b.push({"front":"le nom","back":"name"});
b.push({"front":"la nuit","back":"night"});
b.push({"front":"le bonjour","back":"hello"});
b.push({"front":"la raison","back":"reason"});
b.push({"front":"le moins","back":"less"});
b.push({"front":"la maman","back":"mom"});
b.push({"front":"le reste","back":"rest"});
b.push({"front":"un air","back":"air, appearance"});
b.push({"front":"seul","back":"alone, only"});
b.push({"front":"le moment","back":"moment"});
b.push({"front":"aider","back":"to help, assist"});
b.push({"front":"le papa","back":"dad, daddy"});
b.push({"front":"entre","back":"between"});
b.push({"front":"le passe, la passe","back":"pass, channel"});
b.push({"front":"le problème","back":"problem"});
b.push({"front":"la peur","back":"fear"});
b.push({"front":"le gars","back":"guy"});
b.push({"front":"le fils","back":"son"});
b.push({"front":"eh","back":"hey, uh"});
b.push({"front":"trois","back":"three"});
b.push({"front":"assez","back":"enough"});
b.push({"front":"la famille","back":"family"});
b.push({"front":"trouver","back":"to find"});
b.push({"front":"le travail","back":"work"});
b.push({"front":"la tête","back":"head"});
b.push({"front":"ah","back":"ah, oh"});
b.push({"front":"la voiture","back":"car"});
b.push({"front":"vite","back":"fast, quickly"});
b.push({"front":"partir","back":"to leave"});
b.push({"front":"hé","back":"hey"});
b.push({"front":"la merde","back":"sh*t, crap"});
b.push({"front":"tuer","back":"to kill"});
b.push({"front":"la chance","back":"luck; chance"});
b.push({"front":"le pendant","back":"during"});
b.push({"front":"une idée","back":"idea"});
b.push({"front":"le part, la part","back":"share"});
b.push({"front":"demain","back":"tomorrow"});
b.push({"front":"grand","back":"great, big, tall"});
b.push({"front":"un ami","back":"friend"});
b.push({"front":"venir","back":"to come"});
b.push({"front":"tard","back":"late"});
b.push({"front":"le mec","back":"guy"});
b.push({"front":"hein","back":"eh, huh"});
b.push({"front":"passer","back":"to pass"});
b.push({"front":"le truc","back":"trick; thing"});
b.push({"front":"tant","back":"so much, so many"});
b.push({"front":"combien","back":"how much, how many"});
b.push({"front":"le sens","back":"sense, meaning"});
b.push({"front":"puis","back":"then, so"});
b.push({"front":"la porte","back":"door"});
b.push({"front":"super","back":"great"});
b.push({"front":"sortir","back":"to go out, leave"});
b.push({"front":"une heure","back":"hour"});
b.push({"front":"contre","back":"against"});
b.push({"front":"le coup","back":"coup, blow, knock, stroke"});
b.push({"front":"ensemble","back":"together"});
b.push({"front":"nouveau","back":"new"});
b.push({"front":"un amour","back":"love"});
b.push({"front":"le sang","back":"blood"});
b.push({"front":"sous","back":"under"});
b.push({"front":"le cas","back":"case"});
b.push({"front":"rester","back":"to stay"});
b.push({"front":"la question","back":"question"});
b.push({"front":"la partie","back":"part"});
b.push({"front":"une histoire","back":"history, story"});
b.push({"front":"chercher","back":"to look for"});
b.push({"front":"seulement","back":"only"});
b.push({"front":"la police","back":"police"});
b.push({"front":"un aide, une aide","back":"help, assistance"});
b.push({"front":"la demande","back":"request, demand"});
b.push({"front":"le genre","back":"type, kind, sort"});
b.push({"front":"le mois","back":"month"});
b.push({"front":"le frère","back":"brother"});
b.push({"front":"laisser","back":"to leave, to let"});
b.push({"front":"le car","back":"because; bus"});
b.push({"front":"mettre","back":"to put, place"});
b.push({"front":"aucun","back":"none, either, neither, not any"});
b.push({"front":"eux","back":"them"});
b.push({"front":"la ville","back":"city"});
b.push({"front":"chaque","back":"each"});
b.push({"front":"arrivé","back":"arrived"});
b.push({"front":"le bébé","back":"baby"});
b.push({"front":"longtemps","back":"a long time, a long while"});
b.push({"front":"la putain","back":"whore, bitch; stupid"});
b.push({"front":"revoir","back":"to see again, revise"});
b.push({"front":"la place","back":"room, space, square, place"});
b.push({"front":"ni","back":"nor"});
b.push({"front":"une attention","back":"attention"});
b.push({"front":"voici","back":"here is, here are, this is, these are"});
b.push({"front":"une affaire","back":"business, matter"});
b.push({"front":"donner","back":"to give"});
b.push({"front":"le type","back":"type; guy"});
b.push({"front":"le train","back":"train"});
b.push({"front":"le corps","back":"body"});
b.push({"front":"un endroit","back":"place, spot"});
b.push({"front":"la façon","back":"way, manner"});
b.push({"front":"une écoute","back":"listening"});
b.push({"front":"dont","back":"whose, of which"});
b.push({"front":"le premier","back":"first"});
b.push({"front":"perdu","back":"lost, stray, wasted"});
b.push({"front":"la main","back":"hand"});
b.push({"front":"le côté","back":"side"});
b.push({"front":"pouvoir","back":"can, to be able to"});
b.push({"front":"le vieux","back":"old"});
b.push({"front":"tiens","back":"ah, well"});
b.push({"front":"le matin","back":"morning"});
b.push({"front":"tellement","back":"so much, indeed"});
b.push({"front":"un enfant, une enfant","back":"child"});
b.push({"front":"le point","back":"point; at all"});
b.push({"front":"venu","back":"come"});
b.push({"front":"la suite","back":"result, follow-up, rest"});
b.push({"front":"le pardon","back":"forgiveness"});
b.push({"front":"le devant","back":"in front, ahead"});
b.push({"front":"le vers","back":"toward"});
b.push({"front":"la chambre","back":"bedroom, chamber"});
b.push({"front":"le droit","back":"right"});
b.push({"front":"le mari, la mari","back":"husband"});
b.push({"front":"la cause","back":"cause"});
b.push({"front":"enfin","back":"at last, finally"});
b.push({"front":"une eau","back":"water"});
b.push({"front":"le parti","back":"political party; gone"});
b.push({"front":"le boulot","back":"work, job"});
b.push({"front":"arrêter","back":"to stop, arrest"});
b.push({"front":"la terre","back":"earth, world, soil, land"});
b.push({"front":"le compte","back":"account, count"});
b.push({"front":"loin","back":"far"});
b.push({"front":"le fin, la fin","back":"end; gist; clever person"});
b.push({"front":"croire","back":"to believe"});
b.push({"front":"gros","back":"big"});
b.push({"front":"plutôt","back":"rather"});
b.push({"front":"jouer","back":"to play"});
b.push({"front":"le bureau","back":"office, desk"});
b.push({"front":"hier","back":"yesterday"});
b.push({"front":"le prêt","back":"ready"});
b.push({"front":"mourir","back":"to die"});
b.push({"front":"celui","back":"that, the one, he, him"});
b.push({"front":"demander","back":"to ask for"});
b.push({"front":"possible","back":"possible"});
b.push({"front":"le jeune, la jeune","back":"young"});
b.push({"front":"le dehors","back":"outside"});
b.push({"front":"euh","back":"er, um, uh"});
b.push({"front":"une école","back":"school"});
b.push({"front":"beau","back":"handsome, fine, right"});
b.push({"front":"appeler","back":"to call"});
b.push({"front":"la semaine","back":"week"});
b.push({"front":"le propos","back":"remark, about"});
b.push({"front":"la vérité","back":"truth"});
b.push({"front":"le chef","back":"head, leader, chief"});
b.push({"front":"la confiance","back":"confidence, trust"});
b.push({"front":"le feu","back":"fire"});
b.push({"front":"vivre","back":"to live"});
b.push({"front":"le docteur","back":"doctor"});
b.push({"front":"la journée","back":"day"});
b.push({"front":"près","back":"near, nearby, close by"});
b.push({"front":"la madame","back":"madam, lady"});
b.push({"front":"le meilleur","back":"better, best"});
b.push({"front":"le dessus","back":"above, on top"});
b.push({"front":"le téléphone","back":"telephone"});
b.push({"front":"le dur","back":"hard"});
b.push({"front":"manger","back":"to eat"});
b.push({"front":"le garçon","back":"boy"});
b.push({"front":"le mariage","back":"marriage"});
b.push({"front":"une équipe","back":"team"});
b.push({"front":"arriver","back":"to arrive, happen"});
b.push({"front":"la marche","back":"walk, step, march"});
b.push({"front":"la guerre","back":"war"});
b.push({"front":"le derrière","back":"last; behind"});
b.push({"front":"plein","back":"full"});
b.push({"front":"important","back":"important"});
b.push({"front":"le fort","back":"strong"});
b.push({"front":"exactement","back":"exactly"});
b.push({"front":"presque","back":"almost"});
b.push({"front":"dernier","back":"last, previous"});
b.push({"front":"le fou","back":"mad, crazy"});
b.push({"front":"la fête","back":"holiday, celebration"});
b.push({"front":"tomber","back":"to fall"});
b.push({"front":"attendre","back":"to wait"});
b.push({"front":"la sécurité","back":"security, safety"});
b.push({"front":"la vue","back":"view"});
b.push({"front":"le jeu","back":"game"});
b.push({"front":"génial","back":"inspired, great, brilliant"});
b.push({"front":"une envie","back":"envy, desire"});
b.push({"front":"le capitaine","back":"captain"});
b.push({"front":"le pays","back":"country"});
b.push({"front":"le garde, la garde","back":"guard"});
b.push({"front":"le cours, la cours","back":"course"});
b.push({"front":"le numéro","back":"number"});
b.push({"front":"bientôt","back":"soon"});
b.push({"front":"cinq","back":"five"});
b.push({"front":"le parfait","back":"perfect"});
b.push({"front":"la minute","back":"minute"});
b.push({"front":"ainsi","back":"thus"});
b.push({"front":"autant","back":"as much, as many"});
b.push({"front":"le retour","back":"return"});
b.push({"front":"la peine","back":"effort, trouble"});
b.push({"front":"un instant","back":"instant, moment"});
b.push({"front":"mauvais","back":"bad, wrong"});
b.push({"front":"une arme","back":"weapon"});
b.push({"front":"le prison, la prison","back":"prison"});
b.push({"front":"penser","back":"to think"});
b.push({"front":"le mot","back":"word"});
b.push({"front":"le film","back":"film"});
b.push({"front":"quatre","back":"four"});
b.push({"front":"essayer","back":"to try"});
b.push({"front":"rentrer","back":"to go in, come in, come back, return"});
b.push({"front":"le plan","back":"plan"});
b.push({"front":"travailler","back":"to work"});
b.push({"front":"regarder","back":"to look, watch"});
b.push({"front":"parfois","back":"sometimes"});
b.push({"front":"la faute","back":"mistake, error, fault"});
b.push({"front":"le choix","back":"choice"});
b.push({"front":"le bas","back":"low; stockings"});
b.push({"front":"heureux","back":"happy, lucky, fortunate"});
b.push({"front":"facile","back":"easy"});
b.push({"front":"entendre","back":"to hear"});
b.push({"front":"changer","back":"to change"});
b.push({"front":"le lit","back":"bed"});
b.push({"front":"entrer","back":"to enter, go in, come in"});
b.push({"front":"le plaisir","back":"pleasure"});
b.push({"front":"ensuite","back":"next, following"});
b.push({"front":"propre","back":"clean, proper, own"});
b.push({"front":"la route","back":"road"});
b.push({"front":"le tour, la tour","back":"tower; turn; tour"});
b.push({"front":"garder","back":"to keep"});
b.push({"front":"une année","back":"year"});
b.push({"front":"drôle","back":"funny, strange"});
b.push({"front":"le service","back":"service"});
b.push({"front":"rendre","back":"to render, return, yield, give up"});
b.push({"front":"un agent, une agent","back":"agent"});
b.push({"front":"le lieu","back":"the place"});
b.push({"front":"devoir","back":"to have to, owe; duty"});
b.push({"front":"le sujet","back":"subject, topic"});
b.push({"front":"difficile","back":"difficult"});
b.push({"front":"le pire","back":"worse, worst"});
b.push({"front":"la sorte","back":"sort, kind"});
b.push({"front":"ceci","back":"this"});
b.push({"front":"un état","back":"state"});
b.push({"front":"bizarre","back":"strange, odd"});
b.push({"front":"le chien","back":"dog"});
b.push({"front":"perdre","back":"to lose"});
b.push({"front":"impossible","back":"impossible"});
b.push({"front":"tôt","back":"early"});
b.push({"front":"dès","back":"from, as soon"});
b.push({"front":"payer","back":"to pay"});
b.push({"front":"le calme","back":"calm"});
b.push({"front":"le café","back":"coffee, café"});
b.push({"front":"le verre","back":"glass, cup"});
b.push({"front":"la ferme","back":"farm; firm"});
b.push({"front":"la photo","back":"photo"});
b.push({"front":"sûrement","back":"surely"});
b.push({"front":"montrer","back":"to show"});
b.push({"front":"le cœur","back":"heart"});
b.push({"front":"le meurtre","back":"murder"});
b.push({"front":"un hôpital","back":"hospital"});
b.push({"front":"la musique","back":"music"});
b.push({"front":"un avis","back":"opinion, mind"});
b.push({"front":"sauf","back":"except; safe"});
b.push({"front":"le courant","back":"current"});
b.push({"front":"le doute, la doute","back":"doubt"});
b.push({"front":"la seconde","back":"second"});
b.push({"front":"sérieux","back":"serious"});
b.push({"front":"le marché","back":"market"});
b.push({"front":"le gentil","back":"nice, kind"});
b.push({"front":"un haut","back":"top, high"});
b.push({"front":"le malade, la malade","back":"ill, sick"});
b.push({"front":"dîner","back":"dinner; to dine"});
b.push({"front":"un esprit","back":"mind, spirit"});
b.push({"front":"le moyen","back":"means, way; medium"});
b.push({"front":"le six","back":"six"});
b.push({"front":"la salle","back":"the room, the hall"});
b.push({"front":"comprendre","back":"to understand"});
b.push({"front":"sauver","back":"to rescue, save"});
b.push({"front":"le cul","back":"bum, arse, ass"});
b.push({"front":"le seigneur","back":"lord"});
b.push({"front":"le simple","back":"simple"});
b.push({"front":"le bras","back":"arm"});
b.push({"front":"le chéri","back":"darling, love, dear"});
b.push({"front":"partout","back":"everywhere"});
b.push({"front":"le visage","back":"face"});
b.push({"front":"le chemin","back":"path, way"});
b.push({"front":"le retard","back":"delay"});
b.push({"front":"la soirée","back":"evening, party"});
b.push({"front":"un écrit","back":"writing"});
b.push({"front":"le livre, la livre","back":"book"});
b.push({"front":"la face","back":"front, side, face"});
b.push({"front":"boire","back":"to drink"});
b.push({"front":"le surtout","back":"especially, above all"});
b.push({"front":"le bois","back":"wood"});
b.push({"front":"la joue","back":"cheek"});
b.push({"front":"le rapport","back":"relationship, report"});
b.push({"front":"le message","back":"message"});
b.push({"front":"le pauvre","back":"poor"});
b.push({"front":"une erreur","back":"mistake, error"});
b.push({"front":"sinon","back":"otherwise, or else"});
b.push({"front":"un honneur","back":"honor"});
b.push({"front":"rencontrer","back":"to meet"});
b.push({"front":"un an","back":"year"});
b.push({"front":"devenir","back":"to become"});
b.push({"front":"souvent","back":"often"});
b.push({"front":"revenir","back":"to come back"});
b.push({"front":"messieurs","back":"gentlemen"});
b.push({"front":"le sort","back":"fate, curse"});
b.push({"front":"la pièce","back":"piece, part, component; room"});
b.push({"front":"dormir","back":"to sleep"});
b.push({"front":"la grave","back":"serious, grave"});
b.push({"front":"commencer","back":"to begin, start"});
b.push({"front":"le roi","back":"king"});
b.push({"front":"le groupe","back":"group"});
b.push({"front":"la carte","back":"card, map"});
b.push({"front":"un intérieur","back":"interior, inside"});
b.push({"front":"le reçu","back":"receipt, accepted"});
b.push({"front":"le rêve","back":"dream"});
b.push({"front":"bonsoir","back":"good evening"});
b.push({"front":"le faux, la faux","back":"false; scythe"});
b.push({"front":"le manque, la manque","back":"lack"});
b.push({"front":"un appel","back":"call"});
b.push({"front":"le sac","back":"bag, sack"});
b.push({"front":"content","back":"glad, pleased, happy"});
b.push({"front":"cher","back":"expensive"});
b.push({"front":"le président","back":"president"});
b.push({"front":"acheter","back":"to buy"});
b.push({"front":"le début","back":"the beginning"});
b.push({"front":"le secret","back":"secret"});
b.push({"front":"le maître","back":"master"});
b.push({"front":"la venue","back":"coming"});
b.push({"front":"le patron","back":"boss"});
b.push({"front":"la rue","back":"street"});
b.push({"front":"occuper","back":"to occupy"});
b.push({"front":"le âge","back":"age"});
b.push({"front":"le prix","back":"price; prize"});
b.push({"front":"gagner","back":"to win, earn"});
b.push({"front":"un effet","back":"effect"});
b.push({"front":"tirer","back":"to pull, fire"});
b.push({"front":"un avocat","back":"lawyer"});
b.push({"front":"la grâce","back":"thanks, grace, favour"});
b.push({"front":"la voix","back":"voice"});
b.push({"front":"le général","back":"general"});
b.push({"front":"le noir","back":"black"});
b.push({"front":"long","back":"long, lengthy"});
b.push({"front":"apprendre","back":"to learn"});
b.push({"front":"dix","back":"ten"});
b.push({"front":"un accident","back":"accident"});
b.push({"front":"probablement","back":"probably"});
b.push({"front":"le bout","back":"bit, tip, end"});
b.push({"front":"un ordre","back":"order"});
b.push({"front":"incroyable","back":"incredible, unbelievable"});
b.push({"front":"la scène","back":"scene"});
b.push({"front":"le voyage","back":"trip, journey"});
b.push({"front":"retrouver","back":"to find, recall"});
b.push({"front":"la force","back":"force"});
b.push({"front":"simplement","back":"simply"});
b.push({"front":"ailleurs","back":"elsewhere, somewhere else"});
b.push({"front":"la situation","back":"situation"});
b.push({"front":"protéger","back":"to protect"});
b.push({"front":"un hôtel","back":"hotel"});
b.push({"front":"utiliser","back":"to use"});
b.push({"front":"la sœur","back":"sister"});
b.push({"front":"le complètement","back":"completely"});
b.push({"front":"le crime","back":"crime"});
b.push({"front":"le dos","back":"back"});
b.push({"front":"un idiot","back":"idiot, fool, stupid"});
b.push({"front":"une armée","back":"army"});
b.push({"front":"la sale","back":"dirty"});
b.push({"front":"la liste","back":"list"});
b.push({"front":"un anniversaire","back":"anniversary, birthday"});
b.push({"front":"un oncle","back":"uncle"});
b.push({"front":"la victime","back":"victim"});
b.push({"front":"un arrêté","back":"decree, order"});
b.push({"front":"la paix","back":"peace"});
b.push({"front":"battre","back":"to beat, hit"});
b.push({"front":"absolument","back":"absolutely"});
b.push({"front":"finir","back":"to finish"});
b.push({"front":"libre","back":"free"});
b.push({"front":"un avion","back":"plane"});
b.push({"front":"le rouge","back":"red"});
b.push({"front":"retourner","back":"to return, go back"});
b.push({"front":"réussi","back":"successful"});
b.push({"front":"le bateau","back":"boat, ship"});
b.push({"front":"stupide","back":"stupid, silly, bemused"});
b.push({"front":"le médecin, la médecin","back":"physician, doctor"});
b.push({"front":"la balle","back":"ball, bullet"});
b.push({"front":"la faim","back":"hungry"});
b.push({"front":"le contrôle","back":"control"});
b.push({"front":"la table","back":"table"});
b.push({"front":"le fond","back":"bottom"});
b.push({"front":"le bordel","back":"brothel, mess, chaos"});
b.push({"front":"une habitude","back":"habit"});
b.push({"front":"une impression","back":"impression"});
b.push({"front":"la surprise","back":"surprise"});
b.push({"front":"porter","back":"to wear, carry"});
b.push({"front":"un autour","back":"around"});
b.push({"front":"la colère","back":"anger"});
b.push({"front":"un or","back":"gold; hence, thus"});
b.push({"front":"la ligne","back":"line"});
b.push({"front":"magnifique","back":"magnificent"});
b.push({"front":"le gauche, la gauche","back":"left"});
b.push({"front":"le clair","back":"clear"});
b.push({"front":"neuf","back":"nine; new"});
b.push({"front":"le cadeau","back":"present, gift"});
b.push({"front":"le risque","back":"risk"});
b.push({"front":"le système","back":"system"});
b.push({"front":"un inspecteur","back":"inspector"});
b.push({"front":"hors","back":"except, outside"});
b.push({"front":"le dedans, la dedans","back":"inside, indoors"});
b.push({"front":"expliquer","back":"to explain"});
b.push({"front":"une espèce","back":"species"});
b.push({"front":"la montre","back":"watch"});
b.push({"front":"le pied","back":"foot"});
b.push({"front":"le présent","back":"present; gift"});
b.push({"front":"plusieurs","back":"several"});
b.push({"front":"marcher","back":"to walk"});
b.push({"front":"la lumière","back":"light"});
b.push({"front":"la réponse","back":"the answer, the response"});
b.push({"front":"le coin","back":"corner"});
b.push({"front":"suivre","back":"to follow"});
b.push({"front":"la moitié","back":"half"});
b.push({"front":"le club","back":"club"});
b.push({"front":"pareil","back":"similar, likewise; peer, equal"});
b.push({"front":"joli","back":"pretty, attractive"});
b.push({"front":"le camp","back":"camp"});
b.push({"front":"vouloir","back":"to want"});
b.push({"front":"envoyer","back":"to send"});
b.push({"front":"la mission","back":"mission"});
b.push({"front":"le soleil","back":"sun"});
b.push({"front":"selon","back":"according to"});
b.push({"front":"un arrière","back":"back, rear"});
b.push({"front":"lire","back":"to read; lira"});
b.push({"front":"doucement","back":"gently, softly"});
b.push({"front":"tenir","back":"to hold"});
b.push({"front":"la sortie","back":"the exit"});
b.push({"front":"exact","back":"exact, correct"});
b.push({"front":"la recherche","back":"research, search"});
b.push({"front":"continuer","back":"to continue"});
b.push({"front":"poser","back":"to put, pose, ask"});
b.push({"front":"le chaud","back":"warm, hot"});
b.push({"front":"la lettre","back":"letter"});
b.push({"front":"le tueur","back":"killer, hit man"});
b.push({"front":"une avance","back":"advance"});
b.push({"front":"une arrivée","back":"arrival"});
b.push({"front":"le bar","back":"bar"});
b.push({"front":"quitter","back":"to leave"});
b.push({"front":"connaître","back":"to know"});
b.push({"front":"la loi","back":"law"});
b.push({"front":"le gamin","back":"kid"});
b.push({"front":"le professeur, la professeur","back":"professor, teacher"});
b.push({"front":"le froid","back":"cold"});
b.push({"front":"la forme","back":"form"});
b.push({"front":"normal","back":"normal"});
b.push({"front":"le but","back":"goal, aim, objective, purpose"});
b.push({"front":"une offre","back":"offer"});
b.push({"front":"le conseil","back":"advice, counsel, council"});
b.push({"front":"debout","back":"standing"});
b.push({"front":"dangereux","back":"dangerous"});
b.push({"front":"tranquille","back":"quiet"});
b.push({"front":"la boîte","back":"box"});
b.push({"front":"le ciel","back":"sky"});
b.push({"front":"la classe","back":"class"});
b.push({"front":"le danger","back":"danger"});
b.push({"front":"une enquête","back":"inquiry, enquiry, investigation"});
b.push({"front":"la télé","back":"TV"});
b.push({"front":"oublier","back":"to forget"});
b.push({"front":"la visite","back":"visit"});
b.push({"front":"le juge, la juge","back":"judge"});
b.push({"front":"le poste, la poste","back":"post, position; post office"});
b.push({"front":"une attaque","back":"attack"});
b.push({"front":"la touche","back":"button, key, touch, touchline"});
b.push({"front":"la droite","back":"right"});
b.push({"front":"triste","back":"sad"});
b.push({"front":"aimer","back":"to like, love"});
b.push({"front":"le vivant","back":"alive, living"});
b.push({"front":"coucher","back":"to lie down, sleep"});
b.push({"front":"la tombe","back":"grave, tomb"});
b.push({"front":"la preuve","back":"proof"});
b.push({"front":"la dame","back":"lady"});
b.push({"front":"le flic, la flic","back":"cop"});
b.push({"front":"écouter","back":"to listen to"});
b.push({"front":"la cuisine","back":"cooking, kitchen"});
b.push({"front":"la relation","back":"relationship"});
b.push({"front":"le dossier","back":"file, record; case"});
b.push({"front":"sentir","back":"to feel, smell"});
b.push({"front":"le blanc","back":"white"});
b.push({"front":"la chanson","back":"song"});
b.push({"front":"la gueule","back":"mouth, trap"});
b.push({"front":"foutre","back":"to f*ck, shove off"});
b.push({"front":"la santé","back":"health"});
b.push({"front":"déjeuner","back":"lunch; to have lunch"});
b.push({"front":"pourtant","back":"yet, nonetheless, nevertheless"});
b.push({"front":"le change","back":"exchange"});
b.push({"front":"le travers","back":"breadth, across; fault, amiss"});
b.push({"front":"ouvrir","back":"to open"});
b.push({"front":"la âme","back":"soul"});
b.push({"front":"voler","back":"to steal, rob; fly"});
b.push({"front":"le centre","back":"center"});
b.push({"front":"chacun","back":"each"});
b.push({"front":"le lieutenant","back":"lieutenant"});
b.push({"front":"le certain","back":"certain, sure"});
b.push({"front":"la compagnie","back":"company"});
b.push({"front":"la clé","back":"key"});
b.push({"front":"la manière","back":"manner, way"});
b.push({"front":"différent","back":"different"});
b.push({"front":"le bord","back":"edge, side"});
b.push({"front":"la décision","back":"decision"});
b.push({"front":"vendre","back":"to sell"});
b.push({"front":"un enfer","back":"hell"});
b.push({"front":"le diable","back":"devil"});
b.push({"front":"un appartement","back":"appartment, flat"});
b.push({"front":"étrange","back":"strange, odd"});
b.push({"front":"monter","back":"to go up, rise, assemble"});
b.push({"front":"le signe","back":"sign"});
b.push({"front":"la bouche","back":"mouth"});
b.push({"front":"écrire","back":"to write"});
b.push({"front":"le cheval","back":"horse"});
b.push({"front":"le responsable, la responsable","back":"responsible"});
b.push({"front":"le coupable, la coupable","back":"guilty"});
b.push({"front":"une honte","back":"shame"});
b.push({"front":"emmener","back":"to take (a person, from a place)"});
b.push({"front":"le soin","back":"care"});
b.push({"front":"le milieu","back":"middle"});
b.push({"front":"le prochain","back":"next"});
b.push({"front":"rire","back":"to laugh"});
b.push({"front":"le cerveau","back":"brain"});
b.push({"front":"la voie","back":"road, lane, route, track, way"});
b.push({"front":"un amoureux","back":"in love, amorous"});
b.push({"front":"le silence","back":"silence"});
b.push({"front":"la drogue","back":"drug"});
b.push({"front":"la blague","back":"joke"});
b.push({"front":"le trou","back":"hole"});
b.push({"front":"un intérêt","back":"interest"});
b.push({"front":"tel","back":"such"});
b.push({"front":"le public","back":"public, audience"});
b.push({"front":"la réunion","back":"meeting"});
b.push({"front":"capable","back":"able, capable"});
b.push({"front":"le client","back":"client"});
b.push({"front":"une époque","back":"era, period"});
b.push({"front":"la prise","back":"grip, hold, seizure, catch"});
b.push({"front":"une adresse","back":"address"});
b.push({"front":"cacher","back":"to hide"});
b.push({"front":"le combat","back":"fight, combat"});
b.push({"front":"la peau","back":"skin"});
b.push({"front":"le blessé","back":"injured"});
b.push({"front":"la robe","back":"dress"});
b.push({"front":"la fiche","back":"card, sheet, slip, form"});
b.push({"front":"la bière","back":"beer; coffin"});
b.push({"front":"le colonel","back":"colonel"});
b.push({"front":"lequel","back":"who, whom, which"});
b.push({"front":"le don","back":"gift, talent"});
b.push({"front":"le journal","back":"newspaper, paper"});
b.push({"front":"la société","back":"society"});
b.push({"front":"sept","back":"seven"});
b.push({"front":"le contact","back":"contact"});
b.push({"front":"la base","back":"base"});
b.push({"front":"le vin","back":"wine"});
b.push({"front":"servir","back":"to serve"});
b.push({"front":"un exemple","back":"example"});
b.push({"front":"jeter","back":"to throw"});
b.push({"front":"la mer","back":"sea"});
b.push({"front":"le tort","back":"wrong"});
b.push({"front":"ouvert","back":"open"});
b.push({"front":"récupérer","back":"to get back, recover, recuperate"});
b.push({"front":"le dommage","back":"damage, harm; too bad"});
b.push({"front":"le gouvernement","back":"government"});
b.push({"front":"le vol","back":"flight, theft"});
b.push({"front":"le nez","back":"nose"});
b.push({"front":"un héros","back":"hero"});
b.push({"front":"horrible","back":"horrible, terrible, dreadful, hideous"});
b.push({"front":"prévu","back":"planned, expected"});
b.push({"front":"une enceinte","back":"pregnant; enclosure"});
b.push({"front":"le secours","back":"help, aid, assistance"});
b.push({"front":"une entrée","back":"entrance"});
b.push({"front":"une opération","back":"operation"});
b.push({"front":"le témoin","back":"witness"});
b.push({"front":"environ","back":"about, thereabouts, or so"});
b.push({"front":"répondre","back":"to answer"});
b.push({"front":"le départ","back":"departure"});
b.push({"front":"la danse","back":"dance, dancing"});
b.push({"front":"vérifier","back":"to check, verify"});
b.push({"front":"la lune","back":"moon"});
b.push({"front":"le sexe","back":"sex"});
b.push({"front":"la justice","back":"justice"});
b.push({"front":"terrible","back":"terrible, dreadful"});
b.push({"front":"le peuple","back":"people"});
b.push({"front":"le bruit","back":"noise"});
b.push({"front":"le commandant","back":"commander"});
b.push({"front":"intéressant","back":"interesting"});
b.push({"front":"le lycée","back":"high school"});
b.push({"front":"ramener","back":"to bring back, return, take back"});
b.push({"front":"la mise","back":"putting, placing"});
b.push({"front":"le radio, la radio","back":"radio"});
b.push({"front":"inutile","back":"useless"});
b.push({"front":"une excuse","back":"excuse, apology"});
b.push({"front":"le tas","back":"pile, lots of"});
b.push({"front":"la banque","back":"bank"});
b.push({"front":"apparemment","back":"apparently"});
b.push({"front":"baiser","back":"to kiss"});
b.push({"front":"la bête","back":"animal, beast; stupid"});
b.push({"front":"ridicule","back":"ridiculous, silly"});
b.push({"front":"un avenir","back":"future"});
b.push({"front":"le thé","back":"tea"});
b.push({"front":"la bande","back":"band, strip"});
b.push({"front":"le œil","back":"eye"});
b.push({"front":"plupart","back":"most, the majority"});
b.push({"front":"le procès","back":"trial, proceedings"});
b.push({"front":"le bravo","back":"bravo, well done"});
b.push({"front":"la position","back":"position"});
b.push({"front":"sérieusement","back":"seriously"});
b.push({"front":"la pitié","back":"pity, mercy"});
b.push({"front":"un humain","back":"human"});
b.push({"front":"une approche","back":"approach"});
b.push({"front":"la liberté","back":"liberty, freedom"});
b.push({"front":"le revenu","back":"income"});
b.push({"front":"un anglais","back":"English"});
b.push({"front":"la nourriture","back":"food"});
b.push({"front":"le nord","back":"north"});
b.push({"front":"le deuxième, la deuxième","back":"second"});
b.push({"front":"le vaisseau","back":"ship, vessel"});
b.push({"front":"éviter","back":"to avoid"});
b.push({"front":"la cour","back":"yard, court"});
b.push({"front":"le rôle","back":"role"});
b.push({"front":"une expérience","back":"experience"});
b.push({"front":"le match","back":"match, game"});
b.push({"front":"empêcher","back":"to prevent"});
b.push({"front":"le directeur","back":"director"});
b.push({"front":"le mur","back":"wall"});
b.push({"front":"conduire","back":"to lead, drive"});
b.push({"front":"la défense","back":"defense"});
b.push({"front":"la tante","back":"aunt"});
b.push({"front":"marier","back":"to marry"});
b.push({"front":"le vide","back":"empty"});
b.push({"front":"spécial","back":"special"});
b.push({"front":"le sud","back":"south"});
b.push({"front":"censé","back":"supposed"});
b.push({"front":"une église","back":"church"});
b.push({"front":"merveilleux","back":"marvellous, wonderful"});
b.push({"front":"huit","back":"eight"});
b.push({"front":"le sol","back":"floor, ground"});
b.push({"front":"excuser","back":"to excuse"});
b.push({"front":"le personnel","back":"personnel, personal"});
b.push({"front":"hum","back":"um, uh"});
b.push({"front":"la bombe","back":"bomb"});
b.push({"front":"le code","back":"code"});
b.push({"front":"le niveau","back":"level"});
b.push({"front":"la fenêtre","back":"window"});
b.push({"front":"le magasin","back":"store"});
b.push({"front":"asseoir","back":"to sit"});
b.push({"front":"la vidéo","back":"video"});
b.push({"front":"obtenir","back":"to get, obtain"});
b.push({"front":"la reine","back":"queen"});
b.push({"front":"un espoir","back":"hope"});
b.push({"front":"certainement","back":"certainly"});
b.push({"front":"la glace","back":"ice, ice cream; mirror"});
b.push({"front":"mien","back":"mine"});
b.push({"front":"la presse","back":"press"});
b.push({"front":"souvenir","back":"memory; to remember"});
b.push({"front":"le terrain","back":"ground, terrain"});
b.push({"front":"danser","back":"to dance"});
b.push({"front":"le quartier","back":"district, quarter"});
b.push({"front":"lorsque","back":"when"});
b.push({"front":"la douleur","back":"pain"});
b.push({"front":"le rose, la rose","back":"rose; pink"});
b.push({"front":"la zone","back":"zone, area"});
b.push({"front":"le spectacle","back":"the sight, the show"});
b.push({"front":"le proche, la proche","back":"nearby, close"});
b.push({"front":"présenter","back":"to present"});
b.push({"front":"honnête","back":"honest, decent, fair"});
b.push({"front":"le rapide","back":"fast, quick"});
b.push({"front":"le camion","back":"truck"});
b.push({"front":"le village","back":"village"});
b.push({"front":"une importance","back":"importance"});
b.push({"front":"nul","back":"nil, null"});
b.push({"front":"le mérite","back":"merit"});
b.push({"front":"assurer","back":"to assure, insure"});
b.push({"front":"fier","back":"to rely on; proud"});
b.push({"front":"prouver","back":"to prove"});
b.push({"front":"une occasion","back":"chance, opportunity"});
b.push({"front":"le projet","back":"project"});
b.push({"front":"la rencontre","back":"meeting"});
b.push({"front":"la machine","back":"machine"});
b.push({"front":"la parole","back":"word"});
b.push({"front":"le gosse, la gosse","back":"kid"});
b.push({"front":"un officier, une officier","back":"officer; officiate"});
b.push({"front":"discuter","back":"to discuss, debate; to question"});
b.push({"front":"remettre","back":"to deliver, replace, set, put"});
b.push({"front":"le copain","back":"friend, buddy, mate"});
b.push({"front":"le respect","back":"respect"});
b.push({"front":"épouser","back":"to marry, wed"});
b.push({"front":"la réalité","back":"reality"});
b.push({"front":"le portable","back":"portable, wearable; cell phone"});
b.push({"front":"choisir","back":"to choose"});
b.push({"front":"le programme","back":"program"});
b.push({"front":"rappeler","back":"to recall, call back"});
b.push({"front":"la planète","back":"planet"});
b.push({"front":"offrir","back":"to offer"});
b.push({"front":"la pression","back":"pressure"});
b.push({"front":"découvrir","back":"to discover"});
b.push({"front":"le court","back":"short"});
b.push({"front":"le bain","back":"bath, bathing"});
b.push({"front":"détruire","back":"to destroy"});
b.push({"front":"chanter","back":"to sing"});
b.push({"front":"la mademoiselle","back":"Miss"});
b.push({"front":"la charge","back":"to charge, load"});
b.push({"front":"énorme","back":"enormous"});
b.push({"front":"la nature","back":"nature"});
b.push({"front":"le monstre","back":"monster"});
b.push({"front":"riche","back":"rich"});
b.push({"front":"la solution","back":"solution"});
b.push({"front":"un envers","back":"towards"});
b.push({"front":"réfléchir","back":"to reflect (over a subject)"});
b.push({"front":"la pierre","back":"stone"});
b.push({"front":"le test","back":"test"});
b.push({"front":"enlever","back":"to remove"});
b.push({"front":"sauter","back":"to jump"});
b.push({"front":"préparer","back":"to prepare"});
b.push({"front":"le nécessaire","back":"necessary, required"});
b.push({"front":"le patient","back":"patient"});
b.push({"front":"finalement","back":"finally, eventually"});
b.push({"front":"immédiatement","back":"immediately"});
b.push({"front":"arranger","back":"to arrange"});
b.push({"front":"toucher","back":"to touch"});
b.push({"front":"le bus, la bus","back":"bus"});
b.push({"front":"un ennemi","back":"enemy"});
b.push({"front":"un invité","back":"guest"});
b.push({"front":"le suspect","back":"suspicious, suspect"});
b.push({"front":"le couteau","back":"knife"});
b.push({"front":"durant","back":"during, for"});
b.push({"front":"ancien","back":"ancient; former"});
b.push({"front":"le vent","back":"wind"});
b.push({"front":"le futur","back":"future"});
b.push({"front":"tourner","back":"to turn"});
b.push({"front":"le repas","back":"meal"});
b.push({"front":"un espace, une espace","back":"space"});
b.push({"front":"la taille","back":"the size, the height"});
b.push({"front":"la politique","back":"politics; political"});
b.push({"front":"le papier","back":"paper"});
b.push({"front":"accepter","back":"to accept"});
b.push({"front":"une université","back":"university"});
b.push({"front":"descendre","back":"to go down, come down"});
b.push({"front":"la conversation","back":"conversation"});
b.push({"front":"le contrat","back":"contract"});
b.push({"front":"le chat","back":"cat; chat"});
b.push({"front":"la beauté","back":"beauty"});
b.push({"front":"le double","back":"double"});
b.push({"front":"excellent","back":"excellent"});
b.push({"front":"un ordinateur","back":"computer"});
b.push({"front":"la course","back":"race, shopping"});
b.push({"front":"la carrière","back":"career"});
b.push({"front":"le mille","back":"a thousand"});
b.push({"front":"le bonheur","back":"happiness"});
b.push({"front":"le mémoire, la mémoire","back":"memory"});
b.push({"front":"le permis","back":"license, permit, permitted"});
b.push({"front":"le contraire","back":"opposite, contrary"});
b.push({"front":"une énergie","back":"energy"});
b.push({"front":"une urgence","back":"emergency"});
b.push({"front":"le taxi","back":"taxi"});
b.push({"front":"joyeux","back":"merry, joyful, happy"});
b.push({"front":"parmi","back":"among"});
b.push({"front":"le courage","back":"courage"});
b.push({"front":"la différence","back":"difference"});
b.push({"front":"le couple, la couple","back":"couple"});
b.push({"front":"le prince","back":"prince"});
b.push({"front":"la crise","back":"crisis"});
b.push({"front":"la série","back":"series"});
b.push({"front":"la piste","back":"track, trail"});
b.push({"front":"puisque","back":"since"});
b.push({"front":"une action","back":"action"});
b.push({"front":"la coupe","back":"bowl, dish, cut"});
b.push({"front":"la maladie","back":"illness, disease"});
b.push({"front":"la cible","back":"target"});
b.push({"front":"le restaurant","back":"restaurant"});
b.push({"front":"le fil","back":"thread, wire"});
b.push({"front":"un alcool","back":"alcohol"});
b.push({"front":"la caméra","back":"camera"});
b.push({"front":"lors","back":"at the time of"});
b.push({"front":"un accès","back":"access"});
b.push({"front":"pleurer","back":"to cry"});
b.push({"front":"totalement","back":"totally"});
b.push({"front":"remercier","back":"to thank"});
b.push({"front":"un entier","back":"whole, full"});
b.push({"front":"la couleur","back":"color"});
b.push({"front":"la île","back":"island"});
b.push({"front":"fermer","back":"to close, shut"});
b.push({"front":"le soldat","back":"soldier"});
b.push({"front":"un étage","back":"floor, level"});
b.push({"front":"amuser","back":"to amuse"});
b.push({"front":"régler","back":"to pay, adjust, settle"});
b.push({"front":"le frais","back":"cool, fresh; fee, expense"});
b.push({"front":"une image","back":"picture, image"});
b.push({"front":"la langue","back":"language, tongue"});
b.push({"front":"le suivi","back":"follow-up; consistent, continuous"});
b.push({"front":"la direction","back":"direction, management"});
b.push({"front":"mentir","back":"to lie"});
b.push({"front":"le salaud","back":"bastard"});
b.push({"front":"sacré","back":"sacred"});
b.push({"front":"le troisième, la troisième","back":"third"});
b.push({"front":"le poisson","back":"fish"});
b.push({"front":"frapper","back":"to hit, strike, knock"});
b.push({"front":"courir","back":"to run"});
b.push({"front":"bouger","back":"to move, shift, budge"});
b.push({"front":"rejoindre","back":"to rejoin, reunite"});
b.push({"front":"le bleu","back":"blue"});
b.push({"front":"un américain","back":"American"});
b.push({"front":"superbe","back":"superb, magnificient, handsome, gorgeous"});
b.push({"front":"le destin","back":"fate, destiny"});
b.push({"front":"le mark","back":"mark"});
b.push({"front":"le faible","back":"weak"});
b.push({"front":"le lait","back":"milk"});
b.push({"front":"un adieu","back":"goodbye, farewell, adieu"});
b.push({"front":"le pont","back":"bridge"});
b.push({"front":"le costume","back":"suit, costume, dress"});
b.push({"front":"le procureur","back":"prosecutor"});
b.push({"front":"attraper","back":"to catch, get, pick up"});
b.push({"front":"la princesse","back":"princess"});
b.push({"front":"le partenaire, la partenaire","back":"partner"});
b.push({"front":"un arrêt","back":"stop"});
b.push({"front":"le goût","back":"taste"});
b.push({"front":"sourire","back":"smile, to smile"});
b.push({"front":"la bouteille","back":"bottle"});
b.push({"front":"une intention","back":"intention"});
b.push({"front":"formidable","back":"tremendous, considerable"});
b.push({"front":"moindre","back":"lesser, least, slightest"});
b.push({"front":"unique","back":"unique"});
b.push({"front":"le tribunal","back":"court"});
b.push({"front":"le français","back":"French"});
b.push({"front":"la foi","back":"faith"});
b.push({"front":"un art","back":"art"});
b.push({"front":"évidemment","back":"obviously"});
b.push({"front":"la date","back":"date"});
b.push({"front":"la chasse","back":"chase, hunt, hunting"});
b.push({"front":"amener","back":"to bring someone (to a place)"});
b.push({"front":"un os","back":"bone"});
b.push({"front":"afin","back":"in order to, so that"});
b.push({"front":"le gâteau","back":"cake"});
b.push({"front":"le cou","back":"neck"});
b.push({"front":"couper","back":"to cut"});
b.push({"front":"ha","back":"oh"});
b.push({"front":"chier","back":"to sh*t, piss off, get pissed off"});
b.push({"front":"la pause","back":"break, pause"});
b.push({"front":"utile","back":"useful"});
b.push({"front":"la jambe","back":"leg"});
b.push({"front":"le bref","back":"brief"});
b.push({"front":"intelligent","back":"intelligent, clever, bright"});
b.push({"front":"le morceau","back":"piece, bit_"});
b.push({"front":"obligé","back":"necessary, required"});
b.push({"front":"la présence","back":"presence"});
b.push({"front":"le signal","back":"signal"});
b.push({"front":"raconter","back":"to tell"});
b.push({"front":"une identité","back":"identity"});
b.push({"front":"vendu","back":"sold, bribed"});
b.push({"front":"privé","back":"private"});
b.push({"front":"une entreprise","back":"enterprise, business"});
b.push({"front":"justement","back":"exactly, rightly, precisely"});
b.push({"front":"le cinéma","back":"cinema"});
b.push({"front":"le discours","back":"speech, talk, discourse"});
b.push({"front":"rapidement","back":"quickly, rapidly"});
b.push({"front":"le méchant","back":"nasty, wicked, mean"});
b.push({"front":"la campagne","back":"countryside"});
b.push({"front":"le regard","back":"look, glance"});
b.push({"front":"le lien","back":"link, bond"});
b.push({"front":"un appareil","back":"apparatus, device"});
b.push({"front":"un ange","back":"angel"});
b.push({"front":"le joie, la joie","back":"joy"});
b.push({"front":"compter","back":"to count"});
b.push({"front":"malgré","back":"despite, in spite of"});
b.push({"front":"reprendre","back":"to resume, recover, start again, take back"});
b.push({"front":"le nombre","back":"number"});
b.push({"front":"la star","back":"star"});
b.push({"front":"le chapeau","back":"hat"});
b.push({"front":"décider","back":"to decide"});
b.push({"front":"la menace","back":"threat"});
b.push({"front":"agir","back":"to act"});
b.push({"front":"le produit","back":"product"});
b.push({"front":"le vendredi","back":"Friday"});
b.push({"front":"malheureusement","back":"unfortunately"});
b.push({"front":"une odeur","back":"smell, odor"});
b.push({"front":"mince","back":"thin, slim, slender"});
b.push({"front":"fermé","back":"shut, closed, locked"});
b.push({"front":"une aise","back":"comfort, joy, pleasure, ease"});
b.push({"front":"la saison","back":"season"});
b.push({"front":"le succès","back":"success"});
b.push({"front":"gérer","back":"to manage"});
b.push({"front":"le pain","back":"bread"});
b.push({"front":"la règle","back":"rule"});
b.push({"front":"million","back":"million"});
b.push({"front":"parfaitement","back":"perfectly"});
b.push({"front":"le malin","back":"smart, shrewd, cunning"});
b.push({"front":"la majesté","back":"majesty"});
b.push({"front":"le toit","back":"roof"});
b.push({"front":"la faveur","back":"favor"});
b.push({"front":"doux","back":"soft, sweet"});
b.push({"front":"le coffre","back":"trunk, boot, chest"});
b.push({"front":"la couverture","back":"blanket"});
b.push({"front":"un arbre","back":"tree"});
b.push({"front":"réparer","back":"to repair, fix, correct, make up"});
b.push({"front":"un article","back":"article"});
b.push({"front":"lever","back":"to lift, raise"});
b.push({"front":"une unité","back":"unity; unit"});
b.push({"front":"un échange","back":"exchange"});
b.push({"front":"surpris","back":"surprised, amazed"});
b.push({"front":"le parc","back":"park"});
b.push({"front":"apporter","back":"to bring_"});
b.push({"front":"imaginer","back":"to imagine"});
b.push({"front":"le jardin","back":"garden"});
b.push({"front":"falloir","back":"to take, require, need"});
b.push({"front":"partager","back":"to share"});
b.push({"front":"la plage","back":"beach"});
b.push({"front":"échapper","back":"to escape"});
b.push({"front":"la valeur","back":"value, worth"});
b.push({"front":"également","back":"too, as well, equally"});
b.push({"front":"la folie","back":"madness, folly, insanity"});
b.push({"front":"le ministre, la ministre","back":"minister"});
b.push({"front":"le samedi","back":"Saturday"});
b.push({"front":"le mode, la mode","back":"mode, way, fashion"});
b.push({"front":"le maire, la maire","back":"mayor"});
b.push({"front":"un extérieur","back":"exterior"});
b.push({"front":"le génie","back":"genius"});
b.push({"front":"inquiéter","back":"to worry, disturb"});
b.push({"front":"recevoir","back":"to receive"});
b.push({"front":"un hasard","back":"chance, luck"});
b.push({"front":"un ouest","back":"west"});
b.push({"front":"le membre","back":"member"});
b.push({"front":"le réel","back":"real"});
b.push({"front":"le poids","back":"weight"});
b.push({"front":"prévenir","back":"to prevent, warn; to notify"});
b.push({"front":"la poche","back":"pocket"});
b.push({"front":"la vitesse","back":"speed"});
b.push({"front":"la frappe","back":"strike, striking, stamp, impression, punch"});
b.push({"front":"fantastique","back":"fantastic, terrific, great, weird, eerie"});
b.push({"front":"le fantôme","back":"ghost, phantom"});
b.push({"front":"la viande","back":"meat"});
b.push({"front":"le poulet","back":"chicken"});
b.push({"front":"le page, la page","back":"page"});
b.push({"front":"le trésor","back":"treasure, treasury"});
b.push({"front":"la file","back":"line, queue"});
b.push({"front":"abandonner","back":"to give up, abandon"});
b.push({"front":"embrasser","back":"to kiss, embrace"});
b.push({"front":"le dimanche","back":"Sunday"});
b.push({"front":"le passage","back":"passage, way"});
b.push({"front":"la naissance","back":"birth"});
b.push({"front":"amusant","back":"funny, amusing, entertaining"});
b.push({"front":"le cent","back":"one hundred, cent"});
b.push({"front":"la retraite","back":"retirement, pension"});
b.push({"front":"un étranger","back":"foreigner; foreign"});
b.push({"front":"le paradis","back":"paradise, heaven"});
b.push({"front":"directement","back":"directly"});
b.push({"front":"le champ","back":"field, realm"});
b.push({"front":"débarrasser","back":"to clear, get rid of"});
b.push({"front":"manquer","back":"to miss"});
b.push({"front":"le doigt","back":"finger"});
b.push({"front":"agréable","back":"pleasant, nice, agreeable"});
b.push({"front":"le changement","back":"change"});
b.push({"front":"un univers","back":"universe"});
b.push({"front":"le piège","back":"trap"});
b.push({"front":"la marque","back":"brand, mark"});
b.push({"front":"la perte","back":"the loss"});
b.push({"front":"créer","back":"to create"});
b.push({"front":"nettoyer","back":"to clean"});
b.push({"front":"la note","back":"note, grade"});
b.push({"front":"un animal","back":"animal"});
b.push({"front":"franchement","back":"frankly"});
b.push({"front":"le bâtiment","back":"building"});
b.push({"front":"le cancer","back":"cancer"});
b.push({"front":"heureusement","back":"fortunately, luckily"});
b.push({"front":"compliqué","back":"complicated, complex"});
b.push({"front":"la source","back":"source, spring"});
b.push({"front":"la connaissance","back":"knowledge"});
b.push({"front":"une émission","back":"transmission, broadcasting, programme"});
b.push({"front":"le mensonge","back":"the lie"});
b.push({"front":"joindre","back":"to join"});
b.push({"front":"convaincre","back":"to convince"});
b.push({"front":"nerveux","back":"nervous, irritable"});
b.push({"front":"le pantalon","back":"trousers, pants"});
b.push({"front":"vôtre","back":"yours"});
b.push({"front":"la bataille","back":"battle"});
b.push({"front":"la conscience","back":"conscience, consciousness"});
b.push({"front":"le sentiment","back":"the feel"});
b.push({"front":"le salon","back":"lounge, living room"});
b.push({"front":"le traitement","back":"treatment, salary, wage"});
b.push({"front":"la volonté","back":"will"});
b.push({"front":"un interdit","back":"prohibited, banned"});
b.push({"front":"direct","back":"direct"});
b.push({"front":"le cousin","back":"cousin"});
b.push({"front":"le souci","back":"worry, concern"});
b.push({"front":"la lance","back":"lance"});
b.push({"front":"signer","back":"to sign"});
b.push({"front":"contrôler","back":"to control, check, inspect, monitor"});
b.push({"front":"reposer","back":"to rest"});
b.push({"front":"le gaz","back":"gas"});
b.push({"front":"la victoire","back":"victory"});
b.push({"front":"la trace","back":"trace, mark, track"});
b.push({"front":"une information","back":"information"});
b.push({"front":"la queue","back":"tail, handle, stalk, stem, rear"});
b.push({"front":"désormais","back":"from now on, henceforth, now"});
b.push({"front":"un acte","back":"act"});
b.push({"front":"le paquet","back":"packet"});
b.push({"front":"le semblant","back":"semblance, pretence"});
b.push({"front":"le style","back":"style"});
b.push({"front":"un aéroport","back":"airport"});
b.push({"front":"supporter","back":"to support, endure"});
b.push({"front":"le chinois","back":"Chinese"});
b.push({"front":"innocent","back":"innocent"});
b.push({"front":"autrement","back":"differently, something else, otherwise"});
b.push({"front":"le suicide","back":"suicide"});
b.push({"front":"lancer","back":"to launch"});
b.push({"front":"la théorie","back":"theory"});
b.push({"front":"un immeuble","back":"building"});
b.push({"front":"le métier","back":"job, occupation, trade"});
b.push({"front":"un aveugle, une aveugle","back":"blind"});
b.push({"front":"la leçon","back":"lesson"});
b.push({"front":"le militaire","back":"military"});
b.push({"front":"la protection","back":"protection"});
b.push({"front":"le propriétaire, la propriétaire","back":"owner"});
b.push({"front":"le mandat","back":"term, mandate"});
b.push({"front":"la surveillance","back":"surveillance, monitoring"});
b.push({"front":"le pilote, la pilote","back":"pilot, experimental"});
b.push({"front":"fuir","back":"to flee"});
b.push({"front":"un oiseau","back":"bird"});
b.push({"front":"retirer","back":"to remove, withdraw"});
b.push({"front":"récemment","back":"recently"});
b.push({"front":"un assassin","back":"murderer, assassin"});
b.push({"front":"célèbre","back":"famous"});
b.push({"front":"défendre","back":"to defend, forbid"});
b.push({"front":"le vert","back":"green"});
b.push({"front":"une assurance","back":"insurance, confidence"});
b.push({"front":"charmant","back":"charming"});
b.push({"front":"la chemise","back":"shirt, folder"});
b.push({"front":"le ventre","back":"belly, stomach"});
b.push({"front":"le sport","back":"sport"});
b.push({"front":"un est","back":"east"});
b.push({"front":"commun","back":"common"});
b.push({"front":"atteindre","back":"to reach, to attain"});
b.push({"front":"virer","back":"to turn, change, transfer, kick out"});
b.push({"front":"la pluie","back":"rain"});
b.push({"front":"le talent","back":"talent"});
b.push({"front":"le jury","back":"jury, board of examiners"});
b.push({"front":"la commande","back":"order, control"});
b.push({"front":"la tente","back":"tent"});
b.push({"front":"la couche","back":"layer, coat"});
b.push({"front":"le voleur","back":"thief, light-fingered"});
b.push({"front":"le chocolat","back":"chocolate"});
b.push({"front":"réveiller","back":"to wake up"});
b.push({"front":"la souris","back":"mouse"});
b.push({"front":"accusé","back":"defendant"});
b.push({"front":"le terme","back":"term, deadline"});
b.push({"front":"un emploi","back":"employment, work, use"});
b.push({"front":"un ombre, une ombre","back":"shade, shadow"});
b.push({"front":"le repos","back":"rest"});
b.push({"front":"blesser","back":"to hurt"});
b.push({"front":"la neige","back":"snow"});
b.push({"front":"le lundi","back":"Monday"});
b.push({"front":"le théâtre","back":"theater"});
b.push({"front":"permettre","back":"to allow"});
b.push({"front":"le policier","back":"policeman"});
b.push({"front":"surveiller","back":"to watch"});
b.push({"front":"le saint","back":"saint, holy"});
b.push({"front":"la chaise","back":"chair"});
b.push({"front":"réfléchi","back":"thoughtful, well thought out"});
b.push({"front":"le site","back":"site"});
b.push({"front":"une hâte","back":"haste, impatience"});
b.push({"front":"le zéro","back":"zero"});
b.push({"front":"facilement","back":"easily"});
b.push({"front":"un épisode","back":"episode"});
b.push({"front":"le siège","back":"seat, bench"});
b.push({"front":"la traduction","back":"translation"});
b.push({"front":"la montagne","back":"mountain"});
b.push({"front":"la gorge","back":"throat"});
b.push({"front":"le sommeil","back":"sleep, sleepiness"});
b.push({"front":"la rivière","back":"river"});
b.push({"front":"le miracle","back":"miracle"});
b.push({"front":"le titre","back":"title"});
b.push({"front":"le second","back":"second"});
b.push({"front":"la cellule","back":"cell"});
b.push({"front":"le mouvement","back":"movement"});
b.push({"front":"la mine","back":"mine; appearance, look"});
b.push({"front":"clairement","back":"clearly"});
b.push({"front":"le choc","back":"shock, clash"});
b.push({"front":"la fortune","back":"fortune"});
b.push({"front":"le divorce","back":"divorce"});
b.push({"front":"un ours","back":"bear"});
b.push({"front":"exploser","back":"to explode, blow up"});
b.push({"front":"évident","back":"obvious"});
b.push({"front":"le minuit","back":"midnight"});
b.push({"front":"un examen","back":"exam"});
b.push({"front":"respirer","back":"to breath"});
b.push({"front":"le tableau","back":"frame, picture, painting, panel"});
b.push({"front":"le plat","back":"dish, flat"});
b.push({"front":"le meurtrier","back":"murderer, deadly, lethal"});
b.push({"front":"survivre","back":"to survive"});
b.push({"front":"auprès","back":"nearby, close to"});
b.push({"front":"le principal","back":"principal"});
b.push({"front":"la forêt","back":"forest"});
b.push({"front":"la violence","back":"violence"});
b.push({"front":"une amitié","back":"friendship"});
b.push({"front":"la blessure","back":"injury, wound"});
b.push({"front":"la distance","back":"distance"});
b.push({"front":"une humeur","back":"mood, temper"});
b.push({"front":"le modèle","back":"model"});
b.push({"front":"le démon","back":"demon, fiend"});
b.push({"front":"la puissance","back":"power"});
b.push({"front":"casser","back":"to break"});
b.push({"front":"le romantique, la romantique","back":"romantic"});
b.push({"front":"la responsabilité","back":"responsibility"});
b.push({"front":"le crédit","back":"credit"});
b.push({"front":"crier","back":"to shout, scream, cry out"});
b.push({"front":"le concert","back":"concert"});
b.push({"front":"pousser","back":"to push"});
b.push({"front":"le tir","back":"fire, shot, launch"});
b.push({"front":"la fuite","back":"the escape_"});
b.push({"front":"la gare","back":"station, railway station; beware"});
b.push({"front":"le midi","back":"noon"});
b.push({"front":"la permission","back":"permission, leave"});
b.push({"front":"le dessous","back":"underneath, below, bottom, underside"});
b.push({"front":"une explosion","back":"explosion"});
b.push({"front":"une annonce","back":"announcement"});
b.push({"front":"le secrétaire, la secrétaire","back":"secretary"});
b.push({"front":"le chauffeur","back":"driver, chauffeur"});
b.push({"front":"une oreille","back":"ear"});
b.push({"front":"attaquer","back":"to attack"});
b.push({"front":"le cabinet","back":"cabinet, agency, office"});
b.push({"front":"une usine","back":"factory"});
b.push({"front":"nombreux","back":"numerous"});
b.push({"front":"la vache","back":"cow"});
b.push({"front":"prudent","back":"prudent, careful, cautious"});
b.push({"front":"la station","back":"station"});
b.push({"front":"la vente","back":"sale"});
b.push({"front":"la logique","back":"logic, logical"});
b.push({"front":"le sage, la sage","back":"wise, good, sound, sensible"});
b.push({"front":"le souffle","back":"breath, puff"});
b.push({"front":"la rentrée","back":"reopening, return, start"});
b.push({"front":"le liquide","back":"liquid"});
b.push({"front":"libérer","back":"to free, liberate, release"});
b.push({"front":"la mesure","back":"measure"});
b.push({"front":"le garage","back":"garage"});
b.push({"front":"la vision","back":"vision, view"});
b.push({"front":"le château","back":"castle"});
b.push({"front":"le physique, la physique","back":"physical, physics"});
b.push({"front":"une alerte","back":"agile, alert, warning"});
b.push({"front":"le moteur","back":"motor"});
b.push({"front":"le fer","back":"iron"});
b.push({"front":"la version","back":"version"});
b.push({"front":"le lac","back":"lake"});
b.push({"front":"le canon","back":"gun, cannon"});
b.push({"front":"réellement","back":"really"});
b.push({"front":"un artiste, une artiste","back":"artist"});
b.push({"front":"la côte","back":"coast"});
b.push({"front":"quiconque","back":"whoever, anyone who"});
b.push({"front":"la chaleur","back":"the heat"});
b.push({"front":"une essence","back":"gas, petrol"});
b.push({"front":"le soutien","back":"the support_"});
b.push({"front":"le particulier","back":"particular, peculiar; person"});
b.push({"front":"traiter","back":"to treat, handle, deal with"});
b.push({"front":"le fusil","back":"rifle, gun"});
b.push({"front":"une herbe","back":"grass, herb"});
b.push({"front":"le virus","back":"virus"});
b.push({"front":"la tournée","back":"tour, round"});
b.push({"front":"traverser","back":"to cross, traverse"});
b.push({"front":"sombre","back":"dark"});
b.push({"front":"bosser","back":"to work, bash on"});
b.push({"front":"avancer","back":"to advance, move forward"});
b.push({"front":"puissant","back":"powerful"});
b.push({"front":"cependant","back":"however"});
b.push({"front":"construire","back":"to build, construct"});
b.push({"front":"une agence","back":"agency"});
b.push({"front":"le criminel","back":"criminal"});
b.push({"front":"le chèque","back":"check"});
b.push({"front":"le comportement","back":"behavior"});
b.push({"front":"le période, la période","back":"period"});
b.push({"front":"le lendemain","back":"next day"});
b.push({"front":"disparaître","back":"to disappear, vanish"});
b.push({"front":"fumer","back":"to smoke"});
b.push({"front":"inviter","back":"to invite"});
b.push({"front":"souffrir","back":"to suffer"});
b.push({"front":"le rock","back":"rock music"});
b.push({"front":"le fromage","back":"cheese"});
b.push({"front":"un adulte, une adulte","back":"adult"});
b.push({"front":"le billet","back":"ticket"});
b.push({"front":"résoudre","back":"to solve, resolve"});
b.push({"front":"la chair","back":"flesh"});
b.push({"front":"le résultat","back":"result, follow-up"});
b.push({"front":"taire","back":"to keep quiet"});
b.push({"front":"déranger","back":"to disturb, bother"});
b.push({"front":"le concours","back":"entrance exam, competition"});
b.push({"front":"le crâne","back":"skull"});
b.push({"front":"élevé","back":"high, heavy, tall"});
b.push({"front":"une attente","back":"the wait"});
b.push({"front":"le russe","back":"Russian"});
b.push({"front":"la chaîne","back":"chain, channel"});
b.push({"front":"le gardien","back":"guardian, keeper"});
b.push({"front":"laver","back":"to wash, clean"});
b.push({"front":"le gouverneur, la gouverneur","back":"governor"});
b.push({"front":"enfuir","back":"to run away, flee"});
b.push({"front":"une arrestation","back":"arrest"});
b.push({"front":"une enfance","back":"childhood"});
b.push({"front":"le demi","back":"half"});
b.push({"front":"un objet","back":"objective; object"});
b.push({"front":"le sénateur","back":"senator"});
b.push({"front":"profiter","back":"to take advantage, profit"});
b.push({"front":"le vote","back":"vote"});
b.push({"front":"la caisse","back":"cash desk, box"});
b.push({"front":"la science","back":"science"});
b.push({"front":"la poitrine","back":"chest, breast, breasts, bosom"});
b.push({"front":"magique","back":"magic; magical"});
b.push({"front":"inquiet","back":"worried, anxious"});
b.push({"front":"le sucre","back":"sugar"});
b.push({"front":"le siècle","back":"century"});
b.push({"front":"le geste, la geste","back":"gesture"});
b.push({"front":"étudier","back":"to study"});
b.push({"front":"la réputation","back":"reputation"});
b.push({"front":"forcément","back":"without question, inevitably"});
b.push({"front":"le traité","back":"treaty"});
b.push({"front":"refaire","back":"to redo, make again"});
b.push({"front":"le département","back":"department"});
b.push({"front":"la cloche","back":"bell"});
b.push({"front":"la chute","back":"fall"});
b.push({"front":"le joueur","back":"player"});
b.push({"front":"la peinture","back":"painting, paint, picture"});
b.push({"front":"une horreur","back":"horror"});
b.push({"front":"la tenue","back":"dress, outfit"});
b.push({"front":"la marine","back":"marine, navy"});
b.push({"front":"la promesse","back":"promise"});
b.push({"front":"la barre","back":"bar, rod"});
b.push({"front":"la plainte","back":"the moan, groan, complaint"});
b.push({"front":"la soupe","back":"soup"});
b.push({"front":"le studio","back":"studio, studio apartment"});
b.push({"front":"une opinion","back":"opinion"});
b.push({"front":"le crème, la crème","back":"cream"});
b.push({"front":"le foyer","back":"home, hearth"});
b.push({"front":"le somme, la somme","back":"amount, sum; nap"});
b.push({"front":"le manteau","back":"coat, overcoat"});
b.push({"front":"un incendie","back":"fire, blaze"});
b.push({"front":"le journaliste, la journaliste","back":"journalist"});
b.push({"front":"une aventure","back":"adventure"});
b.push({"front":"mener","back":"to lead"});
b.push({"front":"le cauchemar","back":"nightmare, bad dream"});
b.push({"front":"un uniforme","back":"uniform, steady, regular"});
b.push({"front":"le prêtre","back":"priest"});
b.push({"front":"le scientifique, la scientifique","back":"scientific"});
b.push({"front":"réglé","back":"regular, steady, well-ordered, ruled"});
b.push({"front":"la corde","back":"rope, chord, string"});
b.push({"front":"la propriété","back":"property"});
b.push({"front":"recommencer","back":"to resume, restart"});
b.push({"front":"calmer","back":"to calm down"});
b.push({"front":"deviner","back":"to guess, solve"});
b.push({"front":"un hiver","back":"winter"});
b.push({"front":"le champion","back":"champion"});
b.push({"front":"la conférence","back":"conference"});
b.push({"front":"complet","back":"full, complete; suit"});
b.push({"front":"le couloir","back":"corridor, aisle"});
b.push({"front":"le matériel","back":"material, equipment"});
b.push({"front":"admettre","back":"to admit"});
b.push({"front":"la foule","back":"crowd"});
b.push({"front":"la réaction","back":"reaction"});
b.push({"front":"le désert","back":"desert, wilderness"});
b.push({"front":"le réseau","back":"network"});
b.push({"front":"le commissaire, la commissaire","back":"superintendent, commissioner"});
b.push({"front":"un entraînement","back":"training, coaching, drive"});
b.push({"front":"ex","back":"ex"});
b.push({"front":"le fonds","back":"funds"});
b.push({"front":"le cadavre","back":"corpse"});
b.push({"front":"pardonner","back":"to forgive, excuse"});
b.push({"front":"uniquement","back":"only, uniquely"});
b.push({"front":"la liaison","back":"liaison, connection"});
b.push({"front":"traîner","back":"to drag; to hang out"});
b.push({"front":"le vélo","back":"bike, bicycle"});
b.push({"front":"la discussion","back":"discussion"});
b.push({"front":"filer","back":"slip, get out"});
b.push({"front":"soi","back":"one, oneself, self"});
b.push({"front":"répéter","back":"to repeat"});
b.push({"front":"la boutique","back":"shop"});
b.push({"front":"le front","back":"front, forehead"});
b.push({"front":"le curieux","back":"curious"});
b.push({"front":"le mardi","back":"Tuesday"});
b.push({"front":"un empire","back":"empire"});
b.push({"front":"la médecine","back":"medecine, medical science"});
b.push({"front":"le ménage","back":"housekeeping, housework"});
b.push({"front":"soudain","back":"sudden, suddenly"});
b.push({"front":"le ballon","back":"ball"});
b.push({"front":"combattre","back":"to fight"});
b.push({"front":"remonter","back":"to go back up (previously)"});
b.push({"front":"un acteur","back":"actor"});
b.push({"front":"rare","back":"rare"});
b.push({"front":"le bouton","back":"button, knob, spot"});
b.push({"front":"la tâche","back":"task"});
b.push({"front":"réussir","back":"to succeed"});
b.push({"front":"conseiller","back":"adviser, to advise"});
b.push({"front":"la cérémonie","back":"ceremony"});
b.push({"front":"brûler","back":"to burn"});
b.push({"front":"couvrir","back":"to cover"});
b.push({"front":"un océan","back":"ocean"});
b.push({"front":"rater","back":"to miss, misfire"});
b.push({"front":"la communauté","back":"community"});
b.push({"front":"le prisonnier","back":"prisoner, captive"});
b.push({"front":"le prénom","back":"first name"});
b.push({"front":"la surface","back":"surface"});
b.push({"front":"la gloire","back":"glory, fame"});
b.push({"front":"lourd","back":"heavy"});
b.push({"front":"remplacer","back":"to replace"});
b.push({"front":"affreux","back":"dreadful, awful, horrible"});
b.push({"front":"une humanité","back":"humanity"});
b.push({"front":"le tapis","back":"carpet, mat, covering"});
b.push({"front":"la réserve","back":"reserve"});
b.push({"front":"tenter","back":"to tempt, try"});
b.push({"front":"le véhicule","back":"vehicule"});
b.push({"front":"la déclaration","back":"declaration"});
b.push({"front":"réaliser","back":"to realize, achieve"});
b.push({"front":"lâcher","back":"to let go, release"});
b.push({"front":"la baisse","back":"the fall of, the drop of"});
b.push({"front":"venger","back":"to avenge, take revenge"});
b.push({"front":"installer","back":"to install"});
b.push({"front":"brillant","back":"brilliant"});
b.push({"front":"un inconnu","back":"unknown"});
b.push({"front":"la récompense","back":"reward, award"});
b.push({"front":"poursuivre","back":"to pursue"});
b.push({"front":"la frontière","back":"border"});
b.push({"front":"traite","back":"trade, draft, stretch, milking"});
b.push({"front":"le loup","back":"wolf"});
b.push({"front":"le navire","back":"ship"});
b.push({"front":"une origine","back":"origin, source"});
b.push({"front":"la fleur","back":"flower"});
b.push({"front":"une absence","back":"absence"});
b.push({"front":"la pratique","back":"practice, practical"});
b.push({"front":"le jeudi","back":"Thursday"});
b.push({"front":"le célibataire, la célibataire","back":"single, unmarried"});
b.push({"front":"attirer","back":"to attract"});
b.push({"front":"étonnant","back":"surprising, amazing, incredible__"});
b.push({"front":"la vengeance","back":"revenge"});
b.push({"front":"le professionnel","back":"professional"});
b.push({"front":"la veille","back":"the day before, the eve of, night watch"});
b.push({"front":"le salaire","back":"salary, wage"});
b.push({"front":"le rythme","back":"rhythm, rate"});
b.push({"front":"la tempête","back":"storm, gale, turmoil"});
b.push({"front":"la lutte","back":"struggle, fight, conflict"});
b.push({"front":"accompagner","back":"to accompany"});
b.push({"front":"la ceinture","back":"belt, waist"});
b.push({"front":"la panique","back":"panic"});
b.push({"front":"une opportunité","back":"opportunity, timeliness"});
b.push({"front":"le personnage","back":"character, individual"});
b.push({"front":"le mars","back":"March; Mars"});
b.push({"front":"le vingt","back":"twenty"});
b.push({"front":"profond","back":"deep"});
b.push({"front":"nourrir","back":"to feed, nourish"});
b.push({"front":"le singe","back":"monkey"});
b.push({"front":"la pêche","back":"fishing; peach"});
b.push({"front":"une haine","back":"hatred, hate"});
b.push({"front":"tromper","back":"to deceive_"});
b.push({"front":"le pis","back":"worse"});
b.push({"front":"un écran","back":"screen"});
b.push({"front":"assistant","back":"assistant"});
b.push({"front":"le malheur","back":"misfortune, bad luck"});
b.push({"front":"le couvert","back":"covered, overcast; place, seat, cutlery"});
b.push({"front":"le porc","back":"pig, pork"});
b.push({"front":"une explication","back":"explanation"});
b.push({"front":"la limite","back":"limit"});
b.push({"front":"un entretien","back":"interview, discussion, maintenance"});
b.push({"front":"la région","back":"region"});
b.push({"front":"vierge","back":"virgin"});
b.push({"front":"le comité","back":"committee"});
b.push({"front":"la cigarette","back":"cigarette"});
b.push({"front":"le palais","back":"palace, palate"});
b.push({"front":"identifier","back":"to identify"});
b.push({"front":"gâcher","back":"to waste, spoil"});
b.push({"front":"quant","back":"as for"});
b.push({"front":"annoncer","back":"to announce"});
b.push({"front":"le bloc","back":"block"});
b.push({"front":"un élève, une élève","back":"pupil, student"});
b.push({"front":"engager","back":"to hire, involve"});
b.push({"front":"le masque","back":"mask"});
b.push({"front":"extraordinaire","back":"extraordinary"});
b.push({"front":"un incident","back":"incident"});
b.push({"front":"la monnaie","back":"currency, coin, change"});
b.push({"front":"le temple","back":"temple"});
b.push({"front":"davantage","back":"more"});
b.push({"front":"final","back":"final"});
b.push({"front":"une alarme","back":"alarm"});
b.push({"front":"le roman","back":"novel"});
b.push({"front":"le classique","back":"classic"});
b.push({"front":"la soif","back":"thirst"});
b.push({"front":"normalement","back":"normally"});
b.push({"front":"naturel","back":"natural"});
b.push({"front":"le piano","back":"piano"});
b.push({"front":"la passion","back":"passion"});
b.push({"front":"le pot","back":"jar, pot"});
b.push({"front":"le japonais","back":"Japanese"});
b.push({"front":"la technique","back":"technique, technics, technical"});
b.push({"front":"une étoile","back":"star"});
b.push({"front":"concentrer","back":"to concentrate"});
b.push({"front":"le voisin","back":"neighbor"});
b.push({"front":"la créature","back":"creature"});
b.push({"front":"entièrement","back":"entirely, completely"});
b.push({"front":"le volant","back":"steering wheel"});
b.push({"front":"la portée","back":"range, reach, scope"});
b.push({"front":"le courrier","back":"mail, post"});
b.push({"front":"central","back":"central"});
b.push({"front":"affronter","back":"to confront, face"});
b.push({"front":"impressionnant","back":"impressive, upsetting"});
b.push({"front":"le golf","back":"golf, golf course"});
b.push({"front":"le jaune","back":"yellow"});
b.push({"front":"la bibliothèque","back":"library"});
b.push({"front":"lentement","back":"slowly"});
b.push({"front":"personnellement","back":"personally"});
b.push({"front":"le mystère","back":"mystery"});
b.push({"front":"la clinique","back":"clinic"});
b.push({"front":"une étape","back":"the step, the stage of"});
b.push({"front":"la fumée","back":"smoke"});
b.push({"front":"le royaume","back":"kingdom"});
b.push({"front":"la qualité","back":"quality"});
b.push({"front":"la tension","back":"tension"});
b.push({"front":"courageux","back":"courageous"});
b.push({"front":"le port","back":"harbour, port"});
b.push({"front":"une alliance","back":"alliance"});
b.push({"front":"la copie","back":"copy, replica, paper"});
b.push({"front":"un essai","back":"attempt, try, test"});
b.push({"front":"un expert","back":"expert"});
b.push({"front":"le désir","back":"desire"});
b.push({"front":"avouer","back":"to admit_"});
b.push({"front":"la conduite","back":"behavior, driving"});
b.push({"front":"un hall","back":"foyer, lobby"});
b.push({"front":"soigner","back":"to treat, look after, take care over"});
b.push({"front":"contacter","back":"to contact, get in touch with"});
b.push({"front":"la pile","back":"pile, stack, battery, tails"});
b.push({"front":"approcher","back":"to approach"});
b.push({"front":"le disque","back":"disc"});
b.push({"front":"le jugement","back":"judgement"});
b.push({"front":"un équipage","back":"crew, gear"});
b.push({"front":"une analyse","back":"analysis"});
b.push({"front":"une aube","back":"dawn, daybreak"});
b.push({"front":"la section","back":"section"});
b.push({"front":"la cage","back":"cage"});
b.push({"front":"le miroir","back":"mirror"});
b.push({"front":"une épreuve","back":"test, ordeal, trial"});
b.push({"front":"la condition","back":"condition"});
b.push({"front":"remplir","back":"to fill, fulfill"});
b.push({"front":"une existence","back":"existence"});
b.push({"front":"égal","back":"equal"});
b.push({"front":"retenir","back":"to retain, hold back, remember"});
b.push({"front":"le précis","back":"precise"});
b.push({"front":"annuler","back":"to cancel"});
b.push({"front":"le rayon","back":"ray, beam, radius; department, section, shelf"});
b.push({"front":"le football","back":"football, soccer"});
b.push({"front":"une assise","back":"basis, foundation"});
b.push({"front":"le secteur","back":"sector"});
b.push({"front":"la séance","back":"session, meeting"});
b.push({"front":"le profil","back":"profile, outline, contour"});
b.push({"front":"la valise","back":"suitcase"});
b.push({"front":"un avantage","back":"advantage"});
b.push({"front":"le nu","back":"naked, nude"});
b.push({"front":"la technologie","back":"technology"});
b.push({"front":"la procédure","back":"procedure"});
b.push({"front":"la pointe","back":"point, tip"});
b.push({"front":"le cochon","back":"pig"});
b.push({"front":"la figure","back":"face; figure"});
b.push({"front":"la patience","back":"patience"});
b.push({"front":"la poussière","back":"dust"});
b.push({"front":"le printemps","back":"spring"});
b.push({"front":"interroger","back":"to question, interrogate"});
b.push({"front":"une accusation","back":"accusation, indictment"});
b.push({"front":"un intéressé","back":"concerned, involved"});
b.push({"front":"idéal","back":"ideal"});
b.push({"front":"la poule","back":"hen, chick"});
b.push({"front":"correct","back":"correct"});
b.push({"front":"briser","back":"to break"});
b.push({"front":"le boule, la boule","back":"ball"});
b.push({"front":"le partage","back":"division, cutting, sharing"});
b.push({"front":"le mobile","back":"mobile, portable"});
b.push({"front":"la proposition","back":"proposition, proposal"});
b.push({"front":"une objection","back":"objection"});
b.push({"front":"le sauvage","back":"savage, wild"});
b.push({"front":"le rat","back":"rat"});
b.push({"front":"urgent","back":"urgent"});
b.push({"front":"reconnaître","back":"to recognize"});
b.push({"front":"la œuvre","back":"work, task"});
b.push({"front":"un échec","back":"failure"});
b.push({"front":"une attitude","back":"attitude"});
b.push({"front":"la paire","back":"pair"});
b.push({"front":"médical","back":"medical"});
b.push({"front":"suffisamment","back":"sufficiently"});
b.push({"front":"la fièvre","back":"fever"});
b.push({"front":"la télévision","back":"television"});
b.push({"front":"le magazine","back":"magazine"});
b.push({"front":"auparavant","back":"beforehand"});
b.push({"front":"séparer","back":"to separate"});
b.push({"front":"le musée","back":"museum"});
b.push({"front":"juger","back":"to judge"});
b.push({"front":"carrément","back":"(emphasis word) completely, directly, straight out"});
b.push({"front":"une épaule","back":"shoulder"});
b.push({"front":"la plaque","back":"plate, tag, plaque"});
b.push({"front":"organiser","back":"to organize"});
b.push({"front":"le sable","back":"sand"});
b.push({"front":"la légende","back":"legend, caption, key"});
b.push({"front":"la possibilité","back":"possibility"});
b.push({"front":"diriger","back":"to lead, direct"});
b.push({"front":"une éducation","back":"education"});
b.push({"front":"une imagination","back":"imagination"});
b.push({"front":"le maximum","back":"maximum"});
b.push({"front":"le collègue, la collègue","back":"colleague"});
b.push({"front":"ajouter","back":"to add"});
b.push({"front":"une audience","back":"audience, hearing"});
b.push({"front":"visiter","back":"to visit"});
b.push({"front":"le beurre","back":"butter"});
b.push({"front":"une organisation","back":"organisation"});
b.push({"front":"exprès","back":"deliberately, on purpose, intentionally_"});
b.push({"front":"le camarade, la camarade","back":"friend, comrade, pal, mate"});
b.push({"front":"le domaine","back":"domain, field"});
b.push({"front":"un empereur","back":"emperor"});
b.push({"front":"profondément","back":"profoundly, deeply"});
b.push({"front":"un effort","back":"effort"});
b.push({"front":"le cirque","back":"circus; cirque"});
b.push({"front":"terminer","back":"to finish, end,"});
b.push({"front":"déposer","back":"to deposit, put down"});
b.push({"front":"la balance","back":"scales, balance"});
b.push({"front":"raisonnable","back":"reasonable, fair"});
b.push({"front":"refuser","back":"to refuse"});
b.push({"front":"sensible","back":"sensitive"});
b.push({"front":"forcer","back":"to force"});
b.push({"front":"malheureux","back":"unhappy, miserable"});
b.push({"front":"le critique, la critique","back":"criticism, critic, critical"});
b.push({"front":"la pensée","back":"thought"});
b.push({"front":"chasser","back":"to hunt, chase away"});
b.push({"front":"la disparition","back":"disappearance"});
b.push({"front":"un ordinaire","back":"ordinary"});
b.push({"front":"un étudiant","back":"student"});
b.push({"front":"un orange, une orange","back":"orange"});
b.push({"front":"la coïncidence","back":"coincidence"});
b.push({"front":"voyager","back":"to travel"});
b.push({"front":"fêter","back":"to celebrate"});
b.push({"front":"un allemand","back":"German"});
b.push({"front":"le congé","back":"holiday, time off, day off, notice"});
b.push({"front":"la thérapie","back":"therapy"});
b.push({"front":"la croix","back":"cross"});
b.push({"front":"une autorisation","back":"authorization, permission, permit"});
b.push({"front":"le scénario","back":"scenario, script"});
b.push({"front":"le parfum","back":"perfume, scent, fragrance"});
b.push({"front":"adorer","back":"to adore, worship"});
b.push({"front":"la donnée","back":"fact, datum"});
b.push({"front":"le portefeuille","back":"wallet"});
b.push({"front":"une huile","back":"oil"});
b.push({"front":"examiner","back":"to examine"});
b.push({"front":"le solide","back":"solid"});
b.push({"front":"extrêmement","back":"extremely"});
b.push({"front":"guérir","back":"to cure, heal, get better"});
b.push({"front":"le géant","back":"giant, gigantic"});
b.push({"front":"emprunter","back":"to borrow"});
b.push({"front":"publique","back":"public"});
b.push({"front":"le poil","back":"hair, bristle"});
b.push({"front":"entraîner","back":"to carry along, train"});
b.push({"front":"taper","back":"to beat, slam, bang, type"});
b.push({"front":"digne","back":"dignified, worthy"});
b.push({"front":"le stade","back":"stadium, stage"});
b.push({"front":"renvoyer","back":"to send back, dismiss"});
b.push({"front":"le large","back":"wide; the width"});
b.push({"front":"le taux","back":"the rate of"});
b.push({"front":"armé","back":"armed"});
b.push({"front":"le loyer","back":"rent"});
b.push({"front":"la jeunesse","back":"youth"});
b.push({"front":"une adaptation","back":"adaptation"});
b.push({"front":"le détail","back":"detail"});
b.push({"front":"le juif","back":"Jew, Jewish"});
b.push({"front":"éloigner","back":"to move away, take away, distance"});
b.push({"front":"livrer","back":"to deliver"});
b.push({"front":"le moral","back":"moral, morale"});
b.push({"front":"un incapable","back":"incapable, incompetent"});
b.push({"front":"une invitation","back":"invitation"});
b.push({"front":"le péché","back":"sin"});
b.push({"front":"le cercle","back":"circle, cycle"});
b.push({"front":"le territoire","back":"territory"});
b.push({"front":"le plateau","back":"plateau, tray, set, stage"});
b.push({"front":"éliminer","back":"to eliminate"});
b.push({"front":"le supérieur","back":"superior"});
b.push({"front":"suffisant","back":"sufficient"});
b.push({"front":"le viol","back":"rape"});
b.push({"front":"une ouverture","back":"opening"});
b.push({"front":"furieux","back":"furious, raging, violent"});
b.push({"front":"un exercice","back":"exercise,"});
b.push({"front":"respecter","back":"to respect"});
b.push({"front":"une expression","back":"expression"});
b.push({"front":"un original","back":"original"});
b.push({"front":"la remise","back":"presentation, delivery"});
b.push({"front":"le tribu, la tribu","back":"tribe"});
b.push({"front":"la cabine","back":"hut, cubicle, booth, box, room"});
b.push({"front":"la race","back":"breed, race"});
b.push({"front":"la tentative","back":"the attempt"});
b.push({"front":"le décès","back":"death_"});
b.push({"front":"le cap","back":"cape"});
b.push({"front":"la bourse","back":"purse, scholarship"});
b.push({"front":"le populaire","back":"popular"});
b.push({"front":"la signature","back":"signature"});
b.push({"front":"sexuel","back":"sexual"});
b.push({"front":"un humour","back":"humour"});
b.push({"front":"le cave, la cave","back":"cellar, basement"});
b.push({"front":"précieux","back":"precious"});
b.push({"front":"la matière","back":"matter, subject, material"});
b.push({"front":"la cassette","back":"cassette"});
b.push({"front":"injuste","back":"unfair, unjust"});
b.push({"front":"la réception","back":"reception"});
b.push({"front":"le sommet","back":"summit"});
b.push({"front":"un employé","back":"employee"});
b.push({"front":"le progrès","back":"progress"});
b.push({"front":"le mercredi","back":"Wednesday"});
b.push({"front":"un angle","back":"angle, point of view"});
b.push({"front":"un instinct","back":"instinct"});
b.push({"front":"officiellement","back":"officially"});
b.push({"front":"nôtre","back":"ours, our own"});
b.push({"front":"la panne","back":"the breakdown, the failure (of a machine)"});
b.push({"front":"la compétition","back":"competition"});
b.push({"front":"illégal","back":"illegal"});
b.push({"front":"électrique","back":"electric"});
b.push({"front":"participer","back":"to participate"});
b.push({"front":"la comédie","back":"comedy, playacting"});
b.push({"front":"témoigner","back":"to testify"});
b.push({"front":"la nation","back":"nation"});
b.push({"front":"la commission","back":"commission"});
b.push({"front":"rattraper","back":"to recapture, recover, catch up, make up for"});
b.push({"front":"la poudre","back":"powder"});
b.push({"front":"un objectif","back":"objective, aim, goal; lens"});
b.push({"front":"un accueil","back":"welcome, reception"});
b.push({"front":"une union","back":"union"});
b.push({"front":"le témoignage","back":"testimony"});
b.push({"front":"ranger","back":"to tidy up, put away"});
b.push({"front":"absurde","back":"absurd"});
b.push({"front":"le trafic","back":"traffic, circulation"});
b.push({"front":"une agression","back":"agression"});
b.push({"front":"déplacer","back":"to move, displace"});
b.push({"front":"la division","back":"division"});
b.push({"front":"élever","back":"to grow, lift, raise"});
b.push({"front":"un enregistrement","back":"recording, registration, check-in, logging"});
b.push({"front":"pur","back":"pure"});
b.push({"front":"durer","back":"to last"});
b.push({"front":"le comte","back":"the count"});
b.push({"front":"négatif","back":"negative"});
b.push({"front":"le gagnant","back":"winner, winning"});
b.push({"front":"le langage","back":"language"});
b.push({"front":"le noble, la noble","back":"noble"});
b.push({"front":"une échelle","back":"ladder, scale"});
b.push({"front":"la température","back":"temperature"});
b.push({"front":"prier","back":"to pray"});
b.push({"front":"un indice","back":"indication, sign, clue"});
b.push({"front":"la matinée","back":"morning"});
b.push({"front":"le guide, la guide","back":"guide"});
b.push({"front":"la souffrance","back":"suffering"});
b.push({"front":"le finale, finale","back":"finale, final event"});
b.push({"front":"une influence","back":"influence"});
b.push({"front":"une autorité","back":"authority"});
b.push({"front":"la production","back":"production"});
b.push({"front":"le tunnel","back":"tunnel"});
b.push({"front":"transformer","back":"to transform"});
b.push({"front":"le fauteuil","back":"armchair, seat"});
b.push({"front":"le foie","back":"liver"});
b.push({"front":"causer","back":"to cause"});
b.push({"front":"violent","back":"violent"});
b.push({"front":"commander","back":"to order, command"});
b.push({"front":"fouiller","back":"to search, frisk, go through, rummage through"});
b.push({"front":"la rage","back":"rage, fury, rabies"});
b.push({"front":"une hauteur","back":"height"});
b.push({"front":"le ministère","back":"ministry"});
b.push({"front":"la culture","back":"culture"});
b.push({"front":"le stress","back":"stress"});
b.push({"front":"le pari","back":"the bet"});
b.push({"front":"interne","back":"internal, interior, intern"});
b.push({"front":"le diplôme","back":"diploma, certificate"});
b.push({"front":"une activité","back":"activity"});
b.push({"front":"un auteur, une auteur","back":"author"});
b.push({"front":"paraître","back":"to appear"});
b.push({"front":"le serment","back":"oath, vow"});
b.push({"front":"le clan","back":"clan"});
b.push({"front":"un album","back":"album"});
b.push({"front":"le charme","back":"charm"});
b.push({"front":"apprécier","back":"to appreciate"});
b.push({"front":"la livraison","back":"the delivery"});
b.push({"front":"habiller","back":"to dress, get dressed"});
b.push({"front":"la promotion","back":"promotion, advertising"});
b.push({"front":"pervers","back":"pervert, perverse, perverted"});
b.push({"front":"rompre","back":"to break"});
b.push({"front":"la collection","back":"collection, series"});
b.push({"front":"le plastique","back":"plastic"});
b.push({"front":"naturellement","back":"naturally"});
b.push({"front":"une électricité","back":"electricity"});
b.push({"front":"la flotte","back":"fleet"});
b.push({"front":"une étude","back":"study"});
b.push({"front":"national","back":"national"});
b.push({"front":"le terroriste, la terroriste","back":"terrorist"});
b.push({"front":"autrefois","back":"in the past; once"});
b.push({"front":"la caution","back":"deposit, guarantee, bail"});
b.push({"front":"la cité","back":"city"});
b.push({"front":"le total","back":"total"});
b.push({"front":"le commerce","back":"trade, commerce"});
b.push({"front":"gratuit","back":"free, gratuitous, unwarranted"});
b.push({"front":"un écart","back":"space, gap"});
b.push({"front":"charger","back":"to load, charge"});
b.push({"front":"le cimetière","back":"cemetery, graveyard"});
b.push({"front":"une empreinte","back":"imprint, print, mark, impression"});
b.push({"front":"le septembre","back":"September"});
b.push({"front":"la phase","back":"phase"});
b.push({"front":"rêver","back":"to dream"});
b.push({"front":"le vague, la vague","back":"vague; wave"});
b.push({"front":"le dollar","back":"dollar"});
b.push({"front":"emporter","back":"to take, remove (an object)"});
b.push({"front":"ignorer","back":"to ignore"});
b.push({"front":"le micro","back":"mike, micro, microphone"});
b.push({"front":"le rang","back":"rank, row"});
b.push({"front":"la révolution","back":"revolution"});
b.push({"front":"léger","back":"something light"});
b.push({"front":"douze","back":"twelve"});
b.push({"front":"plaindre","back":"complain"});
b.push({"front":"un esclave, une esclave","back":"slave"});
b.push({"front":"le métro","back":"underground, metro"});
b.push({"front":"soutenir","back":"to sustain, support"});
b.push({"front":"la culpabilité","back":"guilt"});
b.push({"front":"la dette","back":"debt"});
b.push({"front":"le parent","back":"parent"});
b.push({"front":"interrompre","back":"to interrupt"});
b.push({"front":"le sein","back":"breast, bosom"});
b.push({"front":"le commissariat","back":"police station"});
b.push({"front":"produire","back":"to product"});
b.push({"front":"sain","back":"healthy, sane"});
b.push({"front":"le régime","back":"regime"});
b.push({"front":"efficace","back":"effective"});
b.push({"front":"la fierté","back":"pride"});
b.push({"front":"éteindre_","back":"to extinguish, put out, turn off"});
b.push({"front":"écraser_","back":"to crush, grind"});
b.push({"front":"un adjoint","back":"assistant, deputy"});
b.push({"front":"le laboratoire","back":"laboratory"});
b.push({"front":"la religion","back":"religion"});
b.push({"front":"couler","back":"to flow; to sink"});
b.push({"front":"le rond","back":"round"});
b.push({"front":"le comté","back":"county, earldom"});
b.push({"front":"pratiquement","back":"practically"});
b.push({"front":"la communication","back":"communication"});
b.push({"front":"une option","back":"option"});
b.push({"front":"un escalier","back":"stairs, staircase"});
b.push({"front":"un espagnol","back":"Spanish"});
b.push({"front":"la lecture","back":"the (act of) reading"});
b.push({"front":"le quatrième, la quatrième","back":"fourth"});
b.push({"front":"le chirurgien","back":"surgeon"});
b.push({"front":"tandis","back":"while"});
b.push({"front":"un amant","back":"lover"});
b.push({"front":"jusque","back":"to, up to, until"});
b.push({"front":"la personnalité","back":"personality"});
b.push({"front":"une évidence","back":"evidence"});
b.push({"front":"le remède","back":"cure, remedy"});
b.push({"front":"la formation","back":"training"});
b.push({"front":"le manuel","back":"manual"});
b.push({"front":"enterrer","back":"to bury, lay aside"});
b.push({"front":"le caractère","back":"character"});
b.push({"front":"particulièrement","back":"particularly"});
b.push({"front":"le fidèle","back":"faithful"});
b.push({"front":"la dose","back":"dose, amount"});
b.push({"front":"généreux","back":"generous"});
b.push({"front":"rouler","back":"to roll"});
b.push({"front":"le congrès","back":"congress, conference"});
b.push({"front":"la lampe","back":"lamp, light"});
b.push({"front":"actuellement","back":"at present, at the moment"});
b.push({"front":"grandir","back":"to grow, increase, expand"});
b.push({"front":"améliorer","back":"to improve"});
b.push({"front":"résister","back":"to resist"});
b.push({"front":"le réveil","back":"waking up, awakening, alarm clock"});
b.push({"front":"la boisson","back":"drink, beverage"});
b.push({"front":"le dessin","back":"drawing, pattern, design"});
b.push({"front":"crever","back":"to burst, puncture"});
b.push({"front":"nucléaire","back":"nuclear"});
b.push({"front":"goûter","back":"to taste, snack"});
b.push({"front":"le portrait","back":"portrait, photograph"});
b.push({"front":"exprimer","back":"to express"});
b.push({"front":"une avenue","back":"avenue"});
b.push({"front":"un accent","back":"accent"});
b.push({"front":"la découverte","back":"discovery"});
b.push({"front":"centrale","back":"power station, central office"});
b.push({"front":"une exécution","back":"execution, accomplishment"});
b.push({"front":"espérer","back":"to hope"});
b.push({"front":"détendre_","back":"to release, to relax"});
b.push({"front":"plaire","back":"to please"});
b.push({"front":"la brigade","back":"team, squad, brigade"});
b.push({"front":"la tradition","back":"tradition"});
b.push({"front":"officiel","back":"official"});
b.push({"front":"le défi","back":"challenge"});
b.push({"front":"le désastre","back":"disaster"});
b.push({"front":"disponible","back":"available"});
b.push({"front":"un italien","back":"Italian"});
b.push({"front":"le budget","back":"budget"});
b.push({"front":"ressentir","back":"to feel"});
b.push({"front":"la reconnaissance","back":"recognition, gratitude"});
b.push({"front":"le drapeau","back":"flag"});
b.push({"front":"un indien","back":"Indian"});
b.push({"front":"la phrase","back":"sentence, phrase"});
b.push({"front":"le métal","back":"metal"});
b.push({"front":"le processus","back":"process"});
b.push({"front":"correctement","back":"properly, correctly"});
b.push({"front":"la rumeur","back":"rumour"});
b.push({"front":"assister","back":"to attend; to assist, help"});
b.push({"front":"la jungle","back":"jungle"});
b.push({"front":"mortel","back":"mortal, deadly, lethal"});
b.push({"front":"la survie","back":"survival"});
b.push({"front":"une intelligence","back":"intelligence"});
b.push({"front":"le chasseur","back":"hunter, fighter, page, messenger"});
b.push({"front":"quoique","back":"although, though; whatever"});
b.push({"front":"le passeport","back":"passport"});
b.push({"front":"risquer","back":"to risk"});
b.push({"front":"la stratégie","back":"strategy"});
b.push({"front":"accueillir","back":"to welcome, greet, accommodate"});
b.push({"front":"serré","back":"tight, packed, crowded"});
b.push({"front":"la remarque","back":"remark"});
b.push({"front":"le commercial","back":"commercial"});
b.push({"front":"définitivement","back":"definitely, permanently, for good"});
b.push({"front":"le commandement","back":"command, order, commandment"});
b.push({"front":"une interview","back":"interview"});
b.push({"front":"complexe","back":"complex"});
b.push({"front":"le pétrole","back":"crude oil, petroleum"});
b.push({"front":"la pomme","back":"apple"});
b.push({"front":"une intervention","back":"intervention; talk"});
b.push({"front":"le lot","back":"the share, the lot"});
b.push({"front":"la charité","back":"charity"});
b.push({"front":"promener","back":"to take for a walk, go for a walk"});
b.push({"front":"la méthode","back":"method, procedure"});
b.push({"front":"le câble","back":"cable, wire"});
b.push({"front":"creuser","back":"to dig"});
b.push({"front":"tendre","back":"to tighten; to extend, stretch; tender"});
b.push({"front":"la batterie","back":"battery; drum set"});
b.push({"front":"un écrivain","back":"writer"});
b.push({"front":"reconnaissant","back":"grateful"});
b.push({"front":"sincèrement","back":"sincerely"});
b.push({"front":"timide","back":"timid, shy, bashful"});
b.push({"front":"une héroïne","back":"heroine"});
b.push({"front":"la tendance","back":"tendency, trend"});
b.push({"front":"le complice, la complice","back":"accomplice"});
b.push({"front":"la torture","back":"torture"});
b.push({"front":"un otage, une otage","back":"hostage"});
b.push({"front":"techniquement","back":"technically"});
b.push({"front":"la masse","back":"mass"});
b.push({"front":"opérer","back":"to operate, carry out"});
b.push({"front":"sincère","back":"sincere"});
b.push({"front":"le collège","back":"secondary school, college"});
b.push({"front":"un échantillon","back":"sample"});
b.push({"front":"le sacrifice","back":"sacrifice"});
b.push({"front":"le pasteur","back":"minister, clergyman, pastor"});
b.push({"front":"le dent, la dent","back":"tooth"});
b.push({"front":"le quart","back":"quarter"});
b.push({"front":"un équipement","back":"equipment"});
b.push({"front":"cruel","back":"cruel, ferocious, bitter"});
b.push({"front":"arracher","back":"to pull up, tear up_"});
b.push({"front":"le juillet","back":"July"});
b.push({"front":"la génération","back":"generation"});
b.push({"front":"un événement","back":"event_"});
b.push({"front":"solitaire","back":"solitary, lone, lonely"});
b.push({"front":"le bâton","back":"tick, club, baton"});
b.push({"front":"la marge","back":"margin"});
b.push({"front":"un héritage","back":"heritage"});
b.push({"front":"ressembler","back":"to look like, resemble"});
b.push({"front":"le volontaire, la volontaire","back":"volunteer; voluntary"});
b.push({"front":"énormément","back":"enormously"});
b.push({"front":"la priorité","back":"priority"});
b.push({"front":"le mélange","back":"mixing, mixture, blend"});
b.push({"front":"la rupture","back":"the break, rupture"});
b.push({"front":"le sel","back":"salt"});
b.push({"front":"déménager","back":"to move"});
b.push({"front":"tester","back":"to test"});
b.push({"front":"le conducteur","back":"driver, operator, conductor"});
b.push({"front":"la trahison","back":"betrayal, treachery, treason"});
b.push({"front":"le transfert","back":"the transfer"});
b.push({"front":"débrouiller","back":"to untangle, sort out, manage, get by"});
b.push({"front":"la moyenne","back":"average"});
b.push({"front":"moderne","back":"modern"});
b.push({"front":"effacer","back":"to erase, clean"});
b.push({"front":"le positif","back":"positive"});
b.push({"front":"la publicité","back":"advertising, advertisement, publicity"});
b.push({"front":"un environnement","back":"environment"});
b.push({"front":"médias","back":"media"});
b.push({"front":"le scandale","back":"scandal, uproar"});
b.push({"front":"le vendeur","back":"salesman, seller"});
b.push({"front":"invisible","back":"invisible"});
b.push({"front":"la tragédie","back":"tragedy"});
b.push({"front":"une issue","back":"the exit, outcome"});
b.push({"front":"voter","back":"to vote"});
b.push({"front":"probable","back":"probable, likely"});
b.push({"front":"la destruction","back":"destruction"});
b.push({"front":"négocier","back":"to negotiate"});
b.push({"front":"aimable","back":"pleasant, kind, nice"});
b.push({"front":"un avril","back":"April"});
b.push({"front":"la connerie","back":"crap, bullsh*t, stupidity"});
b.push({"front":"le saut","back":"jump, leap"});
b.push({"front":"quinze","back":"fifteen"});
b.push({"front":"le leader, la leader","back":"leader"});
b.push({"front":"le séjour","back":"the stay"});
b.push({"front":"le marin, la marin","back":"sea, marine, sailor"});
b.push({"front":"la sensation","back":"sensation"});
b.push({"front":"une exception","back":"exception"});
b.push({"front":"sien","back":"his, hers"});
b.push({"front":"la possession","back":"possession, ownership"});
b.push({"front":"le motif","back":"motive, purpose"});
b.push({"front":"le serveur","back":"waiter, server"});
b.push({"front":"la prière","back":"prayer"});
b.push({"front":"protégé","back":"protected, protégé"});
b.push({"front":"baisser","back":"to lower"});
b.push({"front":"abattre","back":"to pull down, kill, beat"});
b.push({"front":"une association","back":"association"});
b.push({"front":"le poing","back":"fist, punch"});
b.push({"front":"le producteur","back":"producer"});
b.push({"front":"une écriture","back":"the writing"});
b.push({"front":"craindre","back":"to fear, be afraid of"});
b.push({"front":"la vallée","back":"valley"});
b.push({"front":"le règlement","back":"rule, regulation"});
b.push({"front":"net","back":"clear; Internet"});
b.push({"front":"précisément","back":"precisely"});
b.push({"front":"la morale","back":"ethics; moral"});
b.push({"front":"immense","back":"immense"});
b.push({"front":"informer","back":"to inform"});
b.push({"front":"le chapitre","back":"chapter"});
b.push({"front":"le potentiel","back":"potential"});
b.push({"front":"une audition","back":"hearing, examination, audition"});
b.push({"front":"confirmer","back":"to confirm"});
b.push({"front":"la capacité","back":"capacity, ability"});
b.push({"front":"le fruit","back":"fruit"});
b.push({"front":"le chaos","back":"chaos"});
b.push({"front":"éclater","back":"to burst, explode"});
b.push({"front":"un acier","back":"steel"});
b.push({"front":"le cri","back":"the shout, cry"});
b.push({"front":"la population","back":"population"});
b.push({"front":"effectivement","back":"effectively"});
b.push({"front":"regretter","back":"to regret"});
b.push({"front":"proposer","back":"to propose"});
b.push({"front":"le panneau","back":"sign, notice, panel"});
b.push({"front":"légal","back":"legal, lawful"});
b.push({"front":"la construction","back":"construction, building"});
b.push({"front":"la boue","back":"mud"});
b.push({"front":"rarement","back":"rarely, seldom"});
b.push({"front":"la combinaison","back":"combination"});
b.push({"front":"le franc","back":"frank; franc (money)"});
b.push({"front":"la plante","back":"plant"});
b.push({"front":"une apparence","back":"appearance"});
b.push({"front":"le menu","back":"menu, slender, slim, minor"});
b.push({"front":"le luxe","back":"luxury"});
b.push({"front":"un essentiel","back":"essential"});
b.push({"front":"maintenir","back":"to maintain"});
b.push({"front":"stable","back":"stable"});
b.push({"front":"le satellite","back":"satellite"});
b.push({"front":"la branche","back":"branch"});
b.push({"front":"une autoroute","back":"motorway, highway, freeway"});
b.push({"front":"rembourser","back":"to reimburse, pay back, pay off, repay"});
b.push({"front":"le transport","back":"transportation"});
b.push({"front":"la statue","back":"statue"});
b.push({"front":"le principe","back":"principle"});
b.push({"front":"la couronne","back":"crown, wreath"});
b.push({"front":"subir","back":"to undergo, be subjected to, suffer"});
b.push({"front":"le sec","back":"dry"});
b.push({"front":"accuser","back":"to accuse"});
b.push({"front":"la goutte","back":"the drop (of one liquid)"});
b.push({"front":"la colline","back":"hill"});
b.push({"front":"la revanche","back":"revenge; return"});
b.push({"front":"le trente","back":"thirty"});
b.push({"front":"une aile","back":"wing, sail, blade"});
b.push({"front":"le bienvenu","back":"welcome"});
b.push({"front":"hélas","back":"alas"});
b.push({"front":"la résistance","back":"resistance"});
b.push({"front":"la prime","back":"free gift, premium, bonus"});
b.push({"front":"littéralement","back":"literally"});
b.push({"front":"fédéral","back":"federal"});
b.push({"front":"un engagement","back":"agreement, commitment"});
b.push({"front":"le médicament","back":"medicine, drug, medication"});
b.push({"front":"le symbole","back":"symbol"});
b.push({"front":"un avertissement","back":"warning"});
b.push({"front":"le réalisateur","back":"director"});
b.push({"front":"douter","back":"to doubt"});
b.push({"front":"douloureux","back":"painful, grievous, distressing"});
b.push({"front":"louer","back":"to rent, praise"});
b.push({"front":"un impact","back":"impact"});
b.push({"front":"le chagrin","back":"grief, sorrow,"});
b.push({"front":"révéler","back":"to reveal"});
b.push({"front":"le juin","back":"June"});
b.push({"front":"téléphoner","back":"to telephone, phone, call"});
b.push({"front":"une excellence","back":"excellence"});
b.push({"front":"remarquer","back":"to remark; to notice, point out"});
b.push({"front":"la pension","back":"pension; room and board, boarding school"});
b.push({"front":"roue_","back":"wheel"});
b.push({"front":"un arrangement","back":"arrangement, layout, order, agreement"});
b.push({"front":"la routine","back":"routine"});
b.push({"front":"la poignée","back":"handful, fistful, handle"});
b.push({"front":"le local","back":"local"});
b.push({"front":"le légitime, la légitime","back":"legitimate"});
b.push({"front":"un hélicoptère","back":"helicopter"});
b.push({"front":"filmer","back":"to film, shoot"});
b.push({"front":"un octobre","back":"October"});
b.push({"front":"une obscurité","back":"darkness"});
b.push({"front":"le domicile","back":"home, place of residence"});
b.push({"front":"une administration","back":"administration"});
b.push({"front":"la médaille","back":"medal"});
b.push({"front":"le casque","back":"helmet"});
b.push({"front":"la boucle","back":"loop, buckle, curl"});
b.push({"front":"tarder","back":"to delay"});
b.push({"front":"un asile","back":"shelter, asylum, hospital"});
b.push({"front":"le texte","back":"text"});
b.push({"front":"le deuil","back":"mourning, grief"});
b.push({"front":"un auto, une auto","back":"car"});
b.push({"front":"la fonction","back":"function"});
b.push({"front":"la république","back":"republic"});
b.push({"front":"allumer","back":"to switch on, light up, turn on"});
b.push({"front":"enquêter","back":"to investigate, hold inquiry, conduct a survey"});
b.push({"front":"piquer","back":"to sting, bite, prick, be hot; to steal"});
b.push({"front":"le manche, la manche","back":"handle, sleeve"});
b.push({"front":"la circulation","back":"circulation, traffic"});
b.push({"front":"une enveloppe","back":"envelope"});
b.push({"front":"le blé","back":"wheat"});
b.push({"front":"le record","back":"record"});
b.push({"front":"le puits","back":"well, shaft, pit"});
b.push({"front":"renoncer","back":"renounce"});
b.push({"front":"décrire","back":"to describe"});
b.push({"front":"accomplir","back":"to accomplish"});
b.push({"front":"réduire","back":"to reduce"});
b.push({"front":"enseigner","back":"to teach"});
b.push({"front":"un entraîneur","back":"coach, trainer"});
b.push({"front":"contrairement","back":"contrary"});
b.push({"front":"la facture","back":"invoice, bill"});
b.push({"front":"un époux","back":"husband, spouse"});
b.push({"front":"la revue","back":"review, magazine, journal"});
b.push({"front":"le pouce","back":"thumb, inch"});
b.push({"front":"avaler","back":"to swallow"});
b.push({"front":"remarquable","back":"remarkable, outstanding"});
b.push({"front":"le délit","back":"crime, offence"});
b.push({"front":"le réduit","back":"reduced, scaled-down, cut-down, tiny room, hideout"});
b.push({"front":"ruiner","back":"to ruin, bankrupt oneself"});
b.push({"front":"la détention","back":"detention, possession"});
b.push({"front":"coûter","back":"to cost"});
b.push({"front":"mêler","back":"to mingle, mix"});
b.push({"front":"la douzaine","back":"dozen"});
b.push({"front":"suprême","back":"supreme"});
b.push({"front":"le gris","back":"grey"});
b.push({"front":"le restant","back":"remaining, the rest, the remainder"});
b.push({"front":"la crainte","back":"fear"});
b.push({"front":"le panier","back":"basket"});
b.push({"front":"informé","back":"informed"});
b.push({"front":"sortant","back":"outgoing"});
b.push({"front":"terriblement","back":"terribly, awfully"});
b.push({"front":"le conflit","back":"conflict"});
b.push({"front":"le sourd","back":"deaf"});
b.push({"front":"observer","back":"to observe, watch"});
b.push({"front":"le protocole","back":"etiquette, protocol"});
b.push({"front":"placer","back":"to place"});
b.push({"front":"le silencieux","back":"silent, noiseless, silencer"});
b.push({"front":"le malentendu","back":"misunderstanding"});
b.push({"front":"punir","back":"to punish"});
b.push({"front":"la faiblesse","back":"weakness"});
b.push({"front":"rapporter","back":"to bring back, report"});
b.push({"front":"la quantité","back":"quantity"});
b.push({"front":"un historique","back":"historical"});
b.push({"front":"serrer","back":"to tighten, squeeze"});
b.push({"front":"avertir","back":"to warn"});
b.push({"front":"enfermer","back":"to shut"});
b.push({"front":"le candidat","back":"candidate"});
b.push({"front":"le compromis","back":"compromise, agreement"});
b.push({"front":"une atmosphère","back":"atmosphere"});
b.push({"front":"établir","back":"to establish"});
b.push({"front":"le tube","back":"tube"});
b.push({"front":"le cadre","back":"frame, executive"});
b.push({"front":"le trône","back":"throne"});
b.push({"front":"le festival","back":"festival"});
b.push({"front":"intéresser","back":"to interest, involve"});
b.push({"front":"un ingénieur, une ingénieur","back":"engineer"});
b.push({"front":"différemment","back":"differently"});
b.push({"front":"balancer","back":"to swing, sway"});
b.push({"front":"le minimum","back":"minimum"});
b.push({"front":"un ambassadeur","back":"ambassador"});
b.push({"front":"tragique","back":"tragic"});
b.push({"front":"vaincre","back":"to defeat, overcome, conquer"});
b.push({"front":"conscient","back":"conscious, aware"});
b.push({"front":"le tissu","back":"fabric, material, cloth, tissue, woven"});
b.push({"front":"une intimité","back":"privacy, intimacy"});
b.push({"front":"obéir","back":"to obey, comply with, respond to"});
b.push({"front":"le lancement","back":"the launch"});
b.push({"front":"la demeure","back":"residence, home"});
b.push({"front":"mystérieux","back":"mysterious, secretive"});
b.push({"front":"la fillette","back":"little girl, girl"});
b.push({"front":"le genou","back":"knee"});
b.push({"front":"la sagesse","back":"wisdom, moderation"});
b.push({"front":"une industrie","back":"industry"});
b.push({"front":"le guerrier","back":"warrior; warlike"});
b.push({"front":"fragile","back":"fragile"});
b.push({"front":"la libération","back":"liberation"});
b.push({"front":"promettre","back":"to promise"});
b.push({"front":"un élément","back":"element"});
b.push({"front":"ramasser","back":"to pick up, collect, gather"});
b.push({"front":"un atelier","back":"workshop, studio"});
b.push({"front":"la destinée","back":"fate, destiny"});
b.push({"front":"accéder","back":"to access, reach, attain"});
b.push({"front":"la grossesse","back":"pregnancy"});
b.push({"front":"un usage","back":"use, usage"});
b.push({"front":"royal","back":"royal"});
b.push({"front":"la résidence","back":"residence, block of flats"});
b.push({"front":"quelconque","back":"any, some"});
b.push({"front":"suicider","back":"to commit suicide"});
b.push({"front":"communiquer","back":"to communicate"});
b.push({"front":"le trouble","back":"trouble"});
b.push({"front":"la dépression","back":"depression"});
b.push({"front":"le novembre","back":"November"});
b.push({"front":"la chaussure","back":"shoe, sneaker"});
b.push({"front":"un équilibre","back":"balance, equilibrium"});
b.push({"front":"un élu","back":"elected, elected member"});
b.push({"front":"endormir","back":"to put to sleep, fall asleep"});
b.push({"front":"le gras","back":"fatty, fat, greasy"});
b.push({"front":"la grève","back":"the strike (of workers)"});
b.push({"front":"confortable","back":"comfortable"});
b.push({"front":"le chant","back":"song"});
b.push({"front":"judiciaire","back":"judiciary"});
b.push({"front":"accrocher","back":"to hang up, hang on, put up"});
b.push({"front":"le jouet","back":"toy"});
b.push({"front":"augmenter","back":"to increase, raise"});
b.push({"front":"un automne","back":"fall, autumn"});
b.push({"front":"peindre","back":"to paint, depict, portray"});
b.push({"front":"une exposition","back":"exhibition, show"});
b.push({"front":"cesser","back":"to cease, stop"});
b.push({"front":"la vedette","back":"star, patrol boat"});
b.push({"front":"la curiosité","back":"curiosity"});
b.push({"front":"le débat","back":"debate"});
b.push({"front":"le citoyen","back":"citizen"});
b.push({"front":"le pape","back":"pope"});
b.push({"front":"une assiette","back":"plate, dish, bowl"});
b.push({"front":"le tennis","back":"tennis"});
b.push({"front":"la solitude","back":"solitude, loneliness"});
b.push({"front":"la destination","back":"destination"});
b.push({"front":"une ambiance","back":"the atmosphere (mood)"});
b.push({"front":"archives","back":"archives, records"});
b.push({"front":"la capitale","back":"capital"});
b.push({"front":"le spécialiste, la spécialiste","back":"specialist"});
b.push({"front":"le massacre","back":"massacre, slaughter"});
b.push({"front":"veiller","back":"to look after, stay up"});
b.push({"front":"parier","back":"to bet"});
b.push({"front":"racheter","back":"to repurchase, buy back, redeem"});
b.push({"front":"la description","back":"description"});
b.push({"front":"un irlandais","back":"Irish"});
b.push({"front":"la punition","back":"punishment"});
b.push({"front":"le poème","back":"poem"});
b.push({"front":"prêter","back":"to lend"});
b.push({"front":"dépenser","back":"to spend"});
b.push({"front":"échanger","back":"to exchange"});
b.push({"front":"une économie","back":"economy"});
b.push({"front":"la colonne","back":"column"});
b.push({"front":"la connexion","back":"connection"});
b.push({"front":"fonctionner","back":"to function, work"});
b.push({"front":"la feuille","back":"leaf, sheet, slip"});
b.push({"front":"le suisse","back":"Swiss"});
b.push({"front":"la répétition","back":"repetition, rehearsal"});
b.push({"front":"la météo","back":"weather forecast"});
b.push({"front":"anonyme","back":"anonymous"});
b.push({"front":"un immobilier","back":"property, real estate, property business, real estate business"});
b.push({"front":"la serre","back":"greenhouse"});
b.push({"front":"le plafond","back":"ceiling, roof, maximum"});
b.push({"front":"fournir","back":"to provide, supply"});
b.push({"front":"confier","back":"to entrust"});
b.push({"front":"le diamant","back":"diamond"});
b.push({"front":"le défaut","back":"fault, flaw, shortcoming"});
b.push({"front":"une inquiétude","back":"worry, anxiety"});
b.push({"front":"un août","back":"August"});
b.push({"front":"un acide","back":"acid"});
b.push({"front":"la dignité","back":"dignity"});
b.push({"front":"une ambassade","back":"embassy"});
b.push({"front":"guère","back":"hardly, scarcely"});
b.push({"front":"la tache","back":"stain, spot, mark"});
b.push({"front":"familier","back":"familiar, informal"});
b.push({"front":"saisir","back":"to seize, to grab"});
b.push({"front":"volontiers","back":"with pleasure, willingly, gladly"});
b.push({"front":"signaler","back":"to indicate, signal"});
b.push({"front":"le fixe","back":"fixed"});
b.push({"front":"la foire","back":"the fair"});
b.push({"front":"enregistrer","back":"to record, check in"});
b.push({"front":"le civil","back":"civil; civilian"});
b.push({"front":"une affection","back":"affection, ailment"});
b.push({"front":"la catastrophe","back":"catastrophe, disaster"});
b.push({"front":"le duc","back":"duke"});
b.push({"front":"la fermeture","back":"closing"});
b.push({"front":"buter","back":"to stumble, trip, run into, prop up, score"});
b.push({"front":"accorder","back":"to grant"});
b.push({"front":"le canal","back":"canal, channel"});
b.push({"front":"évacuer","back":"to evacuate, clear"});
b.push({"front":"un absent","back":"absent"});
b.push({"front":"la merveille","back":"marvel, wonder"});
b.push({"front":"la plaie","back":"wound"});
b.push({"front":"la clef","back":"key"});
b.push({"front":"le cinquième, la cinquième","back":"fifth"});
b.push({"front":"le désordre","back":"disorder, confusion"});
b.push({"front":"intime","back":"intimate, close, secret, private"});
b.push({"front":"un adversaire, une adversaire","back":"opponent, adversary"});
b.push({"front":"la réussite","back":"the success"});
b.push({"front":"effrayer","back":"to frighten, scare"});
b.push({"front":"quasiment","back":"almost, early"});
b.push({"front":"le fichier","back":"file"});
b.push({"front":"intervenir","back":"to intervene"});
b.push({"front":"le profit","back":"profit, benefit"});
b.push({"front":"le sou","back":"penny"});
b.push({"front":"une informatique","back":"computer science, computing"});
b.push({"front":"constamment","back":"constantly, continuously, consistent"});
b.push({"front":"désespéré","back":"desperate, hopeless"});
b.push({"front":"la recette","back":"recipe"});
b.push({"front":"la douceur","back":"softness, smoothness, mildness, gentleness,sweetness"});
b.push({"front":"la formule","back":"formula, expression"});
b.push({"front":"la montée","back":"climb, ascent, rise, raising"});
b.push({"front":"le bond","back":"leap, rebound"});
b.push({"front":"le verdict","back":"verdict"});
b.push({"front":"célébrer","back":"to celebrate"});
b.push({"front":"prétendre","back":"to pretend"});
b.push({"front":"la fréquence","back":"frequency"});
b.push({"front":"disputer","back":"to dispute"});
b.push({"front":"un exposé","back":"account, statement, talk"});
b.push({"front":"cuire","back":"to cook, bake, roast"});
b.push({"front":"une illusion","back":"illusion"});
b.push({"front":"le jet","back":"jet, throw, spray, nozzle"});
b.push({"front":"une antenne","back":"antenna"});
b.push({"front":"la compassion","back":"compassion"});
b.push({"front":"la quête","back":"quest, pursuit, collection"});
b.push({"front":"le photographe, la photographe","back":"photographer"});
b.push({"front":"déterminer","back":"to determine, find out, specify"});
b.push({"front":"un assaut","back":"assault, attack, bout"});
b.push({"front":"provoquer","back":"to provoke"});
b.push({"front":"coincer","back":"to jam, hinder, get stuck"});
b.push({"front":"le document","back":"document"});
b.push({"front":"la poésie","back":"poetry"});
b.push({"front":"délicat","back":"delicate, fine, gentle"});
b.push({"front":"piéger","back":"to trap, booby-trap"});
b.push({"front":"le syndicat","back":"union (of workers)"});
b.push({"front":"le tabac","back":"tobacco"});
b.push({"front":"un orchestre","back":"orchestra"});
b.push({"front":"discret","back":"discreet, tactful, quiet"});
b.push({"front":"la ère","back":"era"});
b.push({"front":"relever","back":"to raise"});
b.push({"front":"le décembre","back":"December"});
b.push({"front":"appuyer","back":"to lean, support"});
b.push({"front":"une évasion","back":"evasion, escape"});
b.push({"front":"réagir","back":"to react"});
b.push({"front":"la retenue","back":"deduction; restraint, self-control"});
b.push({"front":"glisser","back":"to slide, slip"});
b.push({"front":"la tristesse","back":"sadness, gloominess, dreariness"});
b.push({"front":"la fatigue","back":"tiredness, fatigue"});
b.push({"front":"la création","back":"creation"});
b.push({"front":"la planche","back":"plank, board"});
b.push({"front":"le voile, la voile","back":"veil, sail"});
b.push({"front":"la galerie","back":"gallery"});
b.push({"front":"le bétail","back":"livestock, cattle"});
b.push({"front":"le drame","back":"drama"});
b.push({"front":"une émotion","back":"emotion, feeling"});
b.push({"front":"la garantie","back":"guarantee"});
b.push({"front":"la terreur","back":"terror, dread"});
b.push({"front":"intense","back":"intense, severe, dense"});
b.push({"front":"le contenu","back":"contents"});
b.push({"front":"le sorcier","back":"sorcerer, witch"});
b.push({"front":"le fleuve","back":"river"});
b.push({"front":"la longueur","back":"length"});
b.push({"front":"vider","back":"to empty, vacate"});
b.push({"front":"certes","back":"indeed, certainly, of course"});
b.push({"front":"le thème","back":"theme, topic"});
b.push({"front":"le refuge","back":"refuge"});
b.push({"front":"le compliment","back":"compliment"});
b.push({"front":"la navette","back":"shuttle"});
b.push({"front":"la poursuite","back":"chase, pursuit"});
b.push({"front":"un ennui","back":"the boredom, trouble, worry"});
b.push({"front":"la sauvetage","back":"rescue, salvaging"});
b.push({"front":"lutter","back":"to struggle, fight"});
b.push({"front":"le reporter, la reporter","back":"to report; to postpone"});
b.push({"front":"britannique","back":"British"});
b.push({"front":"le janvier","back":"January"});
b.push({"front":"le représentant","back":"representative"});
b.push({"front":"ci","back":"this one, here"});
b.push({"front":"la référence","back":"reference"});
b.push({"front":"détester","back":"to hate, detest"});
b.push({"front":"le nettoyage","back":"cleaning, cleansing"});
b.push({"front":"généralement","back":"generally"});
b.push({"front":"la misère","back":"poverty, misery"});
b.push({"front":"une innocence","back":"innocence"});
b.push({"front":"la conclusion","back":"conclusion"});
b.push({"front":"un inverse","back":"opposite, reverse"});
b.push({"front":"coller","back":"to stick, paste"});
b.push({"front":"le plomb","back":"lead"});
b.push({"front":"noyer","back":"walnut; to drown, flood, blur, water down"});
b.push({"front":"attacher","back":"to attach"});
b.push({"front":"confus","back":"confused, embarrassed"});
b.push({"front":"insensé","back":"insane; nonsense"});
b.push({"front":"inhabituel","back":"unusual"});
b.push({"front":"le catholique, la catholique","back":"Catholic"});
b.push({"front":"pêcher","back":"to fish, go fishing; peach tree"});
b.push({"front":"la marchandise","back":"merchandise, commodity"});
b.push({"front":"moquer","back":"to mock, make fun of"});
b.push({"front":"le circuit","back":"circuit"});
b.push({"front":"la centaine","back":"hundred"});
b.push({"front":"spécialement","back":"especially, particularly"});
b.push({"front":"éternel","back":"eternal, everlasting"});
b.push({"front":"un hôte","back":"host, guest"});
b.push({"front":"le règne","back":"reign"});
b.push({"front":"un assassinat","back":"murder, assassination"});
b.push({"front":"fameux","back":"famous"});
b.push({"front":"la quarantaine","back":"forty"});
b.push({"front":"le relevé","back":"statement, list; relieved; put in relief; rolled up"});
b.push({"front":"la structure","back":"structure"});
b.push({"front":"le comptable, la comptable","back":"accountant, accountable"});
b.push({"front":"trahir","back":"to betray, give away"});
b.push({"front":"temporaire","back":"temporary"});
b.push({"front":"le relais","back":"shift, relay"});
b.push({"front":"le vif","back":"lively"});
b.push({"front":"international","back":"international"});
b.push({"front":"le développement","back":"development"});
b.push({"front":"le carton","back":"cardboard, card, score"});
b.push({"front":"impressionner","back":"to impress, upset"});
b.push({"front":"boucher","back":"butcher; to fill in, get clogged up"});
b.push({"front":"dénoncer","back":"to denounce"});
b.push({"front":"une identification","back":"identification"});
b.push({"front":"dégager","back":"to free, to clear_"});
b.push({"front":"la génétique","back":"genetic"});
b.push({"front":"lent","back":"slow"});
b.push({"front":"le cocktail","back":"cocktail, cocktail party"});
b.push({"front":"violer","back":"to rape, infringe"});
b.push({"front":"planter","back":"to plant, pitch"});
b.push({"front":"vain","back":"vain"});
b.push({"front":"la descente","back":"descent, raid, downward slope"});
b.push({"front":"le nuage","back":"cloud"});
b.push({"front":"la vitre","back":"pane, window_"});
b.push({"front":"la majorité","back":"majority"});
b.push({"front":"pénible","back":"hard, difficult, painful, tiresome"});
b.push({"front":"une élection","back":"election"});
b.push({"front":"le social","back":"social"});
b.push({"front":"la confession","back":"confession"});
b.push({"front":"le degré","back":"degree"});
b.push({"front":"une inspiration","back":"inspiration"});
b.push({"front":"dépêcher","back":"to dispatch, send, hurry"});
b.push({"front":"sacrifier","back":"to sacrifice, give away"});
b.push({"front":"le concept","back":"concept"});
b.push({"front":"le banc","back":"bench, workbench, pew"});
b.push({"front":"un engin","back":"machine, tool, vehicle, device"});
b.push({"front":"la spécialité","back":"specialty"});
b.push({"front":"biologique","back":"biological, nature"});
b.push({"front":"surprendre","back":"to surprise"});
b.push({"front":"hurler","back":"to scream, yell"});
b.push({"front":"un orage","back":"storm, thunderstorm"});
b.push({"front":"rassembler","back":"to gather together"});
b.push({"front":"mordre","back":"to bite, overlap into"});
b.push({"front":"le chantier","back":"construction site, roadworks"});
b.push({"front":"pendre","back":"to hang down"});
b.push({"front":"extrême","back":"extreme"});
b.push({"front":"le dépôt","back":"deposit, depot"});
b.push({"front":"un amateur, une amateur","back":"amateur"});
b.push({"front":"le commentaire","back":"comment, remark"});
b.push({"front":"la correction","back":"correction"});
b.push({"front":"la présentation","back":"presentation"});
b.push({"front":"sonner","back":"to ring"});
b.push({"front":"la flèche","back":"arrow"});
b.push({"front":"le tournoi","back":"tournament"});
b.push({"front":"une ordonnance","back":"prescription, organisation, edict, ruling"});
b.push({"front":"une élite","back":"elite"});
b.push({"front":"le trajet","back":"journey, route; traject"});
b.push({"front":"inventer","back":"to invent"});
b.push({"front":"la pompe","back":"pump"});
b.push({"front":"démarrer","back":"to start up"});
b.push({"front":"physiquement","back":"physically"});
b.push({"front":"la requête","back":"request, petition"});
b.push({"front":"habituer","back":"to accustom, get used to"});
b.push({"front":"le statut","back":"status"});
b.push({"front":"une augmentation","back":"the increase, the rise"});
b.push({"front":"développer","back":"to develop"});
b.push({"front":"le col","back":"collar, mountain pass"});
b.push({"front":"le carnet","back":"notebook, notepad"});
b.push({"front":"la gravité","back":"seriousness, solemnity, graveness, gravity"});
b.push({"front":"craquer","back":"to creak, squeak, crackle, give in, strike"});
b.push({"front":"la licence","back":"licence, permit"});
b.push({"front":"réunir","back":"to gather, reunite, raise"});
b.push({"front":"la troupe","back":"troup, troop"});
b.push({"front":"saluer","back":"to greet, salute"});
b.push({"front":"le conte","back":"tale"});
b.push({"front":"le chiffre","back":"figure, number"});
b.push({"front":"la tactique","back":"tactics, tactical"});
b.push({"front":"un hommage","back":"homage, tribute"});
b.push({"front":"nier","back":"to deny"});
b.push({"front":"commettre","back":"to commit"});
b.push({"front":"la flamme","back":"flame, fire, fervor, brilliance"});
b.push({"front":"le croisé","back":"twill; alternate; crusader; crossed"});
b.push({"front":"un impatient","back":"impatient"});
b.push({"front":"le quai","back":"platform, quay, embankment"});
b.push({"front":"le complot","back":"plot, conspiracy"});
b.push({"front":"consulter","back":"to consult"});
b.push({"front":"ultime","back":"ultimate; final"});
b.push({"front":"onze","back":"eleven"});
b.push({"front":"la poussée","back":"push, rise, upsurge"});
b.push({"front":"accompli","back":"accomplished"});
b.push({"front":"aussitôt","back":"as soon as"});
b.push({"front":"le poète","back":"poet"});
b.push({"front":"un inconscient","back":"unconscious, thoughtless"});
b.push({"front":"reculer","back":"to move back, back up"});
b.push({"front":"ralentir","back":"to slow down"});
b.push({"front":"le facteur","back":"postman, mailman; factor"});
b.push({"front":"le registre","back":"log, register, registry"});
b.push({"front":"pâle","back":"pale"});
b.push({"front":"la toile","back":"cloth, canvass, web"});
b.push({"front":"le filet","back":"dribble, trickle, wisp, streak, thread, fillet, net"});
b.push({"front":"le fardeau","back":"burden"});
b.push({"front":"honorable","back":"honorable"});
b.push({"front":"conclure","back":"to conclude"});
b.push({"front":"le compagnon","back":"companion, craftsman, journeyman"});
b.push({"front":"fixer","back":"to fix, arrange, set"});
b.push({"front":"le député","back":"deputy, parliamentary delegate"});
b.push({"front":"le montant","back":"upright, upwards, sum, total"});
b.push({"front":"le standard","back":"standard, switchboard"});
b.push({"front":"solaire","back":"solar"});
b.push({"front":"une évolution","back":"evolution"});
b.push({"front":"la maîtrise","back":"mastery, command, control, master’s degree"});
b.push({"front":"un institut","back":"institute"});
b.push({"front":"visiblement","back":"obviously, clearly, visibly"});
b.push({"front":"la mairie","back":"town hall, city hall"});
b.push({"front":"premièrement","back":"firstly"});
b.push({"front":"la civilisation","back":"civilization"});
b.push({"front":"la grille","back":"railings, gate, grid, scale"});
b.push({"front":"le chanteur","back":"singer"});
b.push({"front":"le gré","back":"liking"});
b.push({"front":"un investissement","back":"investment"});
b.push({"front":"un arrivant","back":"person who arrived"});
b.push({"front":"la discipline","back":"discipline"});
b.push({"front":"surprenant","back":"surprising"});
b.push({"front":"attentivement","back":"attentively, carefully, closely"});
b.push({"front":"âgé","back":"old"});
b.push({"front":"fabriquer","back":"to manufacture, invent, make"});
b.push({"front":"la levée","back":"raising, levying, levee"});
b.push({"front":"la barrière","back":"fence, barrier, gate"});
b.push({"front":"considérer","back":"to consider"});
b.push({"front":"la disposition","back":"arrangement, disposition"});
b.push({"front":"une affiche","back":"poster, public notice, bill"});
b.push({"front":"la correspondance","back":"correspondance, connection"});
b.push({"front":"le trottoir","back":"pavement"});
b.push({"front":"le championnat","back":"championship"});
b.push({"front":"soucier","back":"to care about, show concern for"});
b.push({"front":"le case, la case","back":"box, hut, field"});
b.push({"front":"plonger","back":"to dive"});
b.push({"front":"automatique","back":"automatic"});
b.push({"front":"le perdant","back":"losing, loser"});
b.push({"front":"visuel","back":"visual"});
b.push({"front":"décevoir","back":"to disappoint"});
b.push({"front":"le renfort","back":"help, back-up, support; reinforce"});
b.push({"front":"le cinquante","back":"fifty"});
b.push({"front":"approprié","back":"appropriate"});
b.push({"front":"artistique","back":"artistic"});
b.push({"front":"blâmer","back":"to blame, reprimand"});
b.push({"front":"le brouillard","back":"fog, mist, haze"});
b.push({"front":"le œuf","back":"egg"});
b.push({"front":"analyser","back":"to analyse"});
b.push({"front":"marquer","back":"to mark"});
b.push({"front":"le foudre, la foudre","back":"lightning"});
b.push({"front":"satisfaire","back":"to satisfy"});
b.push({"front":"habiter","back":"to live (in a place)"});
b.push({"front":"la patrie","back":"homeland, home country"});
b.push({"front":"vulnérable","back":"vulnerable"});
b.push({"front":"le domestique, la domestique","back":"servant, domestic"});
b.push({"front":"le ressort","back":"spring; resort; spirit"});
b.push({"front":"un individu","back":"individual"});
b.push({"front":"allonger","back":"to lengthen, extend, stretch out"});
b.push({"front":"la difficulté","back":"difficulty"});
b.push({"front":"impliquer","back":"to imply, implicate; involve"});
b.push({"front":"le marchand","back":"merchant"});
b.push({"front":"le rideau","back":"curtain"});
b.push({"front":"légèrement","back":"lightly, slightly"});
b.push({"front":"la défaite","back":"defeat"});
b.push({"front":"dramatique","back":"dramatic, tragic, drama"});
b.push({"front":"la détresse","back":"distress"});
b.push({"front":"typique","back":"typical"});
b.push({"front":"adopter","back":"to adopt"});
b.push({"front":"ennuyer","back":"to bore, worry, bother"});
b.push({"front":"la toilette","back":"washing, toilet, lavatory, bathroom, restroom"});
b.push({"front":"une insulte","back":"insult"});
b.push({"front":"la corruption","back":"corruption"});
b.push({"front":"fiable","back":"reliable, trustworthy"});
b.push({"front":"voire","back":"if ever; even; indeed"});
b.push({"front":"une allure","back":"speed, pace, walk, look, appearance"});
b.push({"front":"la démocratie","back":"democracy"});
b.push({"front":"rechercher","back":"to search for"});
b.push({"front":"un instrument","back":"instrument"});
b.push({"front":"pacifique","back":"peaceful, peace-loving"});
b.push({"front":"repérer","back":"to spot, pick out; locate, find"});
b.push({"front":"raser","back":"to shave, raze"});
b.push({"front":"un arabe","back":"Arabic, Arab"});
b.push({"front":"transmettre","back":"to forward, transmit"});
b.push({"front":"le désespoir","back":"despair"});
b.push({"front":"la fondation","back":"foundation"});
b.push({"front":"souhaiter","back":"to wish"});
b.push({"front":"le certificat","back":"certificate"});
b.push({"front":"la fraude","back":"fraud"});
b.push({"front":"rapprocher","back":"to bring closer, get closer"});
b.push({"front":"le carburant","back":"fuel"});
b.push({"front":"la fusion","back":"fusion, melting, merging"});
b.push({"front":"secondaire","back":"secondary"});
b.push({"front":"le février","back":"February"});
b.push({"front":"une amende","back":"fine (payment)"});
b.push({"front":"le syndrome","back":"syndrome"});
b.push({"front":"le grain","back":"grain, bean, bead; spot, mole"});
b.push({"front":"loyal","back":"loyal, faithful"});
b.push({"front":"guider","back":"to guide"});
b.push({"front":"vulgaire","back":"vulgar, common, popular"});
b.push({"front":"la séparation","back":"separation"});
b.push({"front":"la farce","back":"joke, prank, hoax, farce"});
b.push({"front":"gratuitement","back":"free, gratuitously"});
b.push({"front":"former","back":"to form"});
b.push({"front":"un héritier","back":"heir"});
b.push({"front":"la transmission","back":"transmission"});
b.push({"front":"torturer","back":"to torture"});
b.push({"front":"le rocher","back":"rock, boulder"});
b.push({"front":"un aîné","back":"oldest"});
b.push({"front":"téléphonique","back":"telephone"});
b.push({"front":"la profondeur","back":"depth"});
b.push({"front":"le triple","back":"triple"});
b.push({"front":"assassiner","back":"to murder, assassinate"});
b.push({"front":"une édition","back":"publishing, editing, edition"});
b.push({"front":"scolaire","back":"school, educational, academic"});
b.push({"front":"infiniment","back":"infinitely"});
b.push({"front":"la faille","back":"fault"});
b.push({"front":"le délai","back":"delay"});
b.push({"front":"le précédent","back":"precedent; previous"});
b.push({"front":"la profession","back":"profession"});
b.push({"front":"honorer","back":"to honour, do credit to"});
b.push({"front":"le raciste, la raciste","back":"racist"});
b.push({"front":"la réplique","back":"reply, retort; replica"});
b.push({"front":"prévoir","back":"to foresee, anticipate"});
b.push({"front":"la dimension","back":"dimension"});
b.push({"front":"le vice","back":"fault, defect, vice"});
b.push({"front":"sembler","back":"to seem"});
b.push({"front":"une angoisse","back":"distress, anguish, dread, fear"});
b.push({"front":"une ambition","back":"ambition"});
b.push({"front":"une observation","back":"observation"});
b.push({"front":"le vainqueur, la vainqueur","back":"winner"});
b.push({"front":"un aspect","back":"aspect"});
b.push({"front":"surmonter","back":"to overcome, top, surmount"});
b.push({"front":"repousser","back":"to push away, postpone"});
b.push({"front":"coopérer","back":"to cooperate"});
b.push({"front":"grossier","back":"unrefined, crude, coarse, rude, rough"});
b.push({"front":"le mineur","back":"minor; miner"});
b.push({"front":"comparer","back":"to compare"});
b.push({"front":"la durée","back":"length, duration"});
b.push({"front":"le parcours","back":"journey, course, route"});
b.push({"front":"le regret","back":"the regret, regretfully"});
b.push({"front":"électronique","back":"electronic"});
b.push({"front":"la faillite","back":"bankruptcy, collapse, failure"});
b.push({"front":"confidentiel","back":"confidential"});
b.push({"front":"le missile","back":"missile"});
b.push({"front":"modeste","back":"modest"});
b.push({"front":"représenter","back":"to represent"});
b.push({"front":"le chômage","back":"unemployment"});
b.push({"front":"renverser","back":"to knock down, turn over, overturn"});
b.push({"front":"alimentaire","back":"food"});
b.push({"front":"exister","back":"to exist"});
b.push({"front":"le favori","back":"favorite"});
b.push({"front":"dessiner","back":"to draw, design"});
b.push({"front":"décoller","back":"to take off; to loosen, unstick"});
b.push({"front":"transporter","back":"to transport, carry"});
b.push({"front":"exécuter","back":"to execute, carry out"});
b.push({"front":"manipuler","back":"to handle, manipulate"});
b.push({"front":"une impasse","back":"dead end, cul-de-sac"});
b.push({"front":"le détenu","back":"prisoner"});
b.push({"front":"le financier","back":"financial, financier"});
b.push({"front":"une égalité","back":"equality"});
b.push({"front":"capturer","back":"to capture, catch"});
b.push({"front":"le béton","back":"concrete"});
b.push({"front":"le distributeur","back":"distributor, machine"});
b.push({"front":"la location","back":"renting"});
b.push({"front":"le score","back":"score"});
b.push({"front":"la ruine","back":"ruin, ruins"});
b.push({"front":"la conviction","back":"conviction, belief"});
b.push({"front":"le pacte","back":"pact, treaty"});
b.push({"front":"le vœu","back":"vow, wish, will"});
b.push({"front":"une éthique","back":"ethical, ethics"});
b.push({"front":"le troupeau","back":"herd, flock"});
b.push({"front":"une obsession","back":"obsession"});
b.push({"front":"un emplacement","back":"site, location"});
b.push({"front":"grimper","back":"to climb, go up"});
b.push({"front":"la proie","back":"prey"});
b.push({"front":"le tiers","back":"third"});
b.push({"front":"le char, la char","back":"tank"});
b.push({"front":"le grec","back":"Greek"});
b.push({"front":"le prétexte","back":"pretext"});
b.push({"front":"épargner","back":"to save, spare"});
b.push({"front":"la démonstration","back":"demonstration"});
b.push({"front":"outre","back":"besides"});
b.push({"front":"une invasion","back":"invasion"});
b.push({"front":"dorénavant","back":"from now on, henceforth"});
b.push({"front":"valable","back":"valid"});
b.push({"front":"le barrage","back":"barrier, obstruction, dam, roadblock"});
b.push({"front":"la commune","back":"locality; common, joint"});
b.push({"front":"le latin","back":"Latin"});
b.push({"front":"la récolte","back":"harvest, crop"});
b.push({"front":"le diagnostic","back":"diagnosis"});
b.push({"front":"un isolé","back":"remote, isolated, insolated"});
b.push({"front":"démissionner","back":"to resign"});
b.push({"front":"le peintre, la peintre","back":"painter"});
b.push({"front":"la messe","back":"mass"});
b.push({"front":"la confusion","back":"confusion, mix-up"});
b.push({"front":"chimique","back":"chemical"});
b.push({"front":"le maigre","back":"thin, skinny, slim, lean"});
b.push({"front":"franchir","back":"to get over"});
b.push({"front":"pointer","back":"to mark off, clock in, clock out, aim"});
b.push({"front":"la violation","back":"violation, transgression"});
b.push({"front":"la vertu","back":"virtue"});
b.push({"front":"raccrocher","back":"to hang up"});
b.push({"front":"mexicain","back":"Mexican"});
b.push({"front":"inscrire","back":"to register, write down"});
b.push({"front":"le religieux","back":"religious"});
b.push({"front":"le stock","back":"stock, to supply"});
b.push({"front":"séduire","back":"to seduce, charm, captivate, appeal to"});
b.push({"front":"explorer","back":"to explore, investigate, examine"});
b.push({"front":"fondre","back":"to melt, merge"});
b.push({"front":"primaire","back":"primary"});
b.push({"front":"une assistance","back":"attendance, assistance"});
b.push({"front":"le rappel","back":"reminder, summary, recall, return, remember"});
b.push({"front":"sympathique","back":"likeable, nice, pleasant person"});
b.push({"front":"le passager","back":"passenger, temporary"});
b.push({"front":"stopper","back":"to stop, halt"});
b.push({"front":"le soulagement","back":"relief"});
b.push({"front":"déclarer","back":"to declare"});
b.push({"front":"instable","back":"unstable"});
b.push({"front":"le plancher","back":"floor"});
b.push({"front":"inévitable","back":"unavoidable, inevitable"});
b.push({"front":"justifier","back":"to justify"});
b.push({"front":"la confirmation","back":"confirmation"});
b.push({"front":"la séquence","back":"sequence"});
b.push({"front":"le voisinage","back":"neighborhood"});
b.push({"front":"insupportable","back":"intolerable"});
b.push({"front":"préserver","back":"to preserve"});
b.push({"front":"la performance","back":"performance"});
b.push({"front":"dépasser","back":"to pass, go beyond"});
b.push({"front":"le souhait","back":"wish"});
b.push({"front":"le dispositif","back":"device, apparatus"});
b.push({"front":"rude","back":"rough, harsh, hard, tough"});
b.push({"front":"sévère","back":"severe"});
b.push({"front":"la baie","back":"bay; berry"});
b.push({"front":"manifestement","back":"manifestly, clearly"});
b.push({"front":"la concentration","back":"concentration"});
b.push({"front":"le privilège","back":"privilege"});
b.push({"front":"humide","back":"moist, damp, humid, wet"});
b.push({"front":"exceptionnel","back":"exceptional"});
b.push({"front":"la préparation","back":"preparation"});
b.push({"front":"le réservoir","back":"tank, reservoir"});
b.push({"front":"le montage","back":"assembly, setting, pitching, putting, editing"});
b.push({"front":"le sixième, la sixième","back":"sixth"});
b.push({"front":"le rebelle","back":"rebel, rebellious"});
b.push({"front":"le pneu","back":"tire"});
b.push({"front":"naître","back":"to be born"});
b.push({"front":"divin","back":"divine, heavenly"});
b.push({"front":"menacer","back":"to threaten"});
b.push({"front":"le charbon","back":"coal"});
b.push({"front":"la coopération","back":"cooperation"});
b.push({"front":"une invention","back":"invention"});
b.push({"front":"néanmoins","back":"nevertheless"});
b.push({"front":"une expédition","back":"dispatch, shipping, shipment, expedition"});
b.push({"front":"raide","back":"stiff, straight"});
b.push({"front":"le pompier","back":"fireman, firefighter"});
b.push({"front":"déclencher","back":"to trigger, release, unleash"});
b.push({"front":"la détente","back":"release, relaxation, loosening"});
b.push({"front":"la philosophie","back":"philosophy"});
b.push({"front":"la croisière","back":"cruise"});
b.push({"front":"une adoption","back":"adoption, passing"});
b.push({"front":"une évaluation","back":"evaluation"});
b.push({"front":"un attentat","back":"attack, assassination attempt"});
b.push({"front":"une altitude","back":"altitude, height"});
b.push({"front":"authentique","back":"genuine, authentic"});
b.push({"front":"publier","back":"to publish"});
b.push({"front":"le capital","back":"major, chief, principal; capital, assets"});
b.push({"front":"le paiement","back":"payment"});
b.push({"front":"humble","back":"humble, lowly"});
b.push({"front":"un office","back":"office, bureau"});
b.push({"front":"le fermier","back":"farmer"});
b.push({"front":"la photographie","back":"photography"});
b.push({"front":"le communiste, la communiste","back":"communist"});
b.push({"front":"une hypothèse","back":"hypothesis"});
b.push({"front":"le calendrier","back":"calendar"});
b.push({"front":"le mental","back":"mental"});
b.push({"front":"ressortir","back":"to go out again, come out again, take out again"});
b.push({"front":"psychologique","back":"psychological"});
b.push({"front":"investir","back":"to invest"});
b.push({"front":"régulièrement","back":"regularly"});
b.push({"front":"exposer","back":"to display, exhibit, expose"});
b.push({"front":"le musicien","back":"musician"});
b.push({"front":"via","back":"via"});
b.push({"front":"le plume, la plume","back":"feather"});
b.push({"front":"la substance","back":"substance"});
b.push({"front":"la chimie","back":"chemistry"});
b.push({"front":"assumer","back":"to assume"});
b.push({"front":"un agenda","back":"diary, planner"});
b.push({"front":"le moine","back":"monk, friar"});
b.push({"front":"actuel","back":"current, present"});
b.push({"front":"le refus","back":"refusal"});
b.push({"front":"habituel","back":"customary, habitual"});
b.push({"front":"renseigner","back":"to give information, get information"});
b.push({"front":"la suggestion","back":"suggestion"});
b.push({"front":"le réaliste, la réaliste","back":"realist, realistic"});
b.push({"front":"familial","back":"family"});
b.push({"front":"féliciter","back":"to congratulate"});
b.push({"front":"le stage","back":"internship, training course"});
b.push({"front":"un abus","back":"abuse, misuse, breach"});
b.push({"front":"le carré","back":"square, broad, plain"});
b.push({"front":"juridique","back":"legal, judicial"});
b.push({"front":"vaste","back":"vast, immense"});
b.push({"front":"relâcher","back":"to loosen, release, let go"});
b.push({"front":"un établissement","back":"establishment, organization"});
b.push({"front":"un achat","back":"the purchase"});
b.push({"front":"la proximité","back":"proximity, nearness, closeness"});
b.push({"front":"atroce","back":"atrocious"});
b.push({"front":"redevenir","back":"to become again"});
b.push({"front":"le cycle","back":"cycle"});
b.push({"front":"une immigration","back":"immigration"});
b.push({"front":"débarquer","back":"to unload, land, disembark"});
b.push({"front":"une alimentation","back":"diet, food, groceries, supply"});
b.push({"front":"le recours","back":"resort, recourse"});
b.push({"front":"une inspection","back":"inspection"});
b.push({"front":"le coton","back":"cotton"});
b.push({"front":"le féminin","back":"feminine"});
b.push({"front":"intégrer","back":"to integrate"});
b.push({"front":"le créateur","back":"creator"});
b.push({"front":"comporter","back":"to comprise, include; to behave"});
b.push({"front":"prononcer","back":"to pronounce"});
b.push({"front":"étouffer","back":"to suffocate, smother, muffle"});
b.push({"front":"maîtriser","back":"to control, overcome, master"});
b.push({"front":"supprimer","back":"to remove, withdraw_"});
b.push({"front":"insulter","back":"to insult"});
b.push({"front":"une ironie","back":"irony"});
b.push({"front":"habituellement","back":"usually, generally"});
b.push({"front":"envisager","back":"to view, contemplate"});
b.push({"front":"le régiment","back":"regiment"});
b.push({"front":"transférer","back":"to transfer"});
b.push({"front":"le vapeur, la vapeur","back":"vapor, steam, steamship"});
b.push({"front":"décrocher","back":"to take down, take off, pick up, lift"});
b.push({"front":"un éditeur","back":"publisher, editor"});
b.push({"front":"imposer","back":"to impose"});
b.push({"front":"la guise","back":"wish; like, by way of"});
b.push({"front":"un écho","back":"echo"});
b.push({"front":"pénétrer","back":"to penetrate"});
b.push({"front":"la tonne","back":"ton"});
b.push({"front":"le comique","back":"comical; comic, comedian"});
b.push({"front":"formé","back":"formed"});
b.push({"front":"la colonie","back":"colony"});
b.push({"front":"élégant","back":"elegant, stylish"});
b.push({"front":"rigoler","back":"to laugh,"});
b.push({"front":"un obstacle","back":"obstacle"});
b.push({"front":"le confort","back":"comfort"});
b.push({"front":"obliger","back":"to require, force, oblige"});
b.push({"front":"imaginaire","back":"imaginary"});
b.push({"front":"revivre","back":"to live again, come back life, revive"});
b.push({"front":"céder","back":"to give up, give way"});
b.push({"front":"un acheteur","back":"buyer, purchaser"});
b.push({"front":"échouer","back":"to fail"});
b.push({"front":"la littérature","back":"literature"});
b.push({"front":"embarquer","back":"to embark, board, take on board, load"});
b.push({"front":"la démission","back":"resignation"});
b.push({"front":"le coude","back":"elbow"});
b.push({"front":"la permanence","back":"permanence, duty, service"});
b.push({"front":"mentionner","back":"to mention"});
b.push({"front":"repasser","back":"to cross again, retake, show again, iron"});
b.push({"front":"la conséquence","back":"consequence"});
b.push({"front":"la réflexion","back":"reflection"});
b.push({"front":"le ski","back":"ski, skiing"});
b.push({"front":"le bœuf","back":"ox, steer, beef"});
b.push({"front":"la sûreté","back":"safety, reliability"});
b.push({"front":"le phénomène","back":"phenomenon"});
b.push({"front":"soulever","back":"to lift up"});
b.push({"front":"déterminé","back":"determined, resolute, specific"});
b.push({"front":"le logiciel","back":"software, program, application"});
b.push({"front":"une étiquette","back":"label, ticket, etiquette, sticker, tag"});
b.push({"front":"la coupure","back":"the cut, the cutting"});
b.push({"front":"la clôture","back":"enclosure; termination, closure"});
b.push({"front":"la prudence","back":"prudence, care, caution"});
b.push({"front":"apparaître","back":"to appear"});
b.push({"front":"procéder","back":"to proceed"});
b.push({"front":"mériter","back":"to deserve, merit"});
b.push({"front":"une intégrité","back":"integrity"});
b.push({"front":"un actif","back":"active"});
b.push({"front":"un enthousiasme","back":"enthusiasm, enthusiastically"});
b.push({"front":"un atout","back":"trump, asset"});
b.push({"front":"le calcul","back":"calculation"});
b.push({"front":"le volume","back":"volume"});
b.push({"front":"une alternative","back":"alternative, choice"});
b.push({"front":"adapter","back":"to adapt"});
b.push({"front":"la condamnation","back":"condemnation"});
b.push({"front":"une utilisation","back":"the use"});
b.push({"front":"une apparition","back":"appearance, apparition"});
b.push({"front":"le chrétien","back":"Christian"});
b.push({"front":"encourager","back":"to encourage"});
b.push({"front":"soulager","back":"to relieve, soothe, ease"});
b.push({"front":"entretenir","back":"to maintain"});
b.push({"front":"la définition","back":"definition"});
b.push({"front":"gai","back":"cheerful, merry, gay"});
b.push({"front":"supplémentaire","back":"additional"});
b.push({"front":"un arbitre, une arbitre","back":"referee, arbitrer, arbitrator"});
b.push({"front":"spatial","back":"spatial, space"});
b.push({"front":"honteux","back":"ashamed, shameful"});
b.push({"front":"la gestion","back":"management"});
b.push({"front":"économiser","back":"to save, save on, conserve"});
b.push({"front":"nuire","back":"to harm"});
b.push({"front":"le retrait","back":"the withdrawal"});
b.push({"front":"un éclat","back":"splinter, fragment, brightness, burst"});
b.push({"front":"mécanique","back":"mechanical"});
b.push({"front":"un architecte, une architecte","back":"architect"});
b.push({"front":"une épidémie","back":"epidemic"});
b.push({"front":"le mou","back":"soft"});
b.push({"front":"déchirer","back":"to tear up, tear, rip"});
b.push({"front":"la richesse","back":"wealth, richness"});
b.push({"front":"une indépendance","back":"independence"});
b.push({"front":"la dépense","back":"expense, expenditure"});
b.push({"front":"le sportif","back":"sports, athletic, competitive"});
b.push({"front":"reprocher","back":"to blame, reproach"});
b.push({"front":"un exemplaire","back":"exemplary; copy"});
b.push({"front":"la catégorie","back":"category"});
b.push({"front":"le terrorisme","back":"terrorism"});
b.push({"front":"une assemblée","back":"assembly, meeting"});
b.push({"front":"un égard","back":"consideration, respect, regard"});
b.push({"front":"le mètre","back":"meter"});
b.push({"front":"le décor","back":"scenery, décor, set"});
b.push({"front":"un horizon","back":"horizon, skyline"});
b.push({"front":"épouvantable","back":"terrible, appalling, dreadful"});
b.push({"front":"la grandeur","back":"size, greatness"});
b.push({"front":"écarter","back":"to separate, move apart, keep away"});
b.push({"front":"agressif","back":"aggressive"});
b.push({"front":"le prophète","back":"prophet"});
b.push({"front":"aérien","back":"aerial"});
b.push({"front":"une initiative","back":"initiative"});
b.push({"front":"garantir","back":"to guarantee"});
b.push({"front":"noter","back":"to note, notice"});
b.push({"front":"le logement","back":"accommodation"});
b.push({"front":"bloquer","back":"to block"});
b.push({"front":"muet","back":"mute, silent, dumb"});
b.push({"front":"le semestre","back":"semester, six-month period"});
b.push({"front":"le brutal","back":"brutal"});
b.push({"front":"quelquefois","back":"sometimes"});
b.push({"front":"plaisanter","back":"to joke"});
b.push({"front":"le mythe","back":"myth"});
b.push({"front":"parvenir","back":"to reach, achieve"});
b.push({"front":"un optimiste, une optimiste","back":"optimistic"});
b.push({"front":"la représentation","back":"representation"});
b.push({"front":"le fouet","back":"whip"});
b.push({"front":"économique","back":"economic, economical"});
b.push({"front":"enfoncer","back":"to ram, drive in, hammer in, sink in"});
b.push({"front":"haïr","back":"to detest, hate, abhor"});
b.push({"front":"la racine","back":"root"});
b.push({"front":"la patte","back":"paw, foot, leg"});
b.push({"front":"posséder","back":"to possess, own, have"});
b.push({"front":"un outil","back":"tool"});
b.push({"front":"le reportage","back":"report, reporting"});
b.push({"front":"récent","back":"recent"});
b.push({"front":"la constitution","back":"constitution"});
b.push({"front":"contenir","back":"to contain"});
b.push({"front":"doubler","back":"to double, pass; to dub"});
b.push({"front":"pleuvoir","back":"to rain"});
b.push({"front":"la certitude","back":"certainty"});
b.push({"front":"le conséquent","back":"logical, rational, consistent"});
b.push({"front":"adresser","back":"to address"});
b.push({"front":"le bilan","back":"balance sheet, outcome"});
b.push({"front":"gravement","back":"seriously, solemnly, gravely"});
b.push({"front":"un argument","back":"argument"});
b.push({"front":"la banlieue","back":"suburbs, outskirts"});
b.push({"front":"le curé","back":"parish priest"});
b.push({"front":"la convention","back":"agreement, convention"});
b.push({"front":"un excès","back":"excess, surplus, abuse"});
b.push({"front":"le rassemblement","back":"gathering, collecting, assembling"});
b.push({"front":"souffler","back":"to blow, puff"});
b.push({"front":"accélérer","back":"to speed up, accelerate"});
b.push({"front":"le quotidien","back":"daily"});
b.push({"front":"encaisser","back":"to receive, collect, cash"});
b.push({"front":"jurer","back":"to swear"});
b.push({"front":"ironique","back":"ironic"});
b.push({"front":"croiser","back":"to cross"});
b.push({"front":"le paysage","back":"landscape, scenery, countryside"});
b.push({"front":"la province","back":"province"});
b.push({"front":"spirituel","back":"witty, spiritual, sacred"});
b.push({"front":"supplier","back":"to beg, implore"});
b.push({"front":"mesurer","back":"to measure"});
b.push({"front":"le convoi","back":"convoy, train"});
b.push({"front":"touchant","back":"with regard to, concerning, touching, moving"});
b.push({"front":"la psychologie","back":"psychology"});
b.push({"front":"un isolement","back":"loneliness, isolation, insulation"});
b.push({"front":"contenter","back":"to satisfy, please"});
b.push({"front":"la perspective","back":"perspective, viewpoint"});
b.push({"front":"la discrétion","back":"discretion"});
b.push({"front":"largement","back":"widely"});
b.push({"front":"modifier","back":"to modify, adjust"});
b.push({"front":"le visiteur","back":"visitor"});
b.push({"front":"une obligation","back":"obligation, bond"});
b.push({"front":"la pâte","back":"paste, dough, pasta"});
b.push({"front":"le combattant","back":"fighter"});
b.push({"front":"percer","back":"to pierce, drill, break into"});
b.push({"front":"corriger","back":"to correct"});
b.push({"front":"le contexte","back":"context"});
b.push({"front":"poster","back":"poster; to post, mail"});
b.push({"front":"la conception","back":"conception"});
b.push({"front":"le dépit","back":"spite, heartache"});
b.push({"front":"le bassin","back":"bowl, basin"});
b.push({"front":"le continent","back":"continent"});
b.push({"front":"la fiction","back":"fiction"});
b.push({"front":"le trait","back":"line, feature"});
b.push({"front":"le tournant","back":"revolving, swivel, encircling, bend, turning point"});
b.push({"front":"une avancée","back":"advanced, overhung"});
b.push({"front":"le mouton","back":"sheep"});
b.push({"front":"le croyant","back":"believer"});
b.push({"front":"la croissance","back":"growth"});
b.push({"front":"le commencement","back":"beginning, start"});
b.push({"front":"la compréhension","back":"understanding, comprehension"});
b.push({"front":"le porteur","back":"carrier, holder"});
b.push({"front":"la réduction","back":"reduction"});
b.push({"front":"le triomphe","back":"triumph"});
b.push({"front":"fortement","back":"strongly"});
b.push({"front":"piloter","back":"to fly, pilot, drive"});
b.push({"front":"le majeur","back":"major"});
b.push({"front":"vanter","back":"to vaunt, boast, brag"});
b.push({"front":"viser","back":"to aim"});
b.push({"front":"le flux","back":"flow"});
b.push({"front":"le nœud","back":"knot"});
b.push({"front":"municipal","back":"municipal"});
b.push({"front":"la distribution","back":"distribution"});
b.push({"front":"le renseignement","back":"information"});
b.push({"front":"la fidélité","back":"loyalty, faithfulness, accuracy, reliability"});
b.push({"front":"la trêve","back":"truce"});
b.push({"front":"secouer","back":"to shake"});
b.push({"front":"le bijou","back":"jewel"});
b.push({"front":"la satisfaction","back":"satisfaction"});
b.push({"front":"toutefois","back":"however"});
b.push({"front":"la concurrence","back":"competition"});
b.push({"front":"visible","back":"visible, obvious"});
b.push({"front":"la signification","back":"significance"});
b.push({"front":"suggérer","back":"to suggest"});
b.push({"front":"le survivant","back":"survivor, surviving"});
b.push({"front":"le vieillard","back":"old man"});
b.push({"front":"nommer","back":"to call, name, appoint"});
b.push({"front":"un horaire","back":"schedule, timetable, hourly"});
b.push({"front":"le réacteur","back":"reactor, jet engine"});
b.push({"front":"rétablir","back":"to restore, re-establish"});
b.push({"front":"le bénéfice","back":"benefit, profit"});
b.push({"front":"un organisme","back":"organism"});
b.push({"front":"condamner","back":"to condemn"});
b.push({"front":"librement","back":"freely"});
b.push({"front":"une harmonie","back":"harmony"});
b.push({"front":"défaire","back":"to undo, dismantle, strip, break up"});
b.push({"front":"la diffusion","back":"diffusion, spreading, circulation"});
b.push({"front":"le visa","back":"visa, stamp"});
b.push({"front":"la déception","back":"disappointment, let-down"});
b.push({"front":"le milliard","back":"billion, thousand million"});
b.push({"front":"envoler","back":"to fly away, fly off, take off"});
b.push({"front":"la générosité","back":"generosity, generously"});
b.push({"front":"plaider","back":"to plead"});
b.push({"front":"reproduire","back":"to reproduce, repeat"});
b.push({"front":"deuxièmement","back":"secondly"});
b.push({"front":"le péril","back":"peril"});
b.push({"front":"le tremblement","back":"shiver, trembling, shaking"});
b.push({"front":"rassurer","back":"to reassure, calm down"});
b.push({"front":"romain","back":"Roman"});
b.push({"front":"toxique","back":"toxic, toxin"});
b.push({"front":"la vérification","back":"check, verification"});
b.push({"front":"le reproche","back":"reproach"});
b.push({"front":"le protecteur","back":"protective, protector, guardian"});
b.push({"front":"presser","back":"to squeeze, press"});
b.push({"front":"une impatience","back":"impatience"});
b.push({"front":"verser","back":"to pour, deposit, shed"});
b.push({"front":"un infini","back":"inifinite, infinity"});
b.push({"front":"amical","back":"friendly"});
b.push({"front":"flou","back":"blurred, fuzzy, vague"});
b.push({"front":"le danseur","back":"dancer"});
b.push({"front":"semer","back":"to sow, scatter, spread"});
b.push({"front":"appliquer","back":"to apply"});
b.push({"front":"indiquer","back":"to indicate, signal"});
b.push({"front":"un acquis","back":"acquired, experience"});
b.push({"front":"le sinistre","back":"disaster, sinister"});
b.push({"front":"jadis","back":"formerly, long ago"});
b.push({"front":"supposer","back":"to suppose, assume"});
b.push({"front":"le climat","back":"climate"});
b.push({"front":"soviétique","back":"Soviet"});
b.push({"front":"un intermédiaire, une intermédiaire","back":"intermediate, intermediary"});
b.push({"front":"le séminaire","back":"seminar, seminary"});
b.push({"front":"principalement","back":"principally, mainly, primarily"});
b.push({"front":"conserver","back":"to keep, preserve"});
b.push({"front":"quarante","back":"forty"});
b.push({"front":"le bulletin","back":"bulletin, report"});
b.push({"front":"un extrait","back":"extract, excerpt"});
b.push({"front":"défier","back":"to challenge, defy, distrust"});
b.push({"front":"boucler","back":"to fasten, loop, resolve"});
b.push({"front":"la pauvreté","back":"poverty"});
b.push({"front":"une embauche","back":"job vacancy, hiring"});
b.push({"front":"le recul","back":"backward movement, setback, slip"});
b.push({"front":"valoir","back":"to be worth"});
b.push({"front":"la précision","back":"precision"});
b.push({"front":"indispensable","back":"essential"});
b.push({"front":"harceler","back":"to harass, plague"});
b.push({"front":"le comble","back":"despair; summit, overmeasure; roof"});
b.push({"front":"le cliché","back":"cliché; negative"});
b.push({"front":"anormal","back":"abnormal"});
b.push({"front":"crédible","back":"credible"});
b.push({"front":"un ouvrier","back":"worker"});
b.push({"front":"procurer","back":"to get, bring"});
b.push({"front":"une installation","back":"installation, setup"});
b.push({"front":"la révélation","back":"diclosure, revelation"});
b.push({"front":"un immédiat","back":"immediate"});
b.push({"front":"introduire","back":"to introduce"});
b.push({"front":"hostile","back":"hostile"});
b.push({"front":"le préfet","back":"prefect"});
b.push({"front":"insister","back":"to insist"});
b.push({"front":"soumettre","back":"to submit"});
b.push({"front":"une inscription","back":"registration, enrolment; engraving"});
b.push({"front":"épais","back":"thick, pitch dark, thickly"});
b.push({"front":"anéantir","back":"to annihilate, wipe out, ruin, vanish"});
b.push({"front":"lier","back":"to link, join"});
b.push({"front":"embaucher","back":"to hire"});
b.push({"front":"étendre","back":"to spread out, stretch out"});
b.push({"front":"citer","back":"to quote"});
b.push({"front":"la marée","back":"tide"});
b.push({"front":"indépendant","back":"independent"});
b.push({"front":"le culte","back":"worship, cult"});
b.push({"front":"le mépris","back":"contempt, scorn, disdain"});
b.push({"front":"une utilité","back":"use, usefulness,"});
b.push({"front":"emmerder","back":"to bug, bother"});
b.push({"front":"préférable","back":"preferable"});
b.push({"front":"une épargne","back":"savings, saving"});
b.push({"front":"la sympathie","back":"liking, warmth, friendship, sympathie"});
b.push({"front":"bancaire","back":"banking"});
b.push({"front":"un exclu, une exclu","back":"outcast"});
b.push({"front":"aborder","back":"to reach, approach"});
b.push({"front":"la motivation","back":"motivation, application"});
b.push({"front":"la gamme","back":"range, scale"});
b.push({"front":"massacrer","back":"to slaughter, massacre"});
b.push({"front":"conquérir","back":"to conquer"});
b.push({"front":"suffire","back":"to be sufficient, suffice"});
b.push({"front":"le pavillon","back":"country house, villa, wing pavilliion, flag"});
b.push({"front":"jouir","back":"to enjoy"});
b.push({"front":"exercer","back":"to exercise, exert, practise, carry out"});
b.push({"front":"tenant","back":"tenant; incumbent, holder"});
b.push({"front":"plier","back":"to fold, fold up, fold back, bend"});
b.push({"front":"une application","back":"application"});
b.push({"front":"la librairie","back":"bookstore, bookshop"});
b.push({"front":"une opposition","back":"opposition"});
b.push({"front":"atomique","back":"atomic"});
b.push({"front":"convenable","back":"suitable, appropriate, correct, proper, acceptable"});
b.push({"front":"la précaution","back":"precaution"});
b.push({"front":"la contribution","back":"contribution"});
b.push({"front":"volontairement","back":"voluntarily, willingly"});
b.push({"front":"asiatique","back":"Asian"});
b.push({"front":"le communiqué","back":"communiqué, release, statement"});
b.push({"front":"répandre","back":"to spread, spill"});
b.push({"front":"passionnant","back":"fascinating, exciting"});
b.push({"front":"rejeter","back":"to reject"});
b.push({"front":"le semblable, la semblable","back":"similar"});
b.push({"front":"reconstruire","back":"to rebuild, reconstruct"});
b.push({"front":"le poumon","back":"lung"});
b.push({"front":"distribuer","back":"to distribute, give out"});
b.push({"front":"pratiquer","back":"to practice"});
b.push({"front":"le banquier","back":"banker"});
b.push({"front":"le globe","back":"globe"});
b.push({"front":"achever","back":"to complete, finish, end"});
b.push({"front":"le repère","back":"reference, benchmark, landmark"});
b.push({"front":"équitable","back":"equitable, fair"});
b.push({"front":"admirer","back":"to admire"});
b.push({"front":"la tranche","back":"slice, edge, section, bracket, slot"});
b.push({"front":"la thèse","back":"thesis, argument"});
b.push({"front":"un orgueil","back":"pride"});
b.push({"front":"baigner","back":"to bathe, wash, get a bath, go for a swim"});
b.push({"front":"le millier","back":"thousand"});
b.push({"front":"briller","back":"to shine"});
b.push({"front":"ambitieux","back":"ambitious, man with ambition"});
b.push({"front":"le cheveu","back":"hair"});
b.push({"front":"une onde","back":"wave"});
b.push({"front":"inacceptable","back":"unacceptabe"});
b.push({"front":"un explosif","back":"explosive"});
b.push({"front":"la distorsion","back":"distortion"});
b.push({"front":"le septième, la septième","back":"seventh"});
b.push({"front":"la bulle","back":"bubble"});
b.push({"front":"une ignorance","back":"ignorance"});
b.push({"front":"inattendu","back":"unexpected"});
b.push({"front":"la franchise","back":"frankness, exemption, duty-free, franchise, deductible"});
b.push({"front":"évaluer","back":"to evaluate"});
b.push({"front":"similaire","back":"similar"});
b.push({"front":"un itinéraire","back":"itinerary, route"});
b.push({"front":"disposer","back":"to arrange, set"});
b.push({"front":"extraire","back":"to extract, mine, quarry, pull out, remove"});
b.push({"front":"allié","back":"allied; ally"});
b.push({"front":"fréquenter","back":"to frequent, go around with"});
b.push({"front":"la citation","back":"quote, quotation, citation"});
b.push({"front":"détourner","back":"to redirect"});
b.push({"front":"le reflet","back":"reflection, glint, highlight"});
b.push({"front":"le lecteur","back":"reader"});
b.push({"front":"le nazi","back":"Nazi"});
b.push({"front":"tracer","back":"to draw, write, mark out"});
b.push({"front":"la cote","back":"rating, share index, quoted value"});
b.push({"front":"éclairer","back":"to light up"});
b.push({"front":"la vingtaine","back":"about twenty"});
b.push({"front":"le révolutionnaire, la révolutionnaire","back":"revolutionary"});
b.push({"front":"un aire, une aire","back":"surface, area"});
b.push({"front":"mélanger","back":"to mix, mix up, confuse"});
b.push({"front":"naïf","back":"naïve, innocent"});
b.push({"front":"méfier","back":"to distrust, mistrust"});
b.push({"front":"le phare","back":"lighthouse, headlight"});
b.push({"front":"un adolescent","back":"teenager, adolescent"});
b.push({"front":"le coût","back":"cost"});
b.push({"front":"le gène","back":"gene"});
b.push({"front":"la session","back":"session"});
b.push({"front":"un envoi","back":"sending, dispatching"});
b.push({"front":"la consultation","back":"consultation"});
b.push({"front":"un universitaire, une universitaire","back":"university, academic"});
b.push({"front":"exploiter","back":"to exploit"});
b.push({"front":"absolu","back":"absolute"});
b.push({"front":"creux","back":"hollow, empty, hole"});
b.push({"front":"la notion","back":"notion"});
b.push({"front":"prétendu","back":"so-called, alleged"});
b.push({"front":"bâtir","back":"to build"});
b.push({"front":"découper","back":"to carve, cut,"});
b.push({"front":"spécifique","back":"specific"});
b.push({"front":"contourner","back":"to bypass, go round"});
b.push({"front":"un enseignement","back":"education, teaching"});
b.push({"front":"la coutume","back":"custom"});
b.push({"front":"une étendue","back":"area, expanse, duration, extent, range"});
b.push({"front":"ôter","back":"to remove, take away, take off, take out"});
b.push({"front":"le blond","back":"blond, fair-haired"});
b.push({"front":"un infirmier","back":"nurse"});
b.push({"front":"barrer","back":"to close, block, bar, cross"});
b.push({"front":"un entrepreneur","back":"contractor, entrepreneur"});
b.push({"front":"permanent","back":"permanent"});
b.push({"front":"la devise","back":"currency, motto, slogan"});
b.push({"front":"identique","back":"identical"});
b.push({"front":"la réparation","back":"repair, repairing, correction, compensation"});
b.push({"front":"musical","back":"musical"});
b.push({"front":"la prostitution","back":"prostitution"});
b.push({"front":"banal","back":"banal, trite, commonplace, ordinary"});
b.push({"front":"le cordon","back":"cord, string, lead"});
b.push({"front":"critiquer","back":"to criticize"});
b.push({"front":"seize","back":"sixteen"});
b.push({"front":"la brèche","back":"breach, gap"});
b.push({"front":"un appui","back":"support"});
b.push({"front":"une entrevue","back":"meeting, interview"});
b.push({"front":"inculper","back":"to charge"});
b.push({"front":"financer","back":"to finance"});
b.push({"front":"persuader","back":"to convince, persuade"});
b.push({"front":"la candidature","back":"application, candidacy, candidature"});
b.push({"front":"la cruauté","back":"cruelty"});
b.push({"front":"unir","back":"to unite"});
b.push({"front":"la transaction","back":"transaction"});
b.push({"front":"le fondé, la fondé","back":"founded, justified; agent, clerk"});
b.push({"front":"un amendement","back":"amendment"});
b.push({"front":"une atteinte","back":"reach; attack, blow"});
b.push({"front":"fatal","back":"fatal, deadly, fateful"});
b.push({"front":"isoler","back":"to isolate, insulate"});
b.push({"front":"traduire","back":"to translate"});
b.push({"front":"la vitrine","back":"window, display cabinet"});
b.push({"front":"le correspondant","back":"correspondent"});
b.push({"front":"une approbation","back":"approval"});
b.push({"front":"mondial","back":"world, global"});
b.push({"front":"la transition","back":"transition"});
b.push({"front":"le consentement","back":"consent"});
b.push({"front":"le parlement","back":"parliament"});
b.push({"front":"spectaculaire","back":"spectacular"});
b.push({"front":"le pêcheur","back":"fisherman"});
b.push({"front":"le détour","back":"bend, curve, detour"});
b.push({"front":"terrestre","back":"land, earth"});
b.push({"front":"une institution","back":"institution"});
b.push({"front":"le polonais","back":"Polish"});
b.push({"front":"immobile","back":"still, motionless"});
b.push({"front":"la tentation","back":"temptation"});
b.push({"front":"la participation","back":"participation"});
b.push({"front":"insensible","back":"insensitive"});
b.push({"front":"une injustice","back":"injustice, unfairness"});
b.push({"front":"nécessairement","back":"necessarily"});
b.push({"front":"réclamer","back":"to ask for, call for; to claim"});
b.push({"front":"le cahier","back":"notebook"});
b.push({"front":"relier","back":"to connect"});
b.push({"front":"enthousiaste","back":"enthusiastic"});
b.push({"front":"une interdiction","back":"ban, banning"});
b.push({"front":"le nocturne","back":"nocturnal, nocturne"});
b.push({"front":"retarder","back":"to delay, hold up"});
b.push({"front":"la suspension","back":"hanging, suspending, breaking off, postponement, suspension"});
b.push({"front":"confiant","back":"trusting, confident"});
b.push({"front":"réserver","back":"to reserve, keep"});
b.push({"front":"strictement","back":"strictly"});
b.push({"front":"le solde, la solde","back":"balance; pay; sale"});
b.push({"front":"un athlète, une athlète","back":"athlete"});
b.push({"front":"un élan","back":"momentum, surge, rush; elk, moose"});
b.push({"front":"une orientation","back":"orientation, trend"});
b.push({"front":"le mécanisme","back":"mechanism"});
b.push({"front":"le masculin","back":"male, masculine"});
b.push({"front":"affirmer","back":"to affirm, maintain, declare, allege"});
b.push({"front":"la négociation","back":"negotiation"});
b.push({"front":"compréhensible","back":"comprehensible, understandable"});
b.push({"front":"effondrer","back":"to collapse, cave in, fall down"});
b.push({"front":"le pôle","back":"pole"});
b.push({"front":"la manifestation","back":"demonstration, event"});
b.push({"front":"la sélection","back":"selection"});
b.push({"front":"un abandon","back":"abandonment, desertion, withdrawal"});
b.push({"front":"obscur","back":"dark, vague, obscure"});
b.push({"front":"obligatoire","back":"mandatory, compulsory"});
b.push({"front":"le paysan","back":"farmer, peasant"});
b.push({"front":"trembler","back":"to shiver, tremble, shake, flicker"});
b.push({"front":"opposer","back":"to oppose"});
b.push({"front":"le désaccord","back":"disagreement, discord, conflict"});
b.push({"front":"le schéma","back":"diagram, outline"});
b.push({"front":"le dirigeant","back":"leader"});
b.push({"front":"une émeute","back":"riot, rioting"});
b.push({"front":"treize","back":"thirteen"});
b.push({"front":"vieillir","back":"to grow old"});
b.push({"front":"un enquêteur","back":"investigator, pollster"});
b.push({"front":"provisoire","back":"temporary, provisional"});
b.push({"front":"amer","back":"bitter"});
b.push({"front":"le fournisseur","back":"supplier, provider"});
b.push({"front":"la fédération","back":"federation"});
b.push({"front":"la recommandation","back":"recommendation"});
b.push({"front":"convaincant","back":"convincing"});
b.push({"front":"détacher","back":"to untie, detach, remove"});
b.push({"front":"gêner","back":"to bother, trouble"});
b.push({"front":"la résolution","back":"resolution"});
b.push({"front":"la juridiction","back":"jurisdiction, court of law"});
b.push({"front":"le fossé","back":"ditch"});
b.push({"front":"intact","back":"intact"});
b.push({"front":"un évêque, une évêque","back":"bishop"});
b.push({"front":"la comparaison","back":"comparison"});
b.push({"front":"la présidence","back":"presidency"});
b.push({"front":"la nécessité","back":"necessity, need"});
b.push({"front":"le malaise","back":"uneasiness, discomfort"});
b.push({"front":"un exil","back":"exile"});
b.push({"front":"consacrer","back":"to devote, consecrate"});
b.push({"front":"une impulsion","back":"impulse, pulse"});
b.push({"front":"une interprétation","back":"interpretation"});
b.push({"front":"délibérément","back":"deliberately"});
b.push({"front":"le terminal","back":"terminal"});
b.push({"front":"affecter","back":"to affect"});
b.push({"front":"le récit","back":"account, narrative"});
b.push({"front":"la clientèle","back":"customers, clientele"});
b.push({"front":"le procédé","back":"processus"});
b.push({"front":"un employeur","back":"employer"});
b.push({"front":"la rive","back":"shore, bank"});
b.push({"front":"divers","back":"diverse, various"});
b.push({"front":"la finance","back":"finance"});
b.push({"front":"gigantesque","back":"gigantic, immense"});
b.push({"front":"une agitation","back":"agitation, excitement"});
b.push({"front":"expulser","back":"to expel, evict, deport, throw out"});
b.push({"front":"le voyageur","back":"traveler"});
b.push({"front":"le suédois","back":"Swedish, Swede"});
b.push({"front":"acceptable","back":"acceptable, satisfactory"});
b.push({"front":"le travailleur","back":"worker"});
b.push({"front":"emparer","back":"to seize, grab, snatch"});
b.push({"front":"neutre","back":"neutral"});
b.push({"front":"une infraction","back":"offence, infrigement, infraction"});
b.push({"front":"parcourir","back":"to cover, travel"});
b.push({"front":"le pair","back":"peer, pair, even"});
b.push({"front":"pleinement","back":"fully, thoroughly"});
b.push({"front":"la collaboration","back":"collaboration"});
b.push({"front":"la transformation","back":"transformation, change"});
b.push({"front":"lointain","back":"distant, faraway"});
b.push({"front":"la faculté","back":"ability, right, option; faculty, university"});
b.push({"front":"le seuil","back":"doorstep, threshold"});
b.push({"front":"faciliter","back":"to make easier, facilitate"});
b.push({"front":"la vocation","back":"vocation, calling"});
b.push({"front":"régulier","back":"regular"});
b.push({"front":"le support","back":"support, stand"});
b.push({"front":"encontre","back":"contrary to"});
b.push({"front":"le néant","back":"nothingness"});
b.push({"front":"la considération","back":"consideration"});
b.push({"front":"le frein","back":"brake"});
b.push({"front":"le déplacement","back":"movement, displacement, trip, travel"});
b.push({"front":"hésiter","back":"to hesitate"});
b.push({"front":"le descendant","back":"downward, descending, descendant"});
b.push({"front":"influencer","back":"to influence"});
b.push({"front":"une aviation","back":"aviation"});
b.push({"front":"dévoiler","back":"to unveil, reveal, disclose"});
b.push({"front":"un autobus","back":"bus"});
b.push({"front":"purement","back":"purely"});
b.push({"front":"manuscrit","back":"manuscript, handwritten"});
b.push({"front":"étroit","back":"narrow, tight"});
b.push({"front":"le kilo","back":"kilo"});
b.push({"front":"audacieux","back":"daring, audacious, bold"});
b.push({"front":"une occupation","back":"occupation, pastime"});
b.push({"front":"défiler","back":"to unthread, parade"});
b.push({"front":"compromettre","back":"to compromise"});
b.push({"front":"planifier","back":"to plan"});
b.push({"front":"activer","back":"to activate, speed up, stoke, get moving"});
b.push({"front":"global","back":"global"});
b.push({"front":"le fonctionnaire, la fonctionnaire","back":"state employee, public servant"});
b.push({"front":"éclaircir","back":"to brighten up, clear up"});
b.push({"front":"delà","back":"beyond, above, over"});
b.push({"front":"la projection","back":"projection, ejection, discharge"});
b.push({"front":"réviser","back":"to review, revise, overhaul"});
b.push({"front":"imiter","back":"to imitate"});
b.push({"front":"la dizaine","back":"approximately ten"});
b.push({"front":"la composition","back":"composition, essay, dialling"});
b.push({"front":"une allusion","back":"allusion"});
b.push({"front":"la lèvre","back":"lip"});
b.push({"front":"un impuissant","back":"powerless, helpless"});
b.push({"front":"envahir","back":"to invade, overrun"});
b.push({"front":"la révolte","back":"revolt"});
b.push({"front":"le cynique, la cynique","back":"cynical, cynic"});
b.push({"front":"une implication","back":"implication"});
b.push({"front":"débattre","back":"to discuss, debate"});
b.push({"front":"le spectre","back":"spectrum, ghost"});
b.push({"front":"le contrôleur","back":"inspector, controller"});
b.push({"front":"la fabrication","back":"manufacture, production"});
b.push({"front":"la préférence","back":"preference, preferably"});
b.push({"front":"la réalisation","back":"realization, achievement"});
b.push({"front":"renforcer","back":"to reinforce, strengthen"});
b.push({"front":"la sensibilité","back":"sensitivity, sensibility"});
b.push({"front":"le soupçon","back":"suspicion"});
b.push({"front":"le rédacteur","back":"editor, writer, drafter, compiler"});
b.push({"front":"odieux","back":"hateful, odious"});
b.push({"front":"la rébellion","back":"rebellion"});
b.push({"front":"une esthétique","back":"aesthetics, attractiveness; attractive"});
b.push({"front":"féroce","back":"ferocious, fierce"});
b.push({"front":"un homosexuel","back":"homosexual"});
b.push({"front":"le trimestre","back":"quarter; three months"});
b.push({"front":"le pourcentage","back":"percentage, commission, cut"});
b.push({"front":"autoriser","back":"to authorize"});
b.push({"front":"chaleureux","back":"warm"});
b.push({"front":"une extraction","back":"extraction"});
b.push({"front":"un organe","back":"organ"});
b.push({"front":"lumineux","back":"luminous, illuminated; light"});
b.push({"front":"quatorze","back":"fourteen"});
b.push({"front":"la navigation","back":"navigation"});
b.push({"front":"la maintenance","back":"maintenance, servicing"});
b.push({"front":"la reprise","back":"resumption, renewal; time"});
b.push({"front":"un armement","back":"arms, weapons, armament"});
b.push({"front":"fonder","back":"to found, set"});
b.push({"front":"vital","back":"vital"});
b.push({"front":"connecter","back":"to connect, go on-line"});
b.push({"front":"préciser","back":"to state, specify, clarify"});
b.push({"front":"le boulevard","back":"boulevard"});
b.push({"front":"le gel","back":"frost, freezing, gel"});
b.push({"front":"un aveu","back":"confession"});
b.push({"front":"un émetteur","back":"transmitter, issuer"});
b.push({"front":"régner","back":"to reign"});
b.push({"front":"le slogan","back":"slogan"});
b.push({"front":"circuler","back":"to drive, circulate"});
b.push({"front":"la pente","back":"slope"});
b.push({"front":"une exploitation","back":"operation, exploitation"});
b.push({"front":"trancher","back":"to cut, sever, settle, decide"});
b.push({"front":"un emprunt","back":"loan"});
b.push({"front":"un opérateur","back":"operator"});
b.push({"front":"la querelle","back":"quarrel"});
b.push({"front":"effectuer","back":"to carry out, undergo"});
b.push({"front":"la tendresse","back":"tenderness, fondness"});
b.push({"front":"annuel","back":"annual"});
b.push({"front":"autrui","back":"others"});
b.push({"front":"la firme","back":"firm"});
b.push({"front":"numérique","back":"numerical"});
b.push({"front":"la consommation","back":"consumption"});
b.push({"front":"un entourage","back":"circle, entourage"});
b.push({"front":"regagner","back":"to win again, regain, get back, make up"});
b.push({"front":"le technicien","back":"technician"});
b.push({"front":"le chancelier","back":"chancellor"});
b.push({"front":"la complicité","back":"complicity"});
b.push({"front":"la trentaine","back":"about thirty"});
b.push({"front":"délivrer","back":"to set free, rid, relieve"});
b.push({"front":"une automobile","back":"automobile"});
b.push({"front":"dresser","back":"to draw up, put up, raise"});
b.push({"front":"un handicapé","back":"disabled, handicapped"});
b.push({"front":"crucial","back":"crucial, critical"});
b.push({"front":"la mutation","back":"transfer, transformation, mutation"});
b.push({"front":"le fondateur","back":"founder"});
b.push({"front":"récolter","back":"to harvest, gather"});
b.push({"front":"une entente","back":"understanding, agreement"});
b.push({"front":"le turc","back":"Turk, Turkish"});
b.push({"front":"un oubli","back":"forgetting, leaving behind, missing"});
b.push({"front":"la mention","back":"mention, note, comment, notice"});
b.push({"front":"le chronique, la chronique","back":"chronic, column, page, chronicle"});
b.push({"front":"dynamique","back":"dynamic"});
b.push({"front":"la maternité","back":"maternity, motherhood"});
b.push({"front":"apercevoir","back":"to see, notice"});
b.push({"front":"scandaleux","back":"scandalous, outrageous"});
b.push({"front":"quasi","back":"almost, nearly"});
b.push({"front":"inquiétant","back":"worrying, disturbing"});
b.push({"front":"brancher","back":"to plug in, connect"});
b.push({"front":"durement","back":"harshly, severely"});
b.push({"front":"hautement","back":"highly"});
b.push({"front":"le kilomètre","back":"kilometer"});
b.push({"front":"abuser","back":"to abuse, mislead, take advantage"});
b.push({"front":"une hausse","back":"rise, raise, increase"});
b.push({"front":"une annulation","back":"cancellation, annulment"});
b.push({"front":"fâcher","back":"to anger, make angry, get angry"});
b.push({"front":"la démarche","back":"walk, process"});
b.push({"front":"susceptible","back":"sensitive, touchy"});
b.push({"front":"mutuellement","back":"mutually, one another"});
b.push({"front":"doré","back":"golden"});
b.push({"front":"le musulman","back":"Muslim, Moslem"});
b.push({"front":"atlantique","back":"Atlantic"});
b.push({"front":"dominer","back":"to dominate"});
b.push({"front":"la motion","back":"motion"});
b.push({"front":"distinguer","back":"to distinguish"});
b.push({"front":"définir","back":"to define"});
b.push({"front":"loger","back":"to put up, accommodate, stay, find accommodation"});
b.push({"front":"clandestin","back":"underground, clandestine"});
b.push({"front":"un axe","back":"axis, axle, main line"});
b.push({"front":"diplomatique","back":"diplomatic"});
b.push({"front":"une architecture","back":"architecture"});
b.push({"front":"vivement","back":"sharply, brusquely, lively"});
b.push({"front":"le républicain","back":"republican"});
b.push({"front":"la détermination","back":"determination, resolution"});
b.push({"front":"photographier","back":"to photograph"});
b.push({"front":"naviguer","back":"to navigate, sail"});
b.push({"front":"le noyau","back":"core, nucleus, pit"});
b.push({"front":"une efficacité","back":"efficiency, effectiveness"});
b.push({"front":"la réciproque","back":"mutual, reciprocal, the opposite"});
b.push({"front":"la provenance","back":"origin, strange"});
b.push({"front":"le dialogue","back":"dialogue"});
b.push({"front":"pertinent","back":"pertinent, relevant"});
b.push({"front":"le touriste, la touriste","back":"tourist"});
b.push({"front":"subtil","back":"subtle, nice"});
b.push({"front":"le politicien","back":"politician"});
b.push({"front":"réjouir","back":"to delight, rejoice"});
b.push({"front":"redoutable","back":"fearsome, formidable"});
b.push({"front":"difficilement","back":"with difficulty"});
b.push({"front":"le fléau","back":"scourge, plague"});
b.push({"front":"le collectif","back":"collective"});
b.push({"front":"la perception","back":"perception, collection"});
b.push({"front":"claquer","back":"to flap, bang, slam, snap"});
b.push({"front":"menaçant","back":"threatening, menacing"});
b.push({"front":"la dépendance","back":"dependence, dependency"});
b.push({"front":"un enseignant","back":"teacher"});
b.push({"front":"prévisible","back":"predictable, forseeable"});
b.push({"front":"le financement","back":"financing"});
b.push({"front":"le savant","back":"scientist, scholar, learned, scholarly, clever, skilfull"});
b.push({"front":"diviser","back":"to divide"});
b.push({"front":"la comptabilité","back":"accountancy, accounting, book-keeping"});
b.push({"front":"le jumeau","back":"twin"});
b.push({"front":"priver","back":"to deprive"});
b.push({"front":"la larme","back":"tear"});
b.push({"front":"assurément","back":"most certainly"});
b.push({"front":"la totalité","back":"totality, entirety"});
b.push({"front":"inférieur","back":"inferior"});
b.push({"front":"un équivalent","back":"equivalent"});
b.push({"front":"le revers","back":"back, reverse, setback"});
b.push({"front":"le supplément","back":"supplement, extra"});
b.push({"front":"imprimer","back":"to print, print out"});
b.push({"front":"intimider","back":"to intimidate"});
b.push({"front":"attentif","back":"attentive, scrupulous, careful"});
b.push({"front":"la crédibilité","back":"credibility"});
b.push({"front":"improbable","back":"unlikely, improbable"});
b.push({"front":"recruter","back":"to recruit"});
b.push({"front":"parallèle","back":"parallel, similar"});
b.push({"front":"une aspiration","back":"aspiration"});
b.push({"front":"le prometteur","back":"promising"});
b.push({"front":"la milice","back":"militia"});
b.push({"front":"la façade","back":"front, façade"});
b.push({"front":"une instruction","back":"instruction, direction"});
b.push({"front":"publiquement","back":"publicly"});
b.push({"front":"un hymne, une hymne","back":"hymn, anthem"});
b.push({"front":"employer","back":"to use, employ"});
b.push({"front":"strict","back":"strict, absolute"});
b.push({"front":"la clause","back":"clause"});
b.push({"front":"interdire","back":"to forbid, prohibit, ban"});
b.push({"front":"exclure","back":"to exclude"});
b.push({"front":"éventuellement","back":"possibly"});
b.push({"front":"antique","back":"antique, ancient"});
b.push({"front":"confondre","back":"to mix up, confuse"});
b.push({"front":"un handicap","back":"handicap"});
b.push({"front":"la famine","back":"famine"});
b.push({"front":"le barreau","back":"bar"});
b.push({"front":"interpréter","back":"to interpret"});
b.push({"front":"le danois","back":"Danish, Dane"});
b.push({"front":"la concession","back":"concession"});
b.push({"front":"une équation","back":"equation"});
b.push({"front":"le golfe","back":"gulf"});
b.push({"front":"rassurant","back":"reassuring, comforting"});
b.push({"front":"caresser","back":"to fondle, caress"});
b.push({"front":"la légion","back":"legion"});
b.push({"front":"désirer","back":"to desire"});
b.push({"front":"le fonctionnement","back":"operation, functioning"});
b.push({"front":"diffuser","back":"to diffuse, broadcast"});
b.push({"front":"concevoir","back":"to conceive"});
b.push({"front":"redire","back":"to say again, repeat"});
b.push({"front":"le sursis","back":"reprieve, deferment"});
b.push({"front":"le monument","back":"monument"});
b.push({"front":"un observateur","back":"observer, observant"});
b.push({"front":"un industriel","back":"industrial"});
b.push({"front":"dissimuler","back":"to conceal, hide"});
b.push({"front":"le préliminaire","back":"preliminary, introductory"});
b.push({"front":"inspirer","back":"to inspire"});
b.push({"front":"précipiter","back":"to quicken, hasten, precipitate"});
b.push({"front":"pencher","back":"to lean, tilt"});
b.push({"front":"évoluer","back":"to evolve"});
b.push({"front":"contrarier","back":"to annoy, bother, thwart"});
b.push({"front":"la propagande","back":"propaganda"});
b.push({"front":"la crête","back":"crest, top, ridge"});
b.push({"front":"une expertise","back":"expertise"});
b.push({"front":"le flot","back":"floodtide, stream of, flood of"});
b.push({"front":"clarifier","back":"to clarify"});
b.push({"front":"la facilité","back":"easiness, ease, aptitude"});
b.push({"front":"le tarif","back":"price, rate, fare, tariff"});
b.push({"front":"tailler","back":"to cut, carve, engrave, sharpen, trim"});
b.push({"front":"la traversée","back":"crossing"});
b.push({"front":"le rival","back":"rival"});
b.push({"front":"compenser","back":"to compensate for, make up for"});
b.push({"front":"le partenariat","back":"partnership"});
b.push({"front":"appartenir","back":"to belong"});
b.push({"front":"le dilemme","back":"dilemma"});
b.push({"front":"remédier","back":"to cure, remedy, put right"});
b.push({"front":"traditionnel","back":"traditional"});
b.push({"front":"subit","back":"sudden"});
b.push({"front":"apaiser","back":"to calm, appease, calm down"});
b.push({"front":"une offensive","back":"offensive, offence"});
b.push({"front":"la conquête","back":"conquest"});
b.push({"front":"prédire","back":"to predict"});
b.push({"front":"proprement","back":"cleanly, neatly, properly"});
b.push({"front":"limiter","back":"to limit"});
b.push({"front":"droguer","back":"to drug, take drugs"});
b.push({"front":"le fabricant, la fabricant","back":"manufacturer"});
b.push({"front":"questionner","back":"to question"});
b.push({"front":"barbare","back":"barbaric; barbarian"});
b.push({"front":"combler","back":"to fill, fill in, fulfill"});
b.push({"front":"un apprentissage","back":"learning, apprenticeship"});
b.push({"front":"le vêtement","back":"garment, item or article of clothing"});
b.push({"front":"fermement","back":"firmly"});
b.push({"front":"définitif","back":"definitive, final"});
b.push({"front":"externe","back":"external, outer"});
b.push({"front":"la succession","back":"succession"});
b.push({"front":"décharger","back":"to unload"});
b.push({"front":"essuyer","back":"to wipe, dry, mop, dust"});
b.push({"front":"canadien","back":"Canadian"});
b.push({"front":"décent","back":"decent, proper"});
b.push({"front":"une admiration","back":"admiration"});
b.push({"front":"le stupéfiant","back":"drug, narcotic; stunning, astounding"});
b.push({"front":"soigneusement","back":"tidily, neatly, carefully"});
b.push({"front":"une ampleur","back":"extent, scope, range"});
b.push({"front":"la tolérance","back":"tolerance"});
b.push({"front":"le yen","back":"yen"});
b.push({"front":"copier","back":"to copy, reproduce"});
b.push({"front":"la probabilité","back":"probability, likelihood"});
b.push({"front":"détecter","back":"to detect"});
b.push({"front":"préoccuper","back":"to worry, preoccupy"});
b.push({"front":"le bagage","back":"luggage, baggage"});
b.push({"front":"un enjeu","back":"stake"});
b.push({"front":"regrettable","back":"unfortunate, regrettable"});
b.push({"front":"blindé","back":"armoured"});
b.push({"front":"la croyance","back":"belief"});
b.push({"front":"concret","back":"concrete"});
b.push({"front":"essentiellement","back":"essentially"});
b.push({"front":"le rejet","back":"rejection"});
b.push({"front":"la rubrique","back":"column, heading, rubric"});
b.push({"front":"agrandir","back":"to enlarge, extend"});
b.push({"front":"ouvertement","back":"openly, overtly"});
b.push({"front":"un islam","back":"Islam"});
b.push({"front":"le renvoi","back":"dismissal, expulsion, suspension, cross-reference"});
b.push({"front":"la prospérité","back":"prosperity"});
b.push({"front":"perturber","back":"to disrupt, disturb"});
b.push({"front":"optique","back":"optical, optic, perspective"});
b.push({"front":"la frustration","back":"frustration"});
b.push({"front":"un exploit","back":"exploit"});
b.push({"front":"la rédaction","back":"writing, composition"});
b.push({"front":"le sonore","back":"sound, resonant, sonorous, voiced"});
b.push({"front":"le souverain","back":"sovereign, supreme ruler, monarch"});
b.push({"front":"inclure","back":"to include"});
b.push({"front":"etc","back":"etc., et cetera"});
b.push({"front":"résumer","back":"to summarize, sum up"});
b.push({"front":"réconcilier","back":"to reconcile"});
b.push({"front":"la perturbation","back":"disruption, disturbance"});
b.push({"front":"brusquement","back":"abruptly, suddenly"});
b.push({"front":"un inconvénient","back":"snag, drawback, disadvantage, inconvenience"});
b.push({"front":"une agriculture","back":"agriculture"});
b.push({"front":"la restauration","back":"restoration; catering"});
b.push({"front":"une amélioration","back":"improvement"});
b.push({"front":"le rétablissement","back":"restoring, re-establishment, recovery"});
b.push({"front":"le titulaire, la titulaire","back":"holder, with tenure, occupant"});
b.push({"front":"une interruption","back":"interruption, break"});
b.push({"front":"le manœuvre, la manœuvre","back":"manoeuvre"});
b.push({"front":"le souterrain","back":"underground, underground passage"});
b.push({"front":"geler","back":"to freeze, ice over, suspend"});
b.push({"front":"le réflexe","back":"reflex"});
b.push({"front":"la rigueur","back":"harshness, severity, rigidness, rigor strictness"});
b.push({"front":"une hiérarchie","back":"hierarchy"});
b.push({"front":"hormis","back":"save, but"});
b.push({"front":"restaurer","back":"to restore, feed"});
b.push({"front":"redonner","back":"to give back, return, give more"});
b.push({"front":"la courbe","back":"curve, curved"});
b.push({"front":"remporter","back":"to take away, win"});
b.push({"front":"retomber","back":"to fall again, fall down again"});
b.push({"front":"le comédien","back":"comedian, comedy"});
b.push({"front":"correspondre","back":"to correspond"});
b.push({"front":"la reproduction","back":"reproduction"});
b.push({"front":"déguiser","back":"to disguise"});
b.push({"front":"le vocabulaire","back":"vocabulary"});
b.push({"front":"flotter","back":"to float, hang, stream"});
b.push({"front":"comparaître","back":"to appear"});
b.push({"front":"une estimation","back":"appraisal, valuation, assessment, estimate"});
b.push({"front":"la douane","back":"customs, duty"});
b.push({"front":"souple","back":"supple, agile, soft, floppy, flexible"});
b.push({"front":"la manipulation","back":"handling, manipulation"});
b.push({"front":"tolérer","back":"to tolerate, access, put up, bear, endure"});
b.push({"front":"constater","back":"to note, notice; to establish, certify"});
b.push({"front":"un analyste, une analyste","back":"analyst"});
b.push({"front":"grandissant","back":"growing, increasing"});
b.push({"front":"la contrainte","back":"constraint"});
b.push({"front":"médiocre","back":"mediocre, second-rate"});
b.push({"front":"la dérive","back":"drift"});
b.push({"front":"automatiquement","back":"automatically"});
b.push({"front":"le philosophe, la philosophe","back":"philosopher"});
b.push({"front":"le diplomate, la diplomate","back":"diplomat, diplomatic"});
b.push({"front":"la pétition","back":"petition"});
b.push({"front":"le conservateur","back":"conservative"});
b.push({"front":"suspendre","back":"to suspend, postpone"});
b.push({"front":"le radical","back":"radical"});
b.push({"front":"improviser","back":"to improvise"});
b.push({"front":"organique","back":"organic"});
b.push({"front":"le recrutement","back":"recruiting, recruitment"});
b.push({"front":"une hésitation","back":"hesitation"});
b.push({"front":"le défenseur, la défenseur","back":"defender"});
b.push({"front":"peser","back":"to weigh"});
b.push({"front":"africain","back":"African"});
b.push({"front":"le tourisme","back":"tourism, sightseeing"});
b.push({"front":"écrouler","back":"to collapse, tumble"});
b.push({"front":"le démocrate, la démocrate","back":"democrat, democratic"});
b.push({"front":"associer","back":"to associate"});
b.push({"front":"le soixante","back":"sixty"});
b.push({"front":"compétent","back":"competent"});
b.push({"front":"une intensité","back":"intensity"});
b.push({"front":"la sincérité","back":"sincerity"});
b.push({"front":"artificiel","back":"artificial"});
b.push({"front":"le symptôme","back":"symptom"});
b.push({"front":"opérationnel","back":"operational, operating"});
b.push({"front":"démontrer","back":"to demonstrate"});
b.push({"front":"la nomination","back":"appointment, nomination"});
b.push({"front":"flagrant","back":"blatant, glaring"});
b.push({"front":"le portugais","back":"Portuguese"});
b.push({"front":"grossir","back":"to get larger"});
b.push({"front":"le magistrat","back":"magistrate, judge"});
b.push({"front":"rédiger","back":"to write, draw up"});
b.push({"front":"recommander","back":"to recommend"});
b.push({"front":"le détachement","back":"detachment"});
b.push({"front":"la formalité","back":"formality"});
b.push({"front":"acquérir","back":"to acquire"});
b.push({"front":"le dixième, la dixième","back":"tenth"});
b.push({"front":"le parquet","back":"parquet floor, hardwood floor, prosecutor’s office"});
b.push({"front":"composer","back":"to compose, dial"});
b.push({"front":"olympique","back":"Olympic"});
b.push({"front":"la compétence","back":"competence"});
b.push({"front":"applaudir","back":"to clap, applaud"});
b.push({"front":"le délinquant","back":"delinquent, offender"});
b.push({"front":"le litre, la litre","back":"litre"});
b.push({"front":"le légume, la légume","back":"vegetable"});
b.push({"front":"le publicitaire, la publicitaire","back":"advertising, promotional"});
b.push({"front":"la reconstruction","back":"reconstruction"});
b.push({"front":"exécutif","back":"executive"});
b.push({"front":"le prélèvement","back":"imposition, levying, withdrawal, removal, deduction"});
b.push({"front":"le tirage","back":"drawing, circulation, run"});
b.push({"front":"européen","back":"European"});
b.push({"front":"le bourgeois","back":"middle class"});
b.push({"front":"le sondage","back":"poll"});
b.push({"front":"stratégique","back":"strategic"});
b.push({"front":"oser","back":"to dare"});
b.push({"front":"agiter","back":"to shake, disturb"});
b.push({"front":"favorable","back":"favorable"});
b.push({"front":"alerter","back":"to alert, inform, warn"});
b.push({"front":"la criminalité","back":"crime"});
b.push({"front":"insignifiant","back":"insignificant, unimportant"});
b.push({"front":"brut","back":"raw, crude"});
b.push({"front":"une actualité","back":"current events, news"});
b.push({"front":"tantôt","back":"this afternoon, sometimes"});
b.push({"front":"recueillir","back":"to collect, gather"});
b.push({"front":"le dictionnaire","back":"dictionary"});
b.push({"front":"le remplacement","back":"replacement, standing in"});
b.push({"front":"culturel","back":"cultural"});
b.push({"front":"le chercheur","back":"researcher"});
b.push({"front":"la défaillance","back":"fault, failure, breakdown, blackout, weakness"});
b.push({"front":"inverser","back":"to reverse, invert"});
b.push({"front":"manifester","back":"to show, demonstrate, display"});
b.push({"front":"cultiver","back":"to cultivate, grow"});
b.push({"front":"la stabilité","back":"stability"});
b.push({"front":"confronter","back":"to confront"});
b.push({"front":"un huitième, une huitième","back":"eighth"});
b.push({"front":"repenser","back":"to rethink"});
b.push({"front":"décevant","back":"disappointing"});
b.push({"front":"un effondrement","back":"collapse, caving-in, falling-in, breaking-down"});
b.push({"front":"signifier","back":"to mean"});
b.push({"front":"relance","back":"boost, reminder, recovery"});
b.push({"front":"balayer","back":"to sweep up, sweep out"});
b.push({"front":"la compensation","back":"compensation, clearing"});
b.push({"front":"la confrontation","back":"confrontation"});
b.push({"front":"gonfler","back":"to inflate, blow up, swell"});
b.push({"front":"le gain","back":"gain"});
b.push({"front":"le partiel","back":"partial"});
b.push({"front":"la clarté","back":"lightness, brightness clearness, clarity"});
b.push({"front":"relativement","back":"relatively"});
b.push({"front":"convertir","back":"to convert"});
b.push({"front":"poétique","back":"poetic, poetical, poetics"});
b.push({"front":"compliquer","back":"to complicate"});
b.push({"front":"une expansion","back":"expansion"});
b.push({"front":"continu","back":"continuous"});
b.push({"front":"le résident","back":"foreign national, foreign resident"});
b.push({"front":"planer","back":"to glide, soar"});
b.push({"front":"le routier","back":"road, long-distance lorry or truck driver"});
b.push({"front":"hanter","back":"to haunt"});
b.push({"front":"une introduction","back":"introduction"});
b.push({"front":"diminuer","back":"to diminish, decrease"});
b.push({"front":"le sceptique, la sceptique","back":"sceptical, sceptic"});
b.push({"front":"rouvrir","back":"to reopen"});
b.push({"front":"la vigueur","back":"vigor"});
b.push({"front":"le paragraphe","back":"paragraph"});
b.push({"front":"respectueux","back":"respectful"});
b.push({"front":"infliger","back":"to inflict"});
b.push({"front":"apte","back":"capable"});
b.push({"front":"une extension","back":"extension, stretching, expansion"});
b.push({"front":"maternel","back":"motherly, maternal"});
b.push({"front":"le bénévole, la bénévole","back":"volunteer, voluntary, unpaid"});
b.push({"front":"bénéfique","back":"beneficial"});
b.push({"front":"notamment","back":"notably"});
b.push({"front":"constant","back":"constant"});
b.push({"front":"littéraire","back":"literary"});
b.push({"front":"la tribune","back":"platform, forum, gallery"});
b.push({"front":"sévèrement","back":"severely, harshly"});
b.push({"front":"troublant","back":"disturbing"});
b.push({"front":"brièvement","back":"briefly"});
b.push({"front":"le bombardement","back":"bombing, shelling"});
b.push({"front":"la récupération","back":"recovery, retrieval, salvage"});
b.push({"front":"le classement","back":"classification, ranking"});
b.push({"front":"le résistant","back":"robust, sturdy, resistance fighter"});
b.push({"front":"le remboursement","back":"reimbursement"});
b.push({"front":"promouvoir","back":"to promote"});
b.push({"front":"un impôt","back":"tax"});
b.push({"front":"contredire","back":"to contradict"});
b.push({"front":"longuement","back":"at length"});
b.push({"front":"le forum","back":"forum, newsgroup"});
b.push({"front":"le successeur","back":"successor"});
b.push({"front":"le placement","back":"investment, placing"});
b.push({"front":"brutalement","back":"brutally"});
b.push({"front":"gouverner","back":"to govern, rule, steer, helm"});
b.push({"front":"sanglant","back":"bloody, cruel, covered in blood"});
b.push({"front":"calculer","back":"to calculate"});
b.push({"front":"la distinction","back":"distinction"});
b.push({"front":"une exploration","back":"exploration, investigation, examination"});
b.push({"front":"originaire","back":"original, first, native to"});
b.push({"front":"aspirer","back":"to breathe in, inhale, aspire to"});
b.push({"front":"le blocage","back":"block"});
b.push({"front":"superficiel","back":"superficial, shallow"});
b.push({"front":"la vieillesse","back":"old age"});
b.push({"front":"le timbre","back":"to stamp"});
b.push({"front":"injecter","back":"to inject"});
b.push({"front":"le croissant","back":"growing, crescent, crescent-shape"});
b.push({"front":"pénal","back":"penal"});
b.push({"front":"le concurrent","back":"competitor, rival"});
b.push({"front":"prioritaire","back":"priority, having priority, having right of way"});
b.push({"front":"la taxe","back":"tax"});
b.push({"front":"autoritaire","back":"authoritarian"});
b.push({"front":"exiger","back":"to require, demand"});
b.push({"front":"la trame","back":"weft, framework; tram"});
b.push({"front":"exciter","back":"to arouse, waken, excite, turn on"});
b.push({"front":"la discrimination","back":"discrimination"});
b.push({"front":"refermer","back":"to close again, shut again, close up"});
b.push({"front":"le pilier","back":"pillar"});
b.push({"front":"miser","back":"to bet, stake"});
b.push({"front":"approuver","back":"to approve"});
b.push({"front":"distant","back":"far-off, distant, faraway"});
b.push({"front":"alimenter","back":"to feed, supply"});
b.push({"front":"user","back":"to wear out, wear away, use up"});
b.push({"front":"intellectuel","back":"intellectual"});
b.push({"front":"une insuffisance","back":"inadequacy, insufficiency"});
b.push({"front":"liquider","back":"to liquidate, sell off, clear"});
b.push({"front":"collaborer","back":"to collaborate, contribute"});
b.push({"front":"stabiliser","back":"to stabilize"});
b.push({"front":"un administrateur","back":"administrator"});
b.push({"front":"le raisonnement","back":"reasoning"});
b.push({"front":"un ouvrage","back":"work"});
b.push({"front":"le massif","back":"massive"});
b.push({"front":"la félicitation","back":"congratulation"});
b.push({"front":"la nouveauté","back":"novelty, new release"});
b.push({"front":"débuter","back":"to start"});
b.push({"front":"une uni","back":"united"});
b.push({"front":"aggraver","back":"to worsen, aggravate"});
b.push({"front":"excessif","back":"excessive, inordinate"});
b.push({"front":"exigeant","back":"demanding, difficult"});
b.push({"front":"éprouver","back":"to feel, experience"});
b.push({"front":"la décennie","back":"decade"});
b.push({"front":"émettre","back":"to emit, issue"});
b.push({"front":"classer","back":"to classify, file, grade, rate"});
b.push({"front":"ajuster","back":"to adjust, alter, aim, aim at"});
b.push({"front":"une incapacité","back":"incompetence, incapability"});
b.push({"front":"considérable","back":"considerable, significant"});
b.push({"front":"le racisme","back":"racism"});
b.push({"front":"relancer","back":"to throw back, restart, relaunch"});
b.push({"front":"politiquement","back":"politically, diplomatically"});
b.push({"front":"une annexe","back":"annex, appendix, related issue"});
b.push({"front":"un instituteur","back":"school teacher"});
b.push({"front":"une affectation","back":"appointment, allocation; show, pretence"});
b.push({"front":"une entité","back":"entity"});
b.push({"front":"songer","back":"to dream"});
b.push({"front":"un éloge","back":"praise"});
b.push({"front":"le meuble","back":"piece of furniture"});
b.push({"front":"la solidarité","back":"solidarity"});
b.push({"front":"une espérance","back":"hope"});
b.push({"front":"le délégué","back":"delegate"});
b.push({"front":"la réforme","back":"reform"});
b.push({"front":"prolonger","back":"to prolong, extend"});
b.push({"front":"contrer","back":"to counter"});
b.push({"front":"protester","back":"to protest"});
b.push({"front":"prochainement","back":"shortly, soon"});
b.push({"front":"symbolique","back":"symbolic"});
b.push({"front":"une élimination","back":"elimination"});
b.push({"front":"enrichir","back":"to expand, enrich, make somebody rich"});
b.push({"front":"primitif","back":"primitive"});
b.push({"front":"un uranium","back":"uranium"});
b.push({"front":"la sérénité","back":"serenity, peacefulness"});
b.push({"front":"démocratique","back":"democratic"});
b.push({"front":"ordonner","back":"to ordain, organize, order"});
b.push({"front":"le retraité","back":"retired"});
b.push({"front":"la préoccupation","back":"worry, concern"});
b.push({"front":"pharmaceutique","back":"pharmaceutical"});
b.push({"front":"redresser","back":"to straighten, set right, redress, turn around"});
b.push({"front":"la progression","back":"progression"});
b.push({"front":"progresser","back":"to progress"});
b.push({"front":"contribuer","back":"to contribute"});
b.push({"front":"choquer","back":"to shock, offend, shake, disturb"});
b.push({"front":"la consigne","back":"deposit, orders, detention"});
b.push({"front":"le dictateur","back":"dictator"});
b.push({"front":"une extrémité","back":"end, extremity"});
b.push({"front":"expérimental","back":"experimental"});
b.push({"front":"fréquent","back":"frequent"});
b.push({"front":"précoce","back":"early, precocious"});
b.push({"front":"compléter","back":"to complete"});
b.push({"front":"régional","back":"regional"});
b.push({"front":"capter","back":"to pick up, capture, tap"});
b.push({"front":"le communisme","back":"communism"});
b.push({"front":"récompenser","back":"to reward, recompense"});
b.push({"front":"la pollution","back":"pollution"});
b.push({"front":"évoquer","back":"to recall, evoke"});
b.push({"front":"une hostilité","back":"hostility, hostilities"});
b.push({"front":"énergétique","back":"energic, vigorous"});
b.push({"front":"le licenciement","back":"dismissal, sacking"});
b.push({"front":"prématuré","back":"premature"});
b.push({"front":"mécontent","back":"discontented, dissatisfied, displeased"});
b.push({"front":"décisif","back":"decisive"});
b.push({"front":"la circonstance","back":"circumstance"});
b.push({"front":"une inondation","back":"flood, deluge"});
b.push({"front":"le déploiement","back":"deployment, spreading, unfurling, display"});
b.push({"front":"le millénaire","back":"millennium, thousand-year- old"});
b.push({"front":"le maintien","back":"holding, maintaining"});
b.push({"front":"une interrogation","back":"question, interviewing, interrogation, questioning, test"});
b.push({"front":"virtuel","back":"virtual, potential"});
b.push({"front":"une hépatite","back":"hepatitis"});
b.push({"front":"universel","back":"universal"});
b.push({"front":"afficher","back":"to display"});
b.push({"front":"la variété","back":"variety"});
b.push({"front":"le décret","back":"decree"});
b.push({"front":"un optimisme","back":"optimism"});
b.push({"front":"rentable","back":"profitable"});
b.push({"front":"un abbé","back":"abbot, priest"});
b.push({"front":"bousculer","back":"to knock over, knock into"});
b.push({"front":"la prestation","back":"benefit"});
b.push({"front":"une éventualité","back":"eventuality, possibility"});
b.push({"front":"le spectateur","back":"member of the audience, spectator, onlooker"});
b.push({"front":"le terrien","back":"earthling; landowner, countryman"});
b.push({"front":"un investisseur","back":"investor"});
b.push({"front":"génétiquement","back":"genetically"});
b.push({"front":"la sphère","back":"sphere"});
b.push({"front":"renouveler","back":"to renew"});
b.push({"front":"la rapidité","back":"speed, quickness"});
b.push({"front":"élémentaire","back":"elementary, rudimentary, basic"});
b.push({"front":"élargir","back":"to widen, expand"});
b.push({"front":"comparable","back":"comparable"});
b.push({"front":"communautaire","back":"community, communal"});
b.push({"front":"éveiller","back":"to arouse, stimulate, awaken"});
b.push({"front":"la réconciliation","back":"reconciliation"});
b.push({"front":"rationnel","back":"rational"});
b.push({"front":"le fondement","back":"foundation"});
b.push({"front":"le capitalisme","back":"capitalism"});
b.push({"front":"un ancêtre, une ancêtre","back":"ancestor, forerunner"});
b.push({"front":"durable","back":"durable, long-lasting"});
b.push({"front":"la domination","back":"domination, dominion, rule"});
b.push({"front":"la révision","back":"review, revision, overhaul"});
b.push({"front":"indifférent","back":"indifferent, unconcerned, unimportant"});
b.push({"front":"la publication","back":"publication"});
b.push({"front":"vigilant","back":"vigilant, watchful"});
b.push({"front":"un habitant","back":"inhabitant"});
b.push({"front":"la censure","back":"censorship"});
b.push({"front":"le transparent","back":"transparent, see-through, evident"});
b.push({"front":"la mœurs","back":"morals, customs, habits, manners, ways"});
b.push({"front":"absorber","back":"to absorb, remove, take up, take over"});
b.push({"front":"maritime","back":"maritime"});
b.push({"front":"naval","back":"naval"});
b.push({"front":"une envergure","back":"wingspan, breadth, scope"});
b.push({"front":"la simplicité","back":"simplicity, straightforwardness"});
b.push({"front":"brouiller","back":"to mix-up, confuse, scramble"});
b.push({"front":"le dépens","back":"expense"});
b.push({"front":"un approvisionnement","back":"supply, supplies, stock, supplying, stocking"});
b.push({"front":"veuf","back":"surviving spouse"});
b.push({"front":"vocal","back":"vocal"});
b.push({"front":"lourdement","back":"heavily"});
b.push({"front":"belge","back":"Belgian"});
b.push({"front":"rayer","back":"to scratch, streak, stripe; to erase, strike out"});
b.push({"front":"satisfaisant","back":"satisfactory, satisfying"});
b.push({"front":"le déclin","back":"decline, deterioration"});
b.push({"front":"humanitaire","back":"humanitarian"});
b.push({"front":"fatiguer","back":"to tire, get tired"});
b.push({"front":"invoquer","back":"to call upon"});
b.push({"front":"véritablement","back":"truly, really"});
b.push({"front":"coûteux","back":"expensive, costly"});
b.push({"front":"une aptitude","back":"ability"});
b.push({"front":"la délégation","back":"delegation"});
b.push({"front":"la minorité","back":"minority"});
b.push({"front":"le promoteur","back":"promoter, instigator, developer"});
b.push({"front":"désigner","back":"to designate"});
b.push({"front":"le patrimoine","back":"heritage, assets"});
b.push({"front":"le loisir","back":"leisure"});
b.push({"front":"imminent","back":"imminent, impending"});
b.push({"front":"le combustible","back":"fuel, combustible"});
b.push({"front":"ménager","back":"to handle, arrange; domestic"});
b.push({"front":"nettement","back":"clearly, distinctly"});
b.push({"front":"motiver","back":"to justify, account for, motivate"});
b.push({"front":"hériter","back":"to inherit"});
b.push({"front":"un accessoire","back":"accessory"});
b.push({"front":"programmer","back":"to program, schedule"});
b.push({"front":"élire","back":"to elect"});
b.push({"front":"un intervalle","back":"space, distance, interval"});
b.push({"front":"expédier","back":"to send, dispatch"});
b.push({"front":"viable","back":"viable, workable"});
b.push({"front":"réputé","back":"famous, renowned"});
b.push({"front":"exagérer","back":"to exaggerate, overdo"});
b.push({"front":"conforme","back":"conform"});
b.push({"front":"la programmation","back":"programming"});
b.push({"front":"reconduire","back":"to renew, drive back"});
b.push({"front":"accessible","back":"accessible, approachable"});
b.push({"front":"le passif","back":"passive, liabilities"});
b.push({"front":"une intégration","back":"integration"});
b.push({"front":"anticiper","back":"to anticipate, foresee, look or think ahead"});
b.push({"front":"estimer","back":"to estimate; to consider, deem"});
b.push({"front":"la rénovation","back":"renovation, restoration"});
b.push({"front":"prélever","back":"to impose, levy, withdraw, remove"});
b.push({"front":"encourageant","back":"encouraging"});
b.push({"front":"dépendre","back":"to depend"});
b.push({"front":"corrompre","back":"to corrupt, bribe"});
b.push({"front":"bombarder","back":"to bomb"});
b.push({"front":"conformément","back":"in accordance"});
b.push({"front":"initial","back":"initial"});
b.push({"front":"le déchet","back":"scrap, waste, trash, garbage"});
b.push({"front":"la rhétorique","back":"rhetorical, rhetoric"});
b.push({"front":"le génocide","back":"genocide"});
b.push({"front":"climatique","back":"climatic"});
b.push({"front":"consommer","back":"to eat, consume, drink, use, consummate"});
b.push({"front":"un encouragement","back":"encouragement"});
b.push({"front":"la provocation","back":"provocation"});
b.push({"front":"reconstituer","back":"to reconstitute, restore, reconstruct"});
b.push({"front":"incompréhensible","back":"incomprehensible"});
b.push({"front":"attribuer","back":"to award, grant, attribute"});
b.push({"front":"le biais","back":"way, device; bias"});
b.push({"front":"la dictature","back":"dictatorship"});
b.push({"front":"catastrophique","back":"catastrophic, disastrous"});
b.push({"front":"chuter","back":"to fall"});
b.push({"front":"le socialiste, la socialiste","back":"socialist"});
b.push({"front":"prescrire","back":"to order, command, prescribe, stipulate"});
b.push({"front":"abriter","back":"to shelter, shade"});
b.push({"front":"sanitaire","back":"health, sanitary, medical"});
b.push({"front":"la diplomatie","back":"diplomacy"});
b.push({"front":"exclusivement","back":"exclusively, solely"});
b.push({"front":"le suspens","back":"suspension, abeyance"});
b.push({"front":"la norme","back":"norm, standard"});
b.push({"front":"un aval","back":"downstream, downhill"});
b.push({"front":"le graphique, la graphique","back":"graph, graphic"});
b.push({"front":"une indifférence","back":"indifference"});
b.push({"front":"intolérable","back":"intolerable"});
b.push({"front":"médiatique","back":"media"});
b.push({"front":"propice","back":"favorable, auspicious propitious"});
b.push({"front":"la portion","back":"portion, share"});
b.push({"front":"une interface","back":"interface"});
b.push({"front":"purger","back":"to purge, bleed, drain"});
b.push({"front":"sombrer","back":"to darken; to sink, lapse"});
b.push({"front":"expérimenter","back":"to experiment"});
b.push({"front":"la fixation","back":"fixation, fixing"});
b.push({"front":"le commerçant","back":"shopkeeper, merchant, commercial"});
b.push({"front":"théoriquement","back":"theoretically"});
b.push({"front":"le quota","back":"quota"});
b.push({"front":"le composant","back":"component, constituent"});
b.push({"front":"la mortalité","back":"mortality, death rate"});
b.push({"front":"le déficit","back":"deficit"});
b.push({"front":"la sécheresse","back":"dryness, drought"});
b.push({"front":"le palier","back":"landing, level, flat"});
b.push({"front":"la cinquantaine","back":"about fifty"});
b.push({"front":"la protestation","back":"protest, protestation"});
b.push({"front":"la nationalité","back":"nationality"});
b.push({"front":"un animateur","back":"animator, host"});
b.push({"front":"relire","back":"to reread, proofread"});
b.push({"front":"appliqué","back":"assiduous, industrious, careful"});
b.push({"front":"soucieux","back":"concerned, worried"});
b.push({"front":"heurter","back":"to strike, hit, collide"});
b.push({"front":"convenir","back":"to agree, be suitable"});
b.push({"front":"stimuler","back":"to stimulate"});
b.push({"front":"issu","back":"descended from"});
b.push({"front":"dicter","back":"to dictate, lay down"});
b.push({"front":"dépendant","back":"answerable, responsible, dependent"});
b.push({"front":"défini","back":"definite"});
b.push({"front":"touristique","back":"holiday, tourist"});
b.push({"front":"ficher","back":"to file; to make fun of, not care, not give a damn"});
b.push({"front":"la coalition","back":"coalition"});
b.push({"front":"déduire","back":"to deduct, deduce, infer, figure out"});
b.push({"front":"occidental","back":"western"});
b.push({"front":"spontané","back":"spontaneous"});
b.push({"front":"cerner","back":"to surround, encircle, delimit"});
b.push({"front":"disperser","back":"to scatter, spread, disperse"});
b.push({"front":"fondamentalement","back":"basically, fundamentally, inherently"});
b.push({"front":"le pessimiste, la pessimiste","back":"pessimistic; pessimist"});
b.push({"front":"entamer","back":"to start"});
b.push({"front":"périr","back":"to perish"});
b.push({"front":"cohérent","back":"coherent"});
b.push({"front":"urbain","back":"urban"});
b.push({"front":"le rail","back":"rail, track"});
b.push({"front":"la mentalité","back":"mentality"});
b.push({"front":"un oral","back":"oral"});
b.push({"front":"rigide","back":"rigid, stiff"});
b.push({"front":"conjugal","back":"conjugal, married"});
b.push({"front":"une avalanche","back":"avalanche"});
b.push({"front":"le négociateur","back":"negotiator"});
b.push({"front":"un égyptien","back":"Egyptian"});
b.push({"front":"la mathématique","back":"mathematical; mathematics"});
b.push({"front":"formel","back":"formal, definite"});
b.push({"front":"dominant","back":"dominant, prevailing"});
b.push({"front":"troubler","back":"to disturb, disrupt, cloud"});
b.push({"front":"qualifier","back":"to qualify"});
b.push({"front":"la justesse","back":"accuracy, precision"});
b.push({"front":"un attachement","back":"attachment, affection"});
b.push({"front":"transit","back":"transit"});
b.push({"front":"un hebdomadaire","back":"weekly"});
b.push({"front":"freiner","back":"to brake, slow down"});
b.push({"front":"épuiser","back":"to exhaust, tire out, wear out, use up"});
b.push({"front":"le repli","back":"bend, twist, wrinkle, fold, fallback"});
b.push({"front":"une acquisition","back":"acquisition, acquire, purchase"});
b.push({"front":"la spéculation","back":"speculation"});
b.push({"front":"incertain","back":"uncertain, unsure"});
b.push({"front":"contester","back":"to contest, question"});
b.push({"front":"le démarrage","back":"start, moving off"});
b.push({"front":"inciter","back":"to incite, encourage"});
b.push({"front":"mutuel","back":"mutual"});
b.push({"front":"une indication","back":"indication"});
b.push({"front":"souligner","back":"to underline, stress"});
b.push({"front":"le gendarme, la gendarme","back":"policeman"});
b.push({"front":"masquer","back":"to mask, conceal, put on a mask"});
b.push({"front":"étonner","back":"to astonish, amaze"});
b.push({"front":"le débit","back":"debit, turnover, delivery, rate"});
b.push({"front":"une acceptation","back":"acceptance"});
b.push({"front":"étaler","back":"to spread, display, apply"});
b.push({"front":"un impératif","back":"need, necessity, urgent, imperative"});
b.push({"front":"commenter","back":"to comment"});
b.push({"front":"agricole","back":"agricultural, farming"});
b.push({"front":"visée","back":"aim, design, sighting"});
b.push({"front":"administratif","back":"administrative"});
b.push({"front":"réfugier","back":"to take refuge"});
b.push({"front":"clore","back":"to close"});
b.push({"front":"un édifice","back":"building"});
b.push({"front":"ravir","back":"to delight, rob"});
b.push({"front":"le préjudice","back":"loss, harm, damage"});
b.push({"front":"la fraction","back":"fraction"});
b.push({"front":"le récepteur","back":"receiver, receiving"});
b.push({"front":"la répression","back":"repression, suppression, crack-down"});
b.push({"front":"la lunette","back":"telescope, glasses"});
b.push({"front":"une incertitude","back":"uncertainty"});
b.push({"front":"dérouler","back":"to unwind, enroll"});
b.push({"front":"technologique","back":"technological"});
b.push({"front":"abstenir","back":"to abstain, refrain"});
b.push({"front":"différencier","back":"to differentiate"});
b.push({"front":"enclin","back":"enclined, prone"});
b.push({"front":"la conversion","back":"conversion"});
b.push({"front":"le surplus","back":"surplus"});
b.push({"front":"le prédécesseur","back":"predecessor"});
b.push({"front":"basculer","back":"to topple, fall over, knock off"});
b.push({"front":"la méfiance","back":"distrust, mistrust, suspicion"});
b.push({"front":"significatif","back":"significative"});
b.push({"front":"autonome","back":"autonomous, independent"});
b.push({"front":"un organisateur","back":"organiser, organising"});
b.push({"front":"exclusif","back":"exclusive, sole"});
b.push({"front":"administrer","back":"to manage, run, administer; to give"});
b.push({"front":"insuffisant","back":"insufficient, inadequate"});
b.push({"front":"convoquer","back":"to call, summon"});
b.push({"front":"le serbe","back":"Serbian"});
b.push({"front":"soupçonner","back":"to suspect"});
b.push({"front":"bénéficier","back":"to benefit"});
b.push({"front":"une échéance","back":"expiration date, date of payment, deadline"});
b.push({"front":"le libéral","back":"liberal"});
b.push({"front":"aligner","back":"to lign up, align"});
b.push({"front":"la caractéristique","back":"characteristic"});
b.push({"front":"simultanément","back":"simultaneously"});
b.push({"front":"adéquat","back":"appropriate, suitable, adequate"});
b.push({"front":"armer","back":"to arm"});
b.push({"front":"la diversité","back":"diversity"});
b.push({"front":"recouvrir","back":"to cover, hide, conceal"});
b.push({"front":"déployer","back":"to deploy, open"});
b.push({"front":"décourager","back":"to discourage, dishearten, lose heart"});
b.push({"front":"allier","back":"to ally, match, unite"});
b.push({"front":"la coordination","back":"coordination"});
b.push({"front":"la précipitation","back":"haste, precipitation"});
b.push({"front":"projeter","back":"to plan, project, throw out"});
b.push({"front":"considérablement","back":"considerably, significantly, extensively"});
b.push({"front":"dépouiller","back":"to skin, strip away, deprive, analyze"});
b.push({"front":"notoire","back":"notorious, well-known"});
b.push({"front":"théorique","back":"theoretical"});
b.push({"front":"prestigieux","back":"prestigious"});
b.push({"front":"partiellement","back":"partly"});
b.push({"front":"élaborer","back":"to work out, develop"});
b.push({"front":"renier","back":"to disown, repudiate, go back on"});
b.push({"front":"postal","back":"postal, mail"});
b.push({"front":"insérer","back":"to insert"});
b.push({"front":"négliger","back":"to neglect"});
b.push({"front":"bouleverser","back":"to upset, distress, disturb, turn upside down"});
b.push({"front":"emprisonner","back":"to imprison, jail, put in jail, trap"});
b.push({"front":"propager","back":"to propagate, spread"});
b.push({"front":"abaisser","back":"to pull down, lower, reduce"});
b.push({"front":"le versement","back":"payment"});
b.push({"front":"présidentiel","back":"presidential"});
b.push({"front":"natal","back":"native, home"});
b.push({"front":"un affrontement","back":"clash, confrontation"});
b.push({"front":"le format","back":"format"});
b.push({"front":"opportun","back":"timely,"});
b.push({"front":"dissoudre","back":"to dissolve, disband, break up"});
b.push({"front":"la sanction","back":"sanction"});
b.push({"front":"un utilisateur","back":"user"});
b.push({"front":"le paradoxe","back":"paradox"});
b.push({"front":"un occupant","back":"occupant, occupier, occupying"});
b.push({"front":"radioactif","back":"radioactive"});
b.push({"front":"surgir","back":"to spring up"});
b.push({"front":"un éventail","back":"fan, range"});
b.push({"front":"avérer","back":"to prove to be, turn out"});
b.push({"front":"affaiblir","back":"to weaken"});
b.push({"front":"le bénéficiaire, la bénéficiaire","back":"beneficiary"});
b.push({"front":"appréhender","back":"to dread, apprehend"});
b.push({"front":"la contrepartie","back":"counterpart, opposite, alternative"});
b.push({"front":"la pénurie","back":"shortage"});
b.push({"front":"éminent","back":"eminent, distinguished"});
b.push({"front":"enchaîner","back":"to chain up, connect, string together"});
b.push({"front":"contaminer","back":"to contaminate, infect"});
b.push({"front":"le synonyme","back":"synonymous; synonym"});
b.push({"front":"préférer","back":"to prefer"});
b.push({"front":"déborder","back":"to overflow, boil over, go out, go over"});
b.push({"front":"la compression","back":"compression; cutback, reduction"});
b.push({"front":"aboutir","back":"to succeed, end up at"});
b.push({"front":"la charte","back":"charter"});
b.push({"front":"primordial","back":"primordial, basic, vital, primary"});
b.push({"front":"la ressource","back":"resource"});
b.push({"front":"la quinzaine","back":"about fifteen, two weeks"});
b.push({"front":"singulier","back":"unique, singular"});
b.push({"front":"couramment","back":"fluently, commonly"});
b.push({"front":"la vigilance","back":"vigilance, watchfulness"});
b.push({"front":"pourvoir","back":"to provide, equip, supply, furnish"});
b.push({"front":"générer","back":"to generate"});
b.push({"front":"une accélération","back":"acceleration"});
b.push({"front":"écouler","back":"to sell, run off, flow out"});
b.push({"front":"la borne","back":"milestone, boundary stone"});
b.push({"front":"le rapprochement","back":"bringing together, coming closer, parallel"});
b.push({"front":"baptiser","back":"to name, christen, baptize"});
b.push({"front":"bannir","back":"to banish, ban"});
b.push({"front":"vraisemblablement","back":"most probably"});
b.push({"front":"couronner","back":"to crown, award"});
b.push({"front":"peut-être","back":"perhaps, maybe"});
b.push({"front":"aujourd’hui","back":"today"});
b.push({"front":"concerner","back":"to concern"});
b.push({"front":"d’abord","back":"first of all"});
b.push({"front":"importer","back":"to import; to be important"});
b.push({"front":"constituer","back":"to constitute"});
b.push({"front":"lui-même","back":"himself"});
b.push({"front":"c’est-à-dire","back":"in other words"});
b.push({"front":"d’ailleurs","back":"moreover, besides, for that matter"});
b.push({"front":"d’après","back":"according to"});
b.push({"front":"d’accord","back":"okay, alright"});
b.push({"front":"demeurer","back":"to remain, live"});
b.push({"front":"quelqu’un","back":"somebody, someone"});
b.push({"front":"situer","back":"to situate, locate"});
b.push({"front":"figurer","back":"to represent, appear"});
b.push({"front":"le mai","back":"May"});
b.push({"front":"susciter","back":"to arouse, provoke"});
b.push({"front":"consister","back":"to consist"});
b.push({"front":"destiner","back":"to intend, be used"});
b.push({"front":"relatif","back":"relative"});
b.push({"front":"entreprendre","back":"to begin, start, undertake"});
b.push({"front":"au-delà","back":"beyond"});
b.push({"front":"parlementaire","back":"parliamentary; member of parliament"});
b.push({"front":"palestinien","back":"Palestinian"});
b.push({"front":"fondamental","back":"fundamental"});
b.push({"front":"une exigence","back":"demand, strictness"});
b.push({"front":"après-midi","back":"afternoon"});
b.push({"front":"vis-à-vis","back":"face to face, regarding"});
b.push({"front":"elle-même","back":"herself, itself"});
b.push({"front":"législatif","back":"legislative"});
b.push({"front":"favoriser","back":"to favor"});
b.push({"front":"précéder","back":"to precede"});
b.push({"front":"israélien","back":"Israeli"});
b.push({"front":"au-dessus","back":"above"});
b.push({"front":"d’autant","back":"since"});
b.push({"front":"entourer","back":"to surround"});
b.push({"front":"accroître","back":"to increase"});
b.push({"front":"moi-même","back":"myself"});
b.push({"front":"provenir","back":"to be from, come from"});
b.push({"front":"la modification","back":"modification"});
b.push({"front":"la prévision","back":"forecast, prediction, expectation"});
b.push({"front":"fiscal","back":"fiscal"});
b.push({"front":"une exportation","back":"export"});
b.push({"front":"percevoir","back":"to perceive"});
b.push({"front":"le consommateur","back":"consumer, customer"});
b.push({"front":"un abri","back":"shelter"});
b.push({"front":"baser","back":"to base"});
b.push({"front":"électoral","back":"electoral"});
b.push({"front":"porte-parole","back":"spokesperson, spokes- woman, spokesman"});
b.push({"front":"la vacance","back":"vacancy; vacation"});
b.push({"front":"monétaire","back":"monetary"});
b.push({"front":"un euro","back":"euro"});
b.push({"front":"là-bas","back":"over there, out there"});
b.push({"front":"doter","back":"to endow, provide"});
b.push({"front":"vice-président","back":"vice-president"});
b.push({"front":"un effectif","back":"effective; size, workforce"});
b.push({"front":"individuel","back":"individual"});
b.push({"front":"rendez-vous","back":"appointment"});
b.push({"front":"refléter","back":"to reflect"});
b.push({"front":"animer","back":"to lead, conduct, animate"});
b.push({"front":"la statistique","back":"statistics, statistical"});
b.push({"front":"gouvernemental","back":"governmental"});
b.push({"front":"irakien","back":"Iraqi"});
b.push({"front":"la proportion","back":"proportion"});
b.push({"front":"le critère","back":"criterion, criteria"});
b.push({"front":"illustrer","back":"to illustrate"});
b.push({"front":"formuler","back":"to formulate"});
b.push({"front":"un électeur","back":"elector, voter"});
b.push({"front":"varier","back":"to vary, change"});
b.push({"front":"québécois","back":"Quebecker, Quebecer, Québécois"});
b.push({"front":"multiplier","back":"to multiply"});
b.push({"front":"budgétaire","back":"budgetary"});
b.push({"front":"spécialiser","back":"to specialize"});
b.push({"front":"éventuel","back":"possible"});
b.push({"front":"le partisan","back":"partisan, supporter"});
b.push({"front":"efforcer","back":"endeavor"});
b.push({"front":"détenir","back":"to hold, detain"});
b.push({"front":"le multiple","back":"multiple"});
b.push({"front":"désoler","back":"to upset, sadden"});
b.push({"front":"résider","back":"to reside"});
b.push({"front":"le volet","back":"shutter"});
b.push({"front":"résulter","back":"to result"});
b.push({"front":"survenir","back":"to occur, take place, appear"});
b.push({"front":"le salarié, la salarié","back":"wage-earning, employee"});
b.push({"front":"orienter","back":"to position, give advice, direct, orientate"});
b.push({"front":"croître","back":"to grow, increase"});
b.push({"front":"contraindre","back":"to compel, force"});
b.push({"front":"le réformiste, la réformiste","back":"reformist"});
b.push({"front":"hausser","back":"to raise"});
b.push({"front":"le provincial","back":"provincial"});
b.push({"front":"répartir","back":"to distribute, spread out, share out, divide up"});
b.push({"front":"là-dessus","back":"on top, about it"});
b.push({"front":"nécessiter","back":"to require, necessitate"});
b.push({"front":"la revendication","back":"claim, demand"});
b.push({"front":"constitutionnel","back":"constitutional"});
b.push({"front":"une importation","back":"import"});
b.push({"front":"le référendum","back":"referendum"});
b.push({"front":"une instance","back":"authority, proceedings, hearing"});
b.push({"front":"recourir","back":"to turn to, run again"});
b.push({"front":"engendrer","back":"to father, breed, generate"});
b.push({"front":"une infrastructure","back":"infrastructure"});
b.push({"front":"la cotisation","back":"subscription"});
b.push({"front":"une affirmation","back":"assertion, affirmation"});
b.push({"front":"requérir","back":"to require"});
b.push({"front":"un agriculteur","back":"farmer"});
b.push({"front":"une inflation","back":"inflation"});
b.push({"front":"une autonomie","back":"autonomy"});
b.push({"front":"la contradiction","back":"contradiction"});
b.push({"front":"la souveraineté","back":"sovereignty"});
b.push({"front":"restreindre","back":"to restrict, cut down, decrease"});
b.push({"front":"présider","back":"to preside"});
b.push({"front":"un autochtone, une autochtone","back":"native, indigenous peoples"});
b.push({"front":"le rendement","back":"yield, output"});
b.push({"front":"une innovation","back":"innovation"});
b.push({"front":"la collectivité","back":"community, group"});
b.push({"front":"modalité","back":"mode, method, modality"});
b.push({"front":"le préalable","back":"prior, previous, preliminary, prerequisite"});
b.push({"front":"caractériser","back":"to characterize"});
b.push({"front":"intituler","back":"to entitle, call"});
b.push({"front":"le collaborateur","back":"associate, fellow worker, contributor, collaborator"});
b.push({"front":"accumuler","back":"to accumulate, amass, store, stockpile"});
b.push({"front":"week-end","back":"weekend"});
b.push({"front":"regrouper","back":"to group together, regroup"});
b.push({"front":"le militant","back":"militant"});
b.push({"front":"le participant","back":"participant"});
b.push({"front":"privilégier","back":"to favour"});
b.push({"front":"dater","back":"to date"});
b.push({"front":"la circonscription","back":"district, constituency"});
b.push({"front":"la subvention","back":"subsidy"});
b.push({"front":"équilibrer","back":"to balance"});
b.push({"front":"quelques-uns","back":"some, a few"});
b.push({"front":"solliciter","back":"to request, solicit, appeal"});
b.push({"front":"la prévention","back":"prevention, custody"});
b.push({"front":"complémentaire","back":"complementary, supplementary"});
b.push({"front":"parisien","back":"Parisian"});
b.push({"front":"respectif","back":"respective"});
b.push({"front":"contemporain","back":"contemporary"});
b.push({"front":"le pétrolier","back":"oil; oil tanker"});
b.push({"front":"la suppression","back":"deletion, suppression"});
b.push({"front":"existant","back":"existing"});
b.push({"front":"la restriction","back":"restriction"});
b.push({"front":"un indicateur","back":"indicator"});
b.push({"front":"la législation","back":"legislation"});
b.push({"front":"approprier","back":"to adapt, appropriate, take over"});
b.push({"front":"le chômeur","back":"unemployed person"});
b.push({"front":"succéder","back":"to succeed, take over"});
b.push({"front":"le paramètre","back":"parameter"});
b.push({"front":"déboucher","back":"to unblock, uncork"});
b.push({"front":"la répartition","back":"distribution, spreading"});
b.push({"front":"combiner","back":"to combine, devise"});
b.push({"front":"le contribuable, la contribuable","back":"taxpayer"});
b.push({"front":"progressivement","back":"progressively"});
b.push({"front":"antérieur","back":"previous, earlier, front"});
b.push({"front":"progressif","back":"progressive"});
b.push({"front":"une adhésion","back":"membership, support"});
b.push({"front":"détailler","back":"to detail"});
b.push({"front":"présumer","back":"to presume, assume"});
b.push({"front":"rigoureux","back":"rigorous, harsh, strict"});
b.push({"front":"revêtir","back":"to take on, assume"});
b.push({"front":"distinct","back":"distinct"});
b.push({"front":"la directive","back":"guideline"});
b.push({"front":"rural","back":"rural"});
b.push({"front":"persister","back":"to persist, keep up, linger"});
b.push({"front":"oriental","back":"Oriental"});
b.push({"front":"consentir","back":"to consent, agree"});
b.push({"front":"la variable","back":"variable"});
b.push({"front":"contradictoire","back":"contradictory, conflicting"});
b.push({"front":"instaurer","back":"to institute, introduce"});
b.push({"front":"revendiquer","back":"to claim"});
b.push({"front":"un accroissement","back":"increase"});
b.push({"front":"la diminution","back":"reduction, decreasing"});
b.push({"front":"la privatisation","back":"privatization"});
b.push({"front":"la réglementation","back":"regulation"});
b.push({"front":"déplorer","back":"to deplore"});
b.push({"front":"mobiliser","back":"to mobilize, call up"});
b.push({"front":"encadrer","back":"to frame, train"});
b.push({"front":"la télécommunication","back":"telecommunication"});
b.push({"front":"un aliment","back":"food"});
b.push({"front":"coordonner","back":"to coordinate"});
b.push({"front":"différer","back":"to differ, vary"});
b.push({"front":"découler","back":"to ensue, follow"});
b.push({"front":"mixte","back":"mixed"});
b.push({"front":"siéger","back":"to sit"});
b.push({"front":"grand-chose","back":"not very much"});
b.push({"front":"la transparence","back":"transparency"});
b.push({"front":"amorcer","back":"to bait, prime, begin, initiate"});
b.push({"front":"la productivité","back":"productivity"});
b.push({"front":"simplifier","back":"to simplify"});
b.push({"front":"le scrutin","back":"ballot, poll"});
b.push({"front":"passionner","back":"to fascinate, grip"});
b.push({"front":"généraliser","back":"to generalize"});
b.push({"front":"un économiste, une économiste","back":"economist"});
b.push({"front":"vouer","back":"to devote, dedicate to, vow to"});
b.push({"front":"proclamer","back":"to proclaim, declare"});
b.push({"front":"le monopole","back":"monopoly"});
b.push({"front":"approfondir","back":"to deepen, make deeper, go further into"});
b.push({"front":"syndical","back":"(trade-) union"});
b.push({"front":"un abonné","back":"subscribed, subscriber"});
b.push({"front":"structurel","back":"structural"});
b.push({"front":"dispenser","back":"to exempt, avoid"});
b.push({"front":"le déroulement","back":"development, progress"});
b.push({"front":"régir","back":"to govern"});
b.push({"front":"ministériel","back":"ministerial; minister"});
b.push({"front":"systématiquement","back":"systematically"});
b.push({"front":"équiper","back":"to equip, kit out, fit out, tool up"});
b.push({"front":"le détriment","back":"detriment"});
b.push({"front":"unanime","back":"unanimous"});
b.push({"front":"islamique","back":"Islamic"});
b.push({"front":"une attribution","back":"awarding, allocation, assignment, attribution"});
b.push({"front":"ethnique","back":"ethnic"});
b.push({"front":"un interlocuteur","back":"speaker"});
b.push({"front":"spécifier","back":"to specify"});
b.push({"front":"la rémunération","back":"remuneration, payment, pay"});
b.push({"front":"adhérer","back":"to stick to, support, join, be a member of"});
b.push({"front":"systématique","back":"systematic"});
b.push({"front":"parallèlement","back":"in parallel, similarly"});
b.push({"front":"francophone","back":"French-speaking, French speaker, francophone"});
b.push({"front":"émaner","back":"to issue from, emanate from, come from, radiate from"});
b.push({"front":"prévaloir","back":"to prevail"});
b.push({"front":"apprêter","back":"to prepare, get ready, dress"});
b.push({"front":"cibler","back":"to target"});
b.push({"front":"additionnel","back":"additional"});
b.push({"front":"le consensus","back":"consensus"});
b.push({"front":"un excédent","back":"surplus"});
b.push({"front":"la mondialisation","back":"internationalisation, globalisation"});
b.push({"front":"le conventionnel","back":"conventional"});
b.push({"front":"une unanimité","back":"unanimity"});
b.push({"front":"une inégalité","back":"difference, uneveness, inequality"});
b.push({"front":"accentuer","back":"to stress, to emphasize, become more pronounced"});
b.push({"front":"rattacher","back":"to attach, join, tie"});
b.push({"front":"contracter","back":"to contract, take out, tense"});
b.push({"front":"territorial","back":"territorial, land"});
b.push({"front":"subsister","back":"to subsist, remain"});
b.push({"front":"un usager","back":"user"});
b.push({"front":"la continuité","back":"continuity, continuation"});
b.push({"front":"maximal","back":"maximal"});
b.push({"front":"une idéologie","back":"ideology"});
b.push({"front":"le demandeur","back":"seeker, complainant"});
b.push({"front":"homologue","back":"counterpart, homologue"});
b.push({"front":"successif","back":"successive"});
b.push({"front":"le matériau","back":"material"});
b.push({"front":"la divergence","back":"divergence, difference"});
b.push({"front":"la municipalité","back":"municipality"});
b.push({"front":"consécutif","back":"consecutive"});
b.push({"front":"institutionnel","back":"institutional"});
b.push({"front":"la confédération","back":"confederation"});
b.push({"front":"acquitter","back":"to acquit, pay, settle, pay off"});
b.push({"front":"référer","back":"to refer, consult, refer to"});
b.push({"front":"substantiel","back":"substantial"});
b.push({"front":"une exclusion","back":"exclusion, expulsion"});
b.push({"front":"préconiser","back":"to recommend, advocate"});
b.push({"front":"un historien","back":"historian"});
b.push({"front":"atténuer","back":"to lessen, diminish, dim, subdue, reduce"});
b.push({"front":"applicable","back":"applicable"});
b.push({"front":"sud-est","back":"south-east"});
b.push({"front":"le conjoint","back":"spouse, joint"});
b.push({"front":"assortir","back":"to match, accompany"});
b.push({"front":"la restructuration","back":"restructure, restructuring"});
b.push({"front":"demi-heure","back":"half an hour"});
b.push({"front":"un actionnaire, une actionnaire","back":"shareholder"});
b.push({"front":"redouter","back":"to dread, fear"});
b.push({"front":"acheminer","back":"to forward, dispatch, transport"});
b.push({"front":"conformer","back":"to model, conform"});
b.push({"front":"délibérer","back":"to deliberate, debate"});
b.push({"front":"puiser","back":"to draw, take"});
b.push({"front":"géographique","back":"geographic, geographical"});
b.push({"front":"œuvrer","back":"to work"});
b.push({"front":"la contestation","back":"questioning, protest"});
b.push({"front":"iranien","back":"Iranian"});
b.push({"front":"conférer","back":"to confer"});
b.push({"front":"interpeller","back":"to call out to, question"});
b.push({"front":"fréquemment","back":"frequently"});
b.push({"front":"la légitimité","back":"legitimacy"});
b.push({"front":"dériver","back":"to divert, derive"});
b.push({"front":"respectivement","back":"respectively"});
b.push({"front":"induire","back":"to infer, induce, result in , lead to"});
b.push({"front":"un arbitrage","back":"refereeing, umpiring, arbitration"});
b.push({"front":"déléguer","back":"to delegate"});
b.push({"front":"miner","back":"to mine, erode"});
b.push({"front":"composante","back":"component"});
b.push({"front":"instituer","back":"to introduce, impose, establish, institute"});
b.push({"front":"marocain","back":"Moroccan"});
b.push({"front":"le nominal","back":"nominal"});
b.push({"front":"peiner","back":"to toil, labor, struggle"});
b.push({"front":"le renouvellement","back":"replacement, recurrence, repetition"});
b.push({"front":"le protestant","back":"Protestant"});
b.push({"front":"le faisceau","back":"bundle, beam, stack"});
b.push({"front":"le dégât","back":"damage"});
b.push({"front":"multinational","back":"multinational"});
b.push({"front":"étroitement","back":"closely"});
b.push({"front":"faillir","back":"to have almost, fail, fail to"});
b.push({"front":"nous-mêmes","back":"ourselves"});
b.push({"front":"coter","back":"to quote, rate"});
b.push({"front":"bien-être","back":"well being"});
b.push({"front":"énoncer","back":"to state, set out, express"});
b.push({"front":"un islamiste, une islamiste","back":"Islamist"});
b.push({"front":"bilatéral","back":"bilateral"});
b.push({"front":"environnemental","back":"environmental"});
b.push({"front":"le constructeur","back":"builder, manufacturer"});
b.push({"front":"déceler","back":"to discover, detect"});
b.push({"front":"acharner","back":"to go at fiercely and unrelentingly"});
b.push({"front":"assimiler","back":"to assimilate, take in"});
b.push({"front":"incarner","back":"to embody, incarnate"});
b.push({"front":"opter","back":"to opt, decide"});
b.push({"front":"décréter","back":"to declare, decree"});
b.push({"front":"dix-huit","back":"eighteen"});
b.push({"front":"coïncider","back":"to coincide, correspond"});
b.push({"front":"le renforcement","back":"reinforcement, strengthening"});
b.push({"front":"une élaboration","back":"working-out, development"});
b.push({"front":"une habitation","back":"residence, home, dwelling, housing"});
b.push({"front":"représentatif","back":"representative"});
b.push({"front":"une imposition","back":"taxation"});
b.push({"front":"un ajustement","back":"adjustment"});
b.push({"front":"la répercussion","back":"repercussion"});
b.push({"front":"soi-disant","back":"so-called, supposedly"});
b.push({"front":"salarial","back":"salary"});
b.push({"front":"abolir","back":"to abolish, do away with"});
b.push({"front":"la cohésion","back":"cohesion"});
b.push({"front":"minimal","back":"minimal, minimum"});
b.push({"front":"implanter","back":"to implant, set up, establish"});
b.push({"front":"exhorter","back":"to exhort, urge"});
b.push({"front":"sélectionner","back":"to select"});
b.push({"front":"paralyser","back":"to paralyze"});
b.push({"front":"le préjugé","back":"prejudice, bias"});
b.push({"front":"nord-ouest","back":"north-west"});
b.push({"front":"un affaiblissement","back":"weakening"});
b.push({"front":"peupler","back":"to populate, inhabit"});
b.push({"front":"resserrer","back":"to tighten up, strengthen"});
b.push({"front":"activement","back":"actively"});
b.push({"front":"incompatible","back":"incompatible"});
b.push({"front":"la synthèse","back":"summary, synthesis"});
b.push({"front":"la conjoncture","back":"situation, climate"});
b.push({"front":"réformer","back":"to re-form, reform, discharge"});
b.push({"front":"reléguer","back":"to relegate"});
b.push({"front":"un intervenant","back":"contributor, intervener"});
b.push({"front":"arbitraire","back":"arbitrary"});
b.push({"front":"la propagation","back":"propagation, spreading"});
b.push({"front":"grand-père","back":"grandfather"});
b.push({"front":"décliner","back":"to decline, refuse, turn down"});
b.push({"front":"un écu","back":"ecu"});
b.push({"front":"indirect","back":"indirect"});
b.push({"front":"démentir","back":"to deny, refute, contradict"});
b.push({"front":"sud-ouest","back":"south-west"});
b.push({"front":"le déterminant","back":"determining, deciding, crucial"});
b.push({"front":"sous-marin","back":"submarine, underwater"});
b.push({"front":"un acheminement","back":"routing, shipment"});
b.push({"front":"le notable","back":"notable, noteworthy"});
b.push({"front":"le tchèque","back":"Czech"});
b.push({"front":"là-dedans","back":"inside, in it"});
b.push({"front":"le différend","back":"disagreement, controversy"});
b.push({"front":"explicite","back":"explicitly"});
b.push({"front":"par-dessus","back":"over"});
b.push({"front":"apparent","back":"apparent, obvious"});
b.push({"front":"une allocation","back":"allocation, granting, allotment, allowance"});
b.push({"front":"décéder","back":"to die, pass away, pass on"});
b.push({"front":"dix-sept","back":"seventeen"});
b.push({"front":"une ambiguïté","back":"ambiguity"});
b.push({"front":"consultatif","back":"advisory"});
b.push({"front":"la complexité","back":"complexity"});
b.push({"front":"brandir","back":"to brandish, wield, wave"});
b.push({"front":"précaire","back":"precarious, makeshift"});
b.push({"front":"la justification","back":"justification, proof"});
b.push({"front":"la conservation","back":"preservation, preserving, retention"});
b.push({"front":"un aménagement","back":"development, planning, fitting, adjustment"});
b.push({"front":"le manifestant","back":"protester, demonstrator"});
b.push({"front":"prôner","back":"to laud, extol, advocate, commend"});
b.push({"front":"radicalement","back":"radically"});
b.push({"front":"ultérieur","back":"later, subsequent"});
b.push({"front":"axer","back":"to center"});
b.push({"front":"rectifier","back":"to rectify, correct"});
b.push({"front":"émouvoir","back":"to move, touch"});
b.push({"front":"alléger","back":"to lighten, alleviate,"});
b.push({"front":"la dégradation","back":"degrading, damaging, erosion; demotion"});
b.push({"front":"le vingtième, la vingtième","back":"twentieth"});
b.push({"front":"grand-mère","back":"grandmother"});
b.push({"front":"la citoyenneté","back":"citizenship"});
b.push({"front":"attester","back":"to attest, confirm"});
b.push({"front":"nullement","back":"not in the least"});
b.push({"front":"incorporer","back":"to incorporate, insert, merge"});
b.push({"front":"débloquer","back":"to free, unfreeze, unjam, release, unblock"});
b.push({"front":"la linguistique","back":"linguistic, linguistics"});
b.push({"front":"main-d’œuvre","back":"manpower, labor, workforce"});
b.push({"front":"rallier","back":"to rally, win over, join"});
b.push({"front":"réaffirmer","back":"to reaffirm, reassert"});
b.push({"front":"assigner","back":"to assign, allocate, attach, attribute"});
b.push({"front":"souhaitable","back":"desirable"});
b.push({"front":"le constat","back":"report, statement"});
b.push({"front":"le dynamisme","back":"dynamism"});
b.push({"front":"concerter","back":"to devise, consult"});
b.push({"front":"désespérer","back":"to despair"});
b.push({"front":"exporter","back":"to export"});
b.push({"front":"ériger","back":"to erect, set up"});
b.push({"front":"transitoire","back":"transient, interim, provisional"});
b.push({"front":"tardif","back":"late"});
b.push({"front":"un apport","back":"supply, contribution"});
b.push({"front":"un échelon","back":"rung, step, grade, echelon"});
b.push({"front":"une occurrence","back":"instance, case, occurrence"});
b.push({"front":"au-dessous","back":"underneath"});
b.push({"front":"fonctionnel","back":"functional"});
b.push({"front":"entre-temps","back":"meanwhile, in the meantime"});
b.push({"front":"le confrère","back":"colleague"});
b.push({"front":"la variation","back":"variation, change"});
b.push({"front":"productif","back":"productive"});
b.push({"front":"le groupement","back":"grouping, group, categorization"});
b.push({"front":"la modernisation","back":"modernization"});
b.push({"front":"souscrire","back":"to subscribe"});
b.push({"front":"le suffrage","back":"vote"});
b.push({"front":"concilier","back":"to reconcile"});
b.push({"front":"libanais","back":"Lebanese"});
b.push({"front":"le rapporteur","back":"telltale, rapporteur"});
b.push({"front":"le dix-neuvième, la dix-neuvième","back":"nineteenth"});
b.push({"front":"une indemnisation","back":"indemnification, compensation"});
b.push({"front":"le leadership","back":"leadership"});
b.push({"front":"la qualification","back":"qualification"});
b.push({"front":"dédier","back":"to dedicate"});
b.push({"front":"un artisan","back":"craftsman, self-employed"});
b.push({"front":"économiquement","back":"economically"});
b.push({"front":"industrialiser","back":"to industrialize"});
b.push({"front":"efficacement","back":"efficiently, effectively"});
b.push({"front":"le marginal","back":"marginal"});
b.push({"front":"modérer","back":"to restrain, moderate, reduce"});
b.push({"front":"une appartenance","back":"membership, belonging"});
b.push({"front":"constructif","back":"constructive"});
b.push({"front":"minime","back":"minor, minimal"});
b.push({"front":"le ralentissement","back":"slowing down"});
b.push({"front":"la mobilisation","back":"mobilization"});
b.push({"front":"tâcher","back":"to endeavor"});
b.push({"front":"la récession","back":"recession"});
b.push({"front":"sensiblement","back":"approximately, more or less, noticeably"});
b.push({"front":"léguer","back":"to bequeath, hand down, pass on"});
b.push({"front":"problématique","back":"problematic; problem"});
b.push({"front":"voiler","back":"to veil"});
b.push({"front":"erroné","back":"erroneous"});
b.push({"front":"yougoslave","back":"Yugoslav, Yugoslavian"});
b.push({"front":"explicitement","back":"explicitly"});
b.push({"front":"la souplesse","back":"suppleness, flexibility"});
b.push({"front":"le contingent","back":"contingent, draft, quota"});
b.push({"front":"émerger","back":"to emerge, rise up, come out"});
b.push({"front":"instruire","back":"to teach, educate, inform"});
b.push({"front":"une équité","back":"equity, fairly"});
b.push({"front":"soustraire","back":"to substract, remove, shield, escape from"});
b.push({"front":"téléviser","back":"to televise"});
b.push({"front":"consolider","back":"to strengthen, reinforce"});
b.push({"front":"le contrevenant","back":"offender, offending"});
b.push({"front":"coder","back":"to code, encode"});
b.push({"front":"la controverse","back":"controversy"});
b.push({"front":"filial","back":"filial; branch office"});
b.push({"front":"un opposant","back":"opponent, opposing"});
b.push({"front":"le sommaire","back":"summary, brief, cursory"});
b.push({"front":"le versant","back":"hillside, mountainside"});
b.push({"front":"la réticence","back":"reluctance, hesitation"});
b.push({"front":"un élargissement","back":"widening, letting-out, stretching, broadening"});
b.push({"front":"dégrader","back":"to degrade, debase, damage, erode"});
b.push({"front":"colonial","back":"colonial"});
b.push({"front":"le pourparler","back":"talk, discussion, negotiation"});
b.push({"front":"un incidence","back":"effect, incidence"});
b.push({"front":"vingt-quatre","back":"twenty four"});
b.push({"front":"le teneur, la teneur","back":"content"});
b.push({"front":"centrer","back":"to center"});
b.push({"front":"algérien","back":"Algerian"});
b.push({"front":"alentour","back":"around, round about"});
b.push({"front":"perpétuer","back":"to perpetuate, carry on"});
b.push({"front":"la doctrine","back":"doctrine"});
b.push({"front":"compétitif","back":"competitive"});
b.push({"front":"omettre","back":"to leave out, miss out, omit"});
b.push({"front":"concurrentiel","back":"competitive"});
b.push({"front":"le désarmement","back":"disarmament, disarming"});
b.push({"front":"quotidiennement","back":"daily, every day"});
b.push({"front":"état-major","back":"staff, staff headquarters"});
b.push({"front":"attarder","back":"to linger"});
b.push({"front":"englober","back":"to include, encompass, incorporate"});
b.push({"front":"le séparatiste, la séparatiste","back":"separatist"});
b.push({"front":"le surcroît","back":"extra, additional"});
b.push({"front":"nationaliste","back":"nationalist"});
b.push({"front":"un exportateur","back":"exportateur, exporting"});
b.push({"front":"ratifier","back":"to ratify"});
b.push({"front":"aviser","back":"to notice, advise"});
b.push({"front":"écologique","back":"ecological"});
b.push({"front":"sanctionner","back":"to sanction, punish, approve"});
b.push({"front":"aisé","back":"easy, well off, well-to-do"});
b.push({"front":"défavoriser","back":"to put at a disadvantage"});
b.push({"front":"civiliser","back":"to civilze"});
b.push({"front":"octroyer","back":"to grant, bestow"});
b.push({"front":"la limitation","back":"limitation, restriction, limit"});
b.push({"front":"irréversible","back":"irreversible"});
b.push({"front":"verbal","back":"verbal"});
b.push({"front":"une appréciation","back":"appreciation, assessment, appraisal"});
b.push({"front":"le complément","back":"complement"});
b.push({"front":"initialement","back":"initially"});
b.push({"front":"replier","back":"to fold, roll up, fold up, withdraw"});
b.push({"front":"le vérificateur","back":"checker, inspector, auditor"});
b.push({"front":"la prétention","back":"claim"});
b.push({"front":"la stabilisation","back":"stabilisation"});
b.push({"front":"la lacune","back":"gap, deficiency"});
b.push({"front":"mépriser","back":"to scorn, look down, spurn, disdain"});
b.push({"front":"minoritaire","back":"minority"});
b.push({"front":"idéologique","back":"ideological"});
b.push({"front":"le compatriote, la compatriote","back":"compatriot"});
b.push({"front":"majoritaire","back":"majority"});
b.push({"front":"le redressement","back":"straightening up, upturn, righting"});
b.push({"front":"chiffrer","back":"to put a figure to, assess, quantify, number"});
b.push({"front":"la compétitivité","back":"competitiveness"});
b.push({"front":"sous-sol","back":"basement, lower ground floor, subsoil, underground"});
b.push({"front":"indépendamment","back":"independently, irrespective of, regardless of"});
b.push({"front":"le rayonnement","back":"radiance"});
b.push({"front":"minier","back":"mining"});
b.push({"front":"ébranler","back":"to shake, rattle"});
b.push({"front":"unilatéral","back":"unilateral"});
b.push({"front":"tisser","back":"to weave"});
b.push({"front":"la cohérence","back":"coherence, consistency"});
b.push({"front":"modéré","back":"moderate, restrained, reasonable"});
b.push({"front":"négligeable","back":"negligible, trivial"});
b.push({"front":"symboliser","back":"to symbolize"});
b.push({"front":"substituer","back":"to substitute"});
b.push({"front":"le gestionnaire, la gestionnaire","back":"administrator, administrative"});
b.push({"front":"un immigrant","back":"immigrant"});
b.push({"front":"la polémique","back":"controversial, controversy"});
b.push({"front":"alourdir","back":"to weigh down, make heavy"});
b.push({"front":"sévir","back":"to act ruthlessly, be rife"});
b.push({"front":"la localité","back":"town, village"});
b.push({"front":"vigoureux","back":"vigorous"});
b.push({"front":"la rentabilité","back":"profitability"});
b.push({"front":"incliner","back":"to tilt, tend towards"});
b.push({"front":"révolter","back":"to revolt, rebel, outrage"});
b.push({"front":"philosophique","back":"philosophical"});
b.push({"front":"la parenthèse","back":"parenthesis, bracket, aside"});
b.push({"front":"le boursier","back":"grant-holder, scholarship holder; stock"});
b.push({"front":"déformer","back":"to bend, distort, deform"});
b.push({"front":"nord-est","back":"north-east"});
b.push({"front":"la substitution","back":"substitution, mix-up"});
b.push({"front":"parer","back":"to adorn, put on; to ward off, parry"});
b.push({"front":"avantageux","back":"profitable, worthwhile, advantageous, attractive"});
b.push({"front":"handicaper","back":"to handicap"});
b.push({"front":"imputer","back":"to impute to, attribute to"});
b.push({"front":"desservir","back":"to clear, go against, harm, serve"});
b.push({"front":"le mensuel","back":"monthly"});
b.push({"front":"le report","back":"postponement, deferment"});
b.push({"front":"aucunement","back":"in no way, not in the least, not at all"});
b.push({"front":"globalement","back":"globally"});
b.push({"front":"alternatif","back":"alternate, alternating"});
b.push({"front":"réglementaire","back":"regulation, control, statutory"});
b.push({"front":"une incitation","back":"incitement, incentive"});
b.push({"front":"un éditorial","back":"editorial"});
b.push({"front":"vingt-cinq","back":"twenty five"});
b.push({"front":"le déséquilibre","back":"imbalance"});
b.push({"front":"entraver","back":"to hinder, hamper, get in the way of"});
b.push({"front":"sous-estimer","back":"to underestimate"});
b.push({"front":"un embargo","back":"embargo"});
b.push({"front":"syrien","back":"Syrian"});
b.push({"front":"ponctuel","back":"punctual"});
b.push({"front":"la fermeté","back":"firmness, solidness, steadiness"});
b.push({"front":"véhiculer","back":"to transport, convey"});
b.push({"front":"répliquer","back":"to reply"});
b.push({"front":"la théologie","back":"theology"});
b.push({"front":"advenir","back":"to happen that, happen to"});
b.push({"front":"immigrer","back":"to immigrate"});
b.push({"front":"le privilégié","back":"privileged"});
b.push({"front":"controversé","back":"much debated, controversial"});
b.push({"front":"nouer","back":"to knot, tie"});
b.push({"front":"la gendarmerie","back":"police force, police station"});
b.push({"front":"analogue","back":"similar, analogous"});
b.push({"front":"initier","back":"to initiate, introduce"});
b.push({"front":"cessez-le-feu","back":"ceasefire"});
b.push({"front":"dissiper","back":"to dispel, disperse, clear away"});
b.push({"front":"entrevoir","back":"to make out, catch a glimpse of, foresee"});
b.push({"front":"stipuler","back":"to state, stipulate, specify"});
b.push({"front":"une impossibilité","back":"impossibility"});
b.push({"front":"le conditionnel","back":"conditional"});
b.push({"front":"la nuance","back":"shade, hue, nuance"});
b.push({"front":"conjointement","back":"jointly"});
b.push({"front":"articuler","back":"to articulate"});
b.push({"front":"successivement","back":"successively"});
b.push({"front":"la provision","back":"stock, supply"});
b.push({"front":"amplifier","back":"to amplify, magnify, expand"});
b.push({"front":"intergouvernemental","back":"intergovernmental"});
b.push({"front":"la délibération","back":"deliberation, debate, consideration"});
b.push({"front":"saisonnier","back":"seasonal"});
b.push({"front":"restituer","back":"to return, restore, refund"});
b.push({"front":"la disponibilité","back":"availability"});
b.push({"front":"le glissement","back":"sliding, slipping, skidding"});
b.push({"front":"un auditeur","back":"auditor, listener"});
b.push({"front":"un indigène, une indigène","back":"native, local"});
b.push({"front":"indirectement","back":"indirectly"});
b.push({"front":"une obtention","back":"obtaining, achievement"});
b.push({"front":"le prostitué","back":"prostitute"});
b.push({"front":"le concitoyen","back":"fellow citizen"});
b.push({"front":"libéralisation","back":"liberalization"});
b.push({"front":"le signataire, la signataire","back":"signatory"});
b.push({"front":"le douanier","back":"customs officer"});
b.push({"front":"borner","back":"to limit, confine"});
b.push({"front":"triompher","back":"to triumph, beat"});
b.push({"front":"concrétiser","back":"to materialise"});
b.push({"front":"la soumission","back":"submission"});
b.push({"front":"continuellement","back":"continually, continuously"});
b.push({"front":"dérober","back":"to steal, hide"});
b.push({"front":"le romancier","back":"novelist"});
b.push({"front":"déplaire","back":"to displease, be unhappy"});
b.push({"front":"innombrable","back":"innumerable, countless"});
b.push({"front":"inédit","back":"unpublished; original, new"});
b.push({"front":"désireux","back":"avid for, anxious to, desirous of"});
b.push({"front":"diversifier","back":"to vary, diversify"});
b.push({"front":"une instabilité","back":"instability"});
b.push({"front":"pénaliser","back":"to penalize, punish"});
b.push({"front":"foncier","back":"land-related, land, fundamental"});
b.push({"front":"envelopper","back":"to wrap, surround, veil"});
b.push({"front":"irrégulier","back":"irregular, uneven"});
b.push({"front":"un encadrement","back":"training, framing, supervision"});
b.push({"front":"moderniser","back":"to modernize"});
b.push({"front":"incomber","back":"to be incumbent upon"});
b.push({"front":"la retombée","back":"fallout, consequences, effects"});
b.push({"front":"équivaloir","back":"to be equivalent, amount to"});
b.push({"front":"le chiite, la chiite","back":"Shiite"});
b.push({"front":"le bouleversement","back":"upheaval"});
b.push({"front":"relater","back":"to relate, recount"});
b.push({"front":"concrètement","back":"in concrete terms"});
b.push({"front":"la coulisse","back":"backstage, wings, behind the scenes"});
b.push({"front":"la ratification","back":"ratification"});
b.push({"front":"le renouveau","back":"renewal"});
b.push({"front":"le néerlandais","back":"Dutch"});
b.push({"front":"intégral","back":"complete, unabridged"});
b.push({"front":"spécification","back":"specification"});
b.push({"front":"la documentation","back":"documentation, literature"});
b.push({"front":"logiquement","back":"logically"});
b.push({"front":"harmoniser","back":"to harmonize, harmonize with"});
b.push({"front":"le débouché","back":"prospect, opportunity, opening"});
b.push({"front":"le secrétariat","back":"secretaryship, secretariat, secretarial offices, secretary’s office"});
b.push({"front":"le détenteur","back":"holder, possessor, bearer"});
b.push({"front":"le basque, la basque","back":"Basque"});
b.push({"front":"une accumulation","back":"accumulation, amassing, storage, stockpiling, build-up"});
b.push({"front":"un essor","back":"expansion, development, flight"});
b.push({"front":"obséder","back":"to obsess, haunt"});
b.push({"front":"préventif","back":"preventive"});
b.push({"front":"la désignation","back":"designation"});
b.push({"front":"la conformité","back":"conformity"});
b.push({"front":"inhérent","back":"inherent"});
b.push({"front":"une illustration","back":"illustration"});
b.push({"front":"néfaste","back":"harmful, ill-fated"});
b.push({"front":"lasser","back":"to tire, weary, grow weary"});
b.push({"front":"influer","back":"to influence, have an influence on"});
b.push({"front":"présentement","back":"at present, presently"});
b.push({"front":"plate-forme","back":"platform"});
b.push({"front":"le kurde","back":"Kurd, Kurdish"});
b.push({"front":"inchangé","back":"unchanged"});
b.push({"front":"la multiplication","back":"multiplication"});
b.push({"front":"camoufler","back":"to cover up, conceal, camouflage"});
b.push({"front":"figer","back":"to clot, coagulate, congeal, set"});
b.push({"front":"la planification","back":"planning"});
b.push({"front":"le regroupement","back":"regrouping, reassembly"});
b.push({"front":"désastreux","back":"disastrous"});
b.push({"front":"la configuration","back":"configuration, layout"});
b.push({"front":"escompter","back":"to discount; to expect"});
b.push({"front":"intensif","back":"intensive"});
b.push({"front":"le scepticisme","back":"scepticism"});
b.push({"front":"plénier","back":"plenary, full"});
b.push({"front":"épanouir","back":"to bloom, blossom"});
b.push({"front":"minimiser","back":"to minimize, play down"});
b.push({"front":"inévitablement","back":"inevitably"});
b.push({"front":"échéant","back":"if need be"});
b.push({"front":"murmurer","back":"to murmur"});
b.push({"front":"une implantation","back":"implanting, setting up, establishment, implantation, installation"});
b.push({"front":"décerner","back":"to award, give, issue"});
b.push({"front":"replacer","back":"to replace, put back"});
b.push({"front":"vêtir","back":"to clothe, dress, put on"});
b.push({"front":"enchanter","back":"to delight, enchant, rejoice"});
b.push({"front":"démographique","back":"demographic"});
b.push({"front":"la fourniture","back":"supply, provision"});
b.push({"front":"taxer","back":"to tax"});
b.push({"front":"dévouer","back":"to devote, sacrifice oneself"});
b.push({"front":"hâter","back":"to quicken, hasten"});
b.push({"front":"la mobilité","back":"mobility"});
b.push({"front":"la dénonciation","back":"denunciation"});
b.push({"front":"exiler","back":"to exile"});
b.push({"front":"forger","back":"to forge, contrive, make up"});
b.push({"front":"le textile","back":"textile"});
b.push({"front":"la médiation","back":"mediation, arbitration"});
b.push({"front":"réprimer","back":"to suppress, repress"});
b.push({"front":"rémunérer","back":"to remunerate, pay"});
b.push({"front":"fasciner","back":"to fascinate"});
b.push({"front":"le progressiste, la progressiste","back":"progressive"});
b.push({"front":"excéder","back":"to exceed"});
b.push({"front":"inexistant","back":"non-existent"});
b.push({"front":"concéder","back":"to grant, concede"});
b.push({"front":"retrancher","back":"to deduct, remove; to entrench"});
b.push({"front":"renfermer","back":"to contain, shut, lock, enclose"});
b.push({"front":"traditionnellement","back":"traditionally"});
b.push({"front":"le mécontentement","back":"displeasure, dissatisfaction"});
b.push({"front":"inaugurer","back":"to unveil, open"});
b.push({"front":"proportionnel","back":"proportional"});
b.push({"front":"un aboutissement","back":"outcome, result"});
b.push({"front":"libre-échange","back":"free trade"});
b.push({"front":"maltraiter","back":"to manhandle, ill-treat, misuse, slight"});
b.push({"front":"continental","back":"continental"});
b.push({"front":"réitérer","back":"to reiterate, repeat"});
b.push({"front":"énumérer","back":"to enumerate"});
b.push({"front":"dix-neuf","back":"nineteen"});
b.push({"front":"guetter","back":"to watch over, watch out for"});
b.push({"front":"frustrer","back":"to frustrate"});
b.push({"front":"anglo-saxon","back":"Anglo-Saxon"});
b.push({"front":"sécuritaire","back":"safe"});
b.push({"front":"écrier","back":"to exclaim, cry out"});
b.push({"front":"la rente","back":"annuity, pension"});
b.push({"front":"résolument","back":"resolutely"});
b.push({"front":"soixante-dix","back":"seventy"});
b.push({"front":"perpétuel","back":"perpetual, everlasting, never-ending"});
b.push({"front":"militer","back":"to militate"});
b.push({"front":"procès-verbal","back":"minutes, statement"});
b.push({"front":"énergique","back":"energetic"});
b.push({"front":"défavorable","back":"unfavorable"});
b.push({"front":"un albanais","back":"Albanian"});
b.push({"front":"savoir-faire","back":"know-how"});
b.push({"front":"écrasant","back":"crushing, overwhelming"});
b.push({"front":"la munition","back":"ammunition, supplies"});
b.push({"front":"allouer","back":"to allocate"});
b.push({"front":"scandaliser","back":"to shock, scandalize"});
b.push({"front":"empresser","back":"to bustle about, hasten to do"});
b.push({"front":"inonder","back":"to flood"});
b.push({"front":"réglementer","back":"to regulate, control"});
b.push({"front":"sonder","back":"to probe, poll, sound out"});
b.push({"front":"le téléspectateur","back":"TV viewer"});
b.push({"front":"le forestier","back":"forest, forester"});
b.push({"front":"ravager","back":"to ravage, devastate"});
b.push({"front":"racial","back":"racial"});
b.push({"front":"ensuivre","back":"to follow, result, ensue"});
b.push({"front":"ajourner","back":"to adjourn, defer, postpone"});
b.push({"front":"la détérioration","back":"deterioration"});
b.push({"front":"civique","back":"civil; civics"});
b.push({"front":"ancrer","back":"to anchor"});
b.push({"front":"la législature","back":"legislature"});
b.push({"front":"audiovisuel","back":"audio-visual"});
b.push({"front":"confiner","back":"to confine"});
b.push({"front":"occasionner","back":"to cause, give rise to"});
b.push({"front":"allégement","back":"lightening, unweighting, reduction"});
b.push({"front":"performant","back":"productive, efficient"});
b.push({"front":"la concertation","back":"meeting, consultation"});
b.push({"front":"une interaction","back":"interaction"});
b.push({"front":"le sillage","back":"wake, slipstream"});
b.push({"front":"hisser","back":"to hoist, raise up"});
b.push({"front":"agréer","back":"to accept, approve of"});
b.push({"front":"le bosniaque","back":"Bosnian"});
b.push({"front":"solidaire","back":"interdependent, jointly dependent"});
b.push({"front":"ferroviaire","back":"railway, rail"});
b.push({"front":"la céréale","back":"cereal"});
b.push({"front":"aménager","back":"to develop, plan, fit, adjust"});
b.push({"front":"un exode","back":"exodus"});
b.push({"front":"le socialisme","back":"socialism"});
b.push({"front":"harmonisation","back":"harmonization"});
b.push({"front":"provisoirement","back":"temporarily, provisionally"});
b.push({"front":"détériorer","back":"to deteriorate"});
